<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tasks on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/</link><description>Recent content in Tasks on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Passing data from a task into the app form</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/pass-data-to-form/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/pass-data-to-form/</guid><description>This guide explains how to pass data from a task into the action application form.
Prerequisites Complex Tasks Tutorial Application Forms Tutorial ScenarioLet&amp;rsquo;s look deeper at the scenario from the Complex Tasks Tutorial where we have an ANC follow-up task which recurs eight times, and we want to ask the user different questions on the first and last follow-up.
Developing the taskFrom the Complex Tasks Tutorial, here is the task.</description></item><item><title>Querying Task Documents</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/query-task-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/query-task-data/</guid><description>This guide explains the data which results from tasks and how to query it.
Write a PostgreSQL query to examine task data Build deeper understanding of task data Present some data considerations of which task authors should remain mindful Prerequisites Data Flows for Analytics Querying task dataThe task system running on each user&amp;rsquo;s device is powered by task documents and those task documents sync to the server and to PostgreSQL just like a contact or a report.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the parameters in the Task Schema</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/task-schema-parameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/tasks/task-schema-parameters/</guid><description>This guide explains the parameters available in the Task Schema and important constraints governing the design of tasks.
Useful knowledge if you are stuck writing your first appliesIf predicate Understanding the data which is available in the task system and important constraints Understand the special significance of the appliesTo attribute Let&amp;rsquo;s synthesize some knowledge about CHT applications to help clarify what is happening within the task system:
All contacts in CHT applications are organised into hierarchies.</description></item></channel></rss>