<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Integrations on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/</link><description>Recent content in Integrations on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/custom/</guid><description>The CHT Core Framework includes functionality that allows sharing data with any API-based system. Developers have configured CHT integrations with OpenMRS, KenyaEMR, Bahmni, DHIS2, RapidPro, Apache NiFi, OpenHIM, custom electronic medical records (EMR), and several other systems.
OverviewIntegrating a CHT App into your digital health ecosystem starts with identifying an integration use case. It&amp;rsquo;s important to first understand all the components present in the ecosystem (EMR, laboratory system, community health information system, etc) and then plan out what the workflow will look like operationally.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/android/</guid><description>The CHT Android application can be launched by clicking on a link or invoking an intent in another Android app. This is useful for enabling login by SMS, directing a user to a specific page, and integrating between Android applications.
Sending a URL When the user clicks on a link to a CHT instance from an SMS, email, WhatsApp, or any other app, Android will prompt the user to choose whether to open the URL in the Android app or the browser.</description></item><item><title>DHIS2</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/dhis2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/dhis2/</guid><description>Most health systems have regular reporting requirements for community-level activities. Health workers often carry around heavy logbooks to manually record all relevant activities. When it is time to submit their data, community health workers (CHWs) summarize what was recorded in their logbooks and share this information with their supervisors, who in turn create paper records of these totals across entire community units or health facilities. This paper record is often passed to yet another individual whose responsibility is to manually key in the data into a health information management system, such as DHIS2.</description></item><item><title>DHIS2 Aggregate</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/dhis2-aggregate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/dhis2-aggregate/</guid><description>One of the first things you’ll need to do is identify the specific DHIS2 data set that you plan to implement. You’ll need a list of all the data elements on that data set, a detailed understanding of how each is calculated, the frequency in which the data set is submitted (weekly, monthly, etc…), and for which organisation units the data set applies. You’ll also want to identify and engage the appropriate DHIS2 stakeholders to get access to DHIS2 metadata, test environments, and discuss workflows.</description></item><item><title>OpenMRS</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/openmrs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/openmrs/</guid><description>OpenMRS is an open source electronic medical record system used in dozens of countries. Integrating CHT apps with OpenMRS can open up opportunities to improve health outcomes for patients by promoting better coordination of care. For example, referrals by CHWs in the community can be sent electronically to health facilities using OpenMRS so that nurses and clinicians can prepare for their visit and have full access to the assessment done by a CHW.</description></item><item><title>RapidPro</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/rapidpro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/rapidpro/</guid><description>RapidPro is the open-source platform that powers TextIt, developed by UNICEF and Nyaruka. RapidPro allows you to visually build messaging workflows for mobile-based services. The flows support a variety of technologies such as: SMS, USSD, IVR, Telegram, Facebook Messenger, and WhatsApp. Review RapidPro’s documentation to familiarize yourself with various components that include the API. Before you embark on designing an integrated RapidPro/CHT workflow, you should start by understanding the needs of your users, identifying a problem to solve, and establishing goals.</description></item><item><title>OppiaMobile</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/oppia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/oppia/</guid><description>OverviewOppiaMobile is an open source mobile learning platform built by Digital Campus specially designed for delivering learning content, multimedia, and quizzes in low connectivity settings. All the content and activities can be accessed and used when no internet connection is available, and users can earn points and badges for completing activities and watching videos. To learn more about the platform, check out the overview, OppiaMobile on Github, and their documentation site.</description></item></channel></rss>