<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interface on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/</link><description>Recent content in Interface on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colors</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/colors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/colors/</guid><description>ColorsColor helps users interpret and interact with app content by establishing a hierarchy of information, highlighting actions, indicating states, and conveying meaning.
Primary colorsThese are the primary colors of the navigation tabs. When necessary, use white #FFFFFF text over these colors.
Blue Periwinkle Pink Teal Yellow #63A2C6 #7193EE #F47B63 #76B0B0 #E9AA22 rgb(99, 162, 198) rgb(113, 147, 238) rgb(244, 123, 99) rgb(118, 176, 176) rgb(233, 170, 34) Messages Tasks People Targets Reports Secondary colorsThese are the secondary (highlight) colors of the navigation tabs.</description></item><item><title>Typography</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/typography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/typography/</guid><description>TypographyThe default app font is Noto Sans. It is free, codepen source, supports 800 languages and was specifically designed for good web legibility. It is bundled with the app so that all users see the same font regardless of their particular device, language, browser, etc. This ensures a consistent experience for all users.
Most text in the app should be the @text-normal-color: @gray-ultra-dark color. The lighter text color @text-secondary-color: @gray-dark) is used for labels and condition card filters.</description></item><item><title>Components</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/components/</guid><description>ButtonsPrimary buttons are used for actions, such as “Next” and “Submit”. Secondary buttons are the alternative to the primary action, such as &amp;ldquo;Previous&amp;rdquo;. Text links are used for less important or less commonly used actions, such as “Cancel”. CheckboxesUse checkboxes to select multiple items within a form. When necessary, use a descriptive error state. RadiosUse radio buttons to select a single item within a form. When necessary, use a descriptive error state.</description></item><item><title>UI Kit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/ui-kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/ui-kit/</guid><description>ComponentsFind reusable components of the CHT in this Figma file. Mockups can easily be created using these components.
DesktopMockups of the CHT on desktop/tablet view can be easily made using the components in this Figma UI Kit.
MobileMockups of the CHT on mobile devices can be easily made using the components in this Figma UI Kit.
Note The UI Kit is continuously being updated to match the CHT app and ensure the CHT community is provided with all the necessary assets to ease the design process.</description></item><item><title>Editable Mockups</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/mockups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/interface/mockups/</guid><description>Use these sample CHT screens and components as needed to test and validate workflows. Make a copy of the slides to edit and use with your content.
MobileMockups of the CHT on mobile devices can be easily made using the components in this Google Slide deck.
DesktopMockups of the CHT in a desktop view are possible using this Google Slide deck.</description></item></channel></rss>