<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contact and User management on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/</link><description>Recent content in Contact and User management on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contacts and Users</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/contacts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/contacts/</guid><description>“People” is the generic name used for individuals in apps built with the Core Framework. They can be patients, family members, nurses or health workers. Anyone with a profile in your app is a person.
“Places” is the generic name that represents a level in the hierarchy. “People” belong to “places”, and “places” belong to other higher level “places” in the hierarchy. A “place” could be a geographic area, like a district with the &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; associated to it being health officers.</description></item><item><title>Contact and User Management - Part 1</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/contact-and-users-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/contact-and-users-1/</guid><description>In this tutorial you will learn how to create and edit contacts and their associated users in and application built with the CHT using the default contact creation forms. This will help you get familiar with the UI of the webapp as well as some features and functionality. If you are already comfortable with this, you can skip to part 2, which covers manipulating contacts and their associated documents using cht-conf.</description></item><item><title>Contact and User Management - Part 2</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/contact-and-users-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/contact-and-users-2/</guid><description>In this tutorial you will learn how to create and edit contacts and their associated users in the CHT application using cht-conf. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, have a look at part 1 of this tutorial for a useful overview of key concepts.
Brief Overview of Key Conceptscht-conf is a command-line interface tool to manage and configure your apps built using the Core Framework of the Community Health Toolkit.
See more key concepts in part 1 of this tutorial.</description></item><item><title>CHT User Management tool</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/user-management-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/contact-management/user-management-tool/</guid><description>The Community Health Toolkit (CHT) is highly configurable and can be customized to support multiple hierarchies and users in the health care system. The CHT user management tool is a user friendly web application that works with the CHT to decentralize the user management process to the subnational levels, increasing efficiency and accuracy. This guide highlights steps for setting up and configuring the user management tool. The guide has been tailored for specific CHT-supported national community health information systems.</description></item></channel></rss>