<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>app_settings.json on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/</link><description>Recent content in app_settings.json on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>.accept_case_reports</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/accept_case_reports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/accept_case_reports/</guid><description>The accept_case_reports key contains the actions to take when reports about cases are received.
app_settings.json .accept_case_reports[] property description required form Form ID of the case form. yes silence_type A comma separated list of schedules to mute. no silence_for Duration from when the report was submitted for which messages should be muted. It is structured as a string with an integer value followed by a space and the time unit. For instance 8 weeks or 2 days.</description></item><item><title>.assetlinks</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/assetlinks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/assetlinks/</guid><description>Requires CHT Core 4.7.0+, CHT Conf 3.22.0+, and CHT Android 1.3.0+
When using a custom flavor of cht-android to connect to your CHT instance, the ecosystem supports using deep links to open specific content in the app. (E.g. token login links). Security measures in Android require these deep links be verified either automatically or manually. This assetlinks configuration enables auto-verification for your CHT links in your Android app. The provided JSON file will be served at https://&amp;lt;your CHT instance&amp;gt;/.</description></item><item><title>.contact_types</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/hierarchy/</guid><description>From 3.7.0 it is possible to configure what types of places and people are available by modifying the contact_types array in the app settings. Each type has the following properties.
Note Prior to version 3.7.0, CHT Core supported 4 contact types - 3 place types (clinic, health_center, district_hospital) and one person type (person). app_settings.json .contact_types[] Property Description Required id String identifier for the type. At times this will be used to sort the contacts in the UI so it is recommended to using a number prefix with gaps between numbers, eg: 10-district, 20-region, etc.</description></item><item><title>.dhis_data_sets</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/dhis2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/dhis2/</guid><description>From 3.9.0 it is possible to integrate with DHIS2 by modifying the dhis_data_sets property in app_settings.json.
See Also: DHIS2 Integration
app_settings.js .dhis_data_sets[] Property Type Description Required id string The data set id from DHIS2 with which to integrate Yes translation_key string The translation key of the DHIS2 data set name to be displayed Yes Code samplesConfigure the id and translation_key of the DHIS2 data set. The id corresponds to the id of the data set in the DHIS2 instance you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>.forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/forms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/forms/</guid><description>JSON forms are defined in either the base_settings.json or the app_settings/forms.json file and compiled in to the app_settings.json file with the compile-app-settings action in the cht-conf tool. JSON Forms are used for parsing reports from formatted SMS, SIM applications, and Medic Collect. JSON form definitions are also used for interoperability with third-party systems. Each form is defined as an JSON form object according to the following schema. The key for each object must be unique and all characters must be uppercase.</description></item><item><title>.header_tabs</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/header_tabs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/header_tabs/</guid><description>app_settings.js .header_tabsAs of 3.10.0, app header tabs icons can be configured by modifying the header_tabs section in the app settings. The header_tabs section consists of key:value pairs, where the key is the name of the tab to configure. These values can also be changed from the Admin console, on the Images page under the &amp;ldquo;Header tabs icons&amp;rdquo; tab.
{ &amp;#34;messages&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;icon&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;fa-user&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;tasks&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;resource_icon&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;medic-health-center&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;analytics&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;icon&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;fa-flag&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;resource_icon&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;icon-treatment&amp;#34; } } Available tabs tab name default FontAwesome icon messages fa-envelope tasks fa-flag reports fa-list-alt contacts fa-user analytics fa-bar-chart-o app_settings.</description></item><item><title>.outbound</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/outbound/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/outbound/</guid><description>Outbound is only available in CHT Core 3.5.0 and above
Outbound push allows configurers to have the creation or editing of CouchDB documents trigger outbound REST requests using the data in that document. For example, upon receiving a referral report you could send that referral to an external facility system that will manage and process that event.
These triggers can apply to all document types (not just common types such as reports or contacts) and as such care should be taken to only send the documents you intend (see configuration of relevant_to below).</description></item><item><title>.patient_reports</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/patient_reports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/patient_reports/</guid><description>The patient_reports key contains the actions to take when reports about people are received.
app_settings.json .patient_reports[] property description required form Form ID of the form. yes name Descriptive name of the form. This is not currently used in the app, but can be a helpful annotation. no format Guide of how the form can be used. This is not currently used in the app, but can be a helpful annotation.</description></item><item><title>.permissions</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/</guid><description>Permissions are defined by the permissions object in the base_settings.json file. The list below illustrates the available system defined permissions. To utilize a permission, you will need to first add the permission as a property of the permissions object, and then associate the permission to user role(s).
Permissions can be assigned to user roles either directly in base_settings.json as an array of user role identifiers, or configured in the App Management app.</description></item><item><title>.registrations</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/registrations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/registrations/</guid><description>The registrations key contains actions that need to be performed for incoming reports of the specified form.
app_settings.json .registrations[] property description required form Form ID that should trigger the schedule. yes events An array of event object definitions of what should happen when this form is received. yes event[].name Name of the event that has happened. The only supported event is on_create which happens when a form is received. yes event[].</description></item><item><title>.reminders</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/reminders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/reminders/</guid><description>Configure SMS reminders to notify primary contacts to submit reports for their places.
app_settings.js .reminders[] Property Type Description Required form string If a report with this ID is submitted for this place then the SMS will not be sent. Yes translation_key string The translation key to use to look up the SMS message content. Yes message array or string Deprecated. The SMS content. Use translation_key instead. No text_expression string The later text expression to use to set the frequency of this reminder.</description></item><item><title>.replication_depth</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/replication_depth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/replication_depth/</guid><description> Replication depth is defined under replication_depth as an array of objects. It grants the ability to limit document replication depending on user roles.
app_settings.json .replication_depth property description required role The configured user role the depth applies to. yes depth The replication depth value. Must be a positive integer or 0. yes report_depth As of 3.10. Replication depth applied to reports submitted by other users no Code sample:{ &amp;#34;replication_depth&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;role&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;district_manager&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;depth&amp;#34;: 1, &amp;#34;report_depth&amp;#34;: 1 }, { &amp;#34;role&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;national_manager&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;depth&amp;#34;: 2 } ] }</description></item><item><title>.replications [deprecated]</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/replications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/replications/</guid><description>Deprecated The replications field is only available in versions 3.5.0 to 3.9.0. As of 3.10.0 this field is ignored, and replication happens nightly for user meta databases to a central meta data database. Replications are defined under the app_settings.replications key as an array of replication objects. The definition takes the typical form below:
&amp;#34;replications&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;fromSuffix&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;user-[^\\-]+-meta&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;toSuffix&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;users-meta&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;text_expression&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cron&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;0 2 * * *&amp;#34; } ] property description required fromSuffix The suffix of the source table(s).</description></item><item><title>.roles</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-roles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-roles/</guid><description>Each user is assigned one of the defined roles. Roles can be defined using the App Management app, which is represented by the roles object of the app-settings.json file. Each role is defined by an identifier as the key, and an object with the following properties:
app_settings.json .roles{} Property Description Required name The translation key for this role Yes offline Determines if user will be an online or offline user.</description></item><item><title>.schedules</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/schedules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/schedules/</guid><description>Schedules are defined in either the base_settings.json or the app_settings/schedules.json file and compiled in to the app_settings.json file with the compile-app-settings action in the cht-conf tool.
The schedules key contains an array of schedule objects, each representing the messages to send based on a registration.
app_settings.json .schedules[] property description required name A unique string label that is used to identify the schedule. Spaces are allowed. yes summary Short description of the of the schedule.</description></item><item><title>.sms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/sms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/sms/</guid><description>SMS settings are defined under the sms key, as an object supporting the following properties:
app_settings.json .sms property default description outgoing_service medic-gateway Defines the service to use to send SMS messages. Currently supports &amp;ldquo;medic-gateway&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;africas-talking&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;rapidpro&amp;rdquo;. For more information read the documentation on &amp;ldquo;africas-talking&amp;rdquo; configuration and &amp;ldquo;rapidpro&amp;rdquo; configuration. duplicate_limit 5 The number of identical sms message allowed to be sent to the same recipient. Code sampleThe definition takes the typical form below:</description></item><item><title>.token_login</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/token_login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/token_login/</guid><description>Login via SMS settings are defined under the token_login key, as an object supporting the following properties:
app_settings.json .token_login property type required description enabled Boolean yes Enables or disables token_login deployment-wide. When this is false, users can&amp;rsquo;t be updated to use token_login and any requests to login with a token link will fail. translation_key String yes Translation key for the information (helper) sms message that the user receives, along with their token-login link Code sampleThe definition takes the typical form below:</description></item><item><title>.transitions</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/transitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/transitions/</guid><description>When sentinel detects a document has changed it runs transitions against the doc. These transitions can be used to generate a short form patient id or assign a report to a facility.
ConfigurationBy default all transitions are disabled. They can be enabled by configuring the transitions property to have a key with the transitions name and a truthy value. As of version 3.12.0 some transitions will partially run on the client for offline users.</description></item></channel></rss>