<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Monitoring and Alerting on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/</link><description>Recent content in Monitoring and Alerting on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to monitoring and alerting</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/introduction/</guid><description>This guide applies to all production instances of the CHT for both 3.x (beyond 3.9) and 4.x.
Be sure to see how to deploy a solution to monitor and alert on production CHT instances.
Each deployment will experience different stresses on its resources. Be sure to tune any alerting levels in the case of a false positive so that you may avoid them in the future. Any thresholds for alerts, and even what is alerted on, is just a guideline, not a guarantee of uptime.</description></item><item><title>CHT Watchdog Setup</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/setup/</guid><description>These instructions apply to both CHT 3.x (beyond 3.12) and CHT 4.x.
Medic maintains CHT Watchdog which is an opinionated configuration of Prometheus (including json_exporter) and Grafana which can easily be deployed using Docker. It is supported on CHT 3.12 and later, including CHT 4.x. By using this solution a CHT deployment can easily get longitudinal monitoring and push alerts using Email, Slack or other mechanisms. All tools are open source and have no licensing fees.</description></item><item><title>Production CHT Watchdog</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/production/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/production/</guid><description>These instructions apply to both CHT 3.x (beyond 3.12) and CHT 4.x.
What it means to run in productionWhen you run CHT Watchdog in production, and it is publicly accessible on the Internet, and has mission-critical data on it, you should take extra precautions around security and backup. This mainly consists of:
using TLS for all HTTP connections using VPN or SSH for insecure protocols like ssl=false in Postgres ensuring if the server were to fail, you can recover the data This guide assumes you have already set up TLS on your CHT instance and have gone through the Setup steps to deploy an instance of CHT Watchdog on server with a static IP and DNS entry, monitor.</description></item><item><title>Custom Postgres metrics in CHT Watchdog</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/postgres-ingest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/postgres-ingest/</guid><description>These instructions apply to both CHT 3.x (beyond 3.12) and CHT 4.x.
IntroductionAfter setting up your Watchdog instance and making it production ready, you can include additional custom metrics from your deployment. These metrics should be ingested by Prometheus and then can be used to create new Grafana dashboards and alerts. Example use cases include monitoring and alerting on health metrics like CHW visits per county or household registration rates, etc.</description></item><item><title>Integrating CHT Watchdog</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/integration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/monitoring/integration/</guid><description>These instructions apply to both CHT 3.x (beyond 3.12) and CHT 4.x.
Going beyond basic setupAfter you have done the setup of CHT Watchdog and configured it to run with TLS and have backups enabled, you may want to extend it to scrape other Prometheus data sources so that Grafana can send alerts on non-CHT Core metrics.
This guide uses example instances of CHT Core (cht.example.com) and CHT Watchdog (watchdog.</description></item></channel></rss>