<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Managing Data on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/</link><description>Recent content in Managing Data on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Database document hydration</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/hydration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/hydration/</guid><description>Documents are connected with each other via their document _id. For example:
a contact document is connected to its parent by storing their _id in the parent property
a report document is connected to its submitter by storing their _id in the contact property
See Also: DB Schema
To optimize database storage, documents are &amp;ldquo;minified&amp;rdquo; when stored and are &amp;ldquo;hydrated&amp;rdquo; when they are used by the app.
MinificationMinification means replacing a linked document&amp;rsquo;s content with an object that only contains its uuid.</description></item><item><title>How to bulk load users</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/users-bulk-load/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/users-bulk-load/</guid><description>The bulk user upload feature is available in 3.16.0 and later versions of the CHT. As of CHT 3.17.0, when creating both a contact and a place, the contact will be set as the default contact of the place. User creation can be scripted using the CHT API directly or using the cht-conf tool, which is detailed in the CSV-to-Docs guide.
This feature can be used to load as many users as possible but works optimally with chunks of 1,000 users or less.</description></item><item><title>CHT Impact Metrics</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/impact-metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/impact-metrics/</guid><description>Impact monitoring is an essential part of both the Community Health Toolkit and Medic&amp;rsquo;s processes and ethos. We are committed to harnessing data to:
Support our partners in data-driven operational and strategic decision making Inform our product roadmap and organizational strategy, and Participate in overarching policy discussions around community health. As a member of the CHT community and potential CHT implementer, we encourage you to learn more about the recommended impact metrics for monitoring and evaluation across priority use cases by reviewing the metrics listed below.</description></item><item><title>Detecting and fixing production data on training instances</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/training-instance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/training-instance/</guid><description>After onboarding CHWs, sometimes data ends up on the wrong CHT instance. There are some passive and active actions you can take to help deal with this situation.
MonitoringMonitoring is a good way to see if CHWs are sending forms to the wrong CHT server. By catching such a problem early, it may be easy to fix manually which avoids more laborious fixes on the command line for admins.
Manual device checksSupervisors can actively monitor CHWs as they register their first household.</description></item><item><title>Revalidate invalid reports</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/invalid-reports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/invalid-reports/</guid><description>You may encounter a dreaded case when reports coming in to a Medic Webapp instance have a red indicator instead of the green indicator.
This may be caused by:
Missing forms in the app_settings config. Missing or incorrect fields in the input form. e.g Missing patient ID, or Patient ID with letters Extra fields in the input form. This happens when you don&amp;rsquo;t configure for some fields in the app_settings.json of the webapp Configuring some forms in the wrong section of the app_settings i.</description></item><item><title>CSV to Docs</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/csv-to-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/data/csv-to-docs/</guid><description>Seeding data with cht-confUsers, contacts, and report data can be specified in comma-separated value (CSV) files, then converted to JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) files and uploaded into your instance using cht-conf. This documentation will cover the CSV notation used, fetching CSV files from Google Sheets, converting the CSV files into JSON docs, and then uploading the data from the JSON files to your instance.
Converting CSVsRunning cht-conf with the csv-to-docs action converts CSV files from the csv folder into JSON docs to be uploaded to your instance.</description></item></channel></rss>