<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Examples and Reference Implementations</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/</link><description>Recent content in Examples and Reference Implementations on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apps: Antenatal Care Reference App</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/anc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/anc/</guid><description>
&lt;p>CHT applications are configurable by design and support an exceptional range of features and health service areas. The ANC Reference App provides organizations with a template for structuring and organizing you app, it’s configuration code, and testing framework. It includes a foundation for forms related to pregnancy and delivery, flexible data fields, and even analytics, and can be deployed as-is or customized by a developer for your unique context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To install the ANC Reference Application, follow the &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/cht-core/blob/master/INSTALL.md">easy installation instructions&lt;/a>. An &lt;a href="anc-reference-app-overview.pdf">overview of the ANC Reference App&lt;/a> and its key features is also available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="anc-reference-app-overview.pdf">&lt;img src="preview-anc-ref-app-overview.png" alt="ANC Overview">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to modify our ANC Reference Application for your project or context, read our &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/design/apps/">configuration best practices&lt;/a> or learn how to &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/">develop your own community health apps&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: Contact Tracing</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/contact-tracing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/contact-tracing/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The CHT’s Contact Tracing functionality enables effective disease surveillance within communities to help control infectious disease outbreaks. It is a community public health tool that is designed to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Centrally register patient cases and track contacts to prevent secondary spread of diseases in communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a coordinated approach to contact tracing within existing health systems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communicate the importance of self-isolation and symptom screening to exposed individuals and their families&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="problem-being-addressed">Problem Being Addressed&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An essential part of containing disease outbreaks, such as COVID-19, requires public health organizations to rapidly notify people who have come into contact with confirmed or suspected patient cases. In many health systems, existing health management information systems are ill equipped to handle the necessary rapid tracking, triage, and care referrals for large numbers of patient cases and contacts to prevent secondary spread of viruses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="solution-overview">Solution Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Contact Tracing with the CHT offers a rapidly scalable surveillance strategy by registering patient cases and their contacts within communities in a responsive and empathetic way. Through proactive tracing of contacts, active symptom screening, and referrals to care or self-isolation, the app can be deployed to assist in:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disrupting secondary transmission via coordinated registration of patient cases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enrolling all contacts and households in monitoring during isolation periods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Referring symptomatic cases for skilled care following triage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Engaging in community education and follow-up during isolation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="app-user-roles-example">App User Roles Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="user-roles.png" alt="user-roles.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reporting-hierarchy-example">Reporting Hierarchy Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="hierarchy.png" alt="hierarchy.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="app-workflow-example">App Workflow Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is a detailed workflow that supports tracing of contacts of suspected or confirmed patient cases, symptom screening, care referrals, and monitoring of asymptomatic contacts during self-isolation. It works on both SMS and the CHT app. It can be combined with other care workflows and configured to suit specific health system needs, particularly in terms of tracer roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="workflow.png" alt="workflow.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: Event Based Surveillance</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/ebs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/ebs/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The CHT’s Event Based Surveillance (EBS) functionality enables rapid capture of information about community events that are a potential risk to public health. Deployed at the community level, this functionality is designed to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Achieve earliest possible detection of COVID-19 cases in communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide visibility into signals, reports, and investigations centrally for follow-up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coordinate and support local action based on existing roles in disease surveillance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="problem-being-addressed">Problem Being Addressed&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Patient reporting through traditional primary health care channels is not well suited for detecting rapidly spreading outbreaks at a community scale. Timely detection of outbreaks and important public health events can be delayed or missed when relying on individual patient data and traditional health management information systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="solution-overview">Solution Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Event Based Surveillance with the CHT offers opportunities for rapid deployment and measurable community impact for reportable diseases, including COVID-19. Through more timely event data reporting and analysis, the CHT provides early indicators of emerging issues to community health workers across the health system. The CHT solution offers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tiered reporting, verification, and escalation process, which can improve speed and quality of data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Signal data that can be mapped for data-driven decision-making&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pre-populated with Supervisor and CHW contact information&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Health program continuity with the inclusion of pre-existing care workflows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>System scalability through training CHWs remotely on their role and responsibilities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-roles-example">User Roles Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="user-roles.png" alt="user-roles.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reporting-hierarchy-example">Reporting Hierarchy Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="hierarchy.png" alt="hierarchy.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="workflow-example">Workflow Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is a simple workflow that enables CHWs to use SMS to report signal codes for specific community health threats. The CHW Supervisor can then verify the initial report and, if warranted, escalate to the sub-county for investigation and follow-up. This example reference workflow is designed to be flexible and can be combined with other complimentary care workflows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="workflow.png" alt="workflow.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: Remote Onboarding and Training</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/remote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/examples/remote/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The CHT’s Remote Onboarding and Training functionality enables Supervisors and Administrators to train CHWs on care workflows and related app use without being physically present. It is designed for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Safety: maintaining distance due to infectious disease&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speed: faster deployment when timing is a critical&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scalability: onboarding large numbers of users at the same time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Measurability: evaluation to provide added support where needed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adaptability: integration with existing program and workflow structures&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="problem-being-addressed">Problem Being Addressed&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Providing consistent training for CHWs is critically important in the context of evolving health programs and use of digital support tools. In-person training is often not feasible (due to distance, infectious disease outbreaks, or similar), but is still required to build and maintain effective care programs. Relying on CHWs to learn to use these new digital tools and adhere to care workflows on their own is a major challenge to health program success.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="solution-overview">Solution Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The CHT’s onboarding and training capabilities offer a remote way to provide education to CHWs and Supervisors about digital tools functionality and care workflows. It can be deployed in both SMS and App based modules. Through asynchronous communication, program administrators are able to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create customized training modules that match program requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capture assessments of CHW knowledge levels of training material&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assess user training participation abandonment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identify CHWs who need additional Supervisor support&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-roles-example">User Roles Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="user-roles.png" alt="user-roles.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reporting-hierarchy-example">Reporting Hierarchy Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="hierarchy.png" alt="hierarchy.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="workflow-example">Workflow Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This SMS based workflow example illustrates how the CHT enables remote training, tasking and communication at scale. Training can be done using simple guides, audio/videos suitable for low bandwidth, or interactive experiences on personal devices. Training programs can be easily configured to suit specific health program needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="workflow1.png" alt="workflow.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="workflow2.png" alt="workflow.png">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>