<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHT Translations on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/</link><description>Recent content in CHT Translations on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/translations-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/translations-overview/</guid><description>Given that CHT apps are used around the world, the Core Framework was designed with localization in mind. The Core Framework itself is available in English, French, Hindi, Nepali, Spanish, Swahili, and Indonesian.
Brief Overview of Key ConceptsLocalization this is setting up the desired language in CHT for the end user.
Translations this is manually setting up extra translations of instance tabs texts or outgoing SMS text. See an outline of how to do that here.</description></item><item><title>Configuring</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/configuring-translations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/configuring-translations/</guid><description>This section will take you through localizing the CHT to a custom language (Swahili). This will include setting up the user interface labels as well as outgoing text messages.
By the end of the section you should be able to:
Change the CHT user interface labels to a custom language. Change outgoing text messages to a custom language(Swahili will be used in the guide). Configuration StepsCreate a new file in the &amp;rsquo;translations/&amp;rsquo; folder called messages-sw.</description></item><item><title>Managing</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/managing-translations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/managing-translations/</guid><description>Apps built with CHT Core are localized so that users can use them in the language of their choice. Languages supported by default are English, French, Nepali, Spanish, and Swahili. The goal of this doc is to help the community manage these and future translations.
OverviewLike the rest of the code the translation files live in the GitHub repo. These translation files are properties files, which are a series of keys and their corresponding values.</description></item><item><title>Localizing</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/localizing-translations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/translations/localizing-translations/</guid><description>Given that CHT apps are used around the world, the Core Framework was designed with localization in mind. The Core Framework itself is available in English, French, Hindi, Nepali, Spanish, Swahili, and Indonesian.
In the app_settings.json file the default language for the application is set by the locale property, along with a separate default language for outgoing messages that are sent via SMS with the locale_outgoing property.
Additionally, languages available to the user can be enabled and disabled through the languages property which contains an array of objects.</description></item></channel></rss>