<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Managing Updates to Applications and Content on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/</link><description>Recent content in Managing Updates to Applications and Content on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Feature Flags</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/feature-flags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/feature-flags/</guid><description>Some CHT Core features can be enabled for specific users only. This can be particularly helpful for features that require training. The updated or &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; version will generally be the system default, but users can be configured to see the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; version. If you do nothing when you upgrade, users will automatically start seeing the new version.
Note Feature flags are used primarily as a way to phase in updates. The old version should be considered deprecated and will be completely removed in a future release.</description></item><item><title>Preparing to upgrade to CHT 4.0</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/preparing-for-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/preparing-for-4/</guid><description>Note This guide applies to both self-hosted and Medic hosted deployments. IntroductionMedic uses Semantic Versioning (aka &amp;ldquo;SemVer&amp;rdquo;) which means that the CHT upgrade from the major 3.x version to the 4.x version denotes there are breaking changes. The key to a successful upgrade will be to understand and plan for these breaking changes. Aside from the Docker hosting infrastructure (out of scope for this prep document), the two breaking changes are around CHT Android and Enketo.</description></item><item><title>Update Collect Forms Remotely</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/collect-forms-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/collect-forms-update/</guid><description>To do over the air Medic Collect form updates via HTTP rather than sending APKs which have a long manual install process, follow the steps below:
Have your xls forms ready in the folder. They should use underscore as name separators. e.g form_name.xlsx They should have form_id and name properties in the settings Upload the forms to the instance using cht-conf Using the upload-collect-forms action as shown below. cht --instance=user:pass@instancename.app.medicmobile.org upload-collect-forms Go to the Collect App.</description></item></channel></rss>