<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHT Targets on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/</link><description>Recent content in CHT Targets on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/targets-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/targets-overview/</guid><description>Targets is the user dashboard or analytics tab. The widgets on this tab provide a summary or analysis of the data in submitted reports. These widgets can be configured to track metrics for an individual CHW, for a Supervisor overseeing a group of CHWs, or for an entire health facility.
For CHWs, the Targets tab provides a quick summary of their progress towards their individual goals. For Supervisors, Nurses, and facility-based users, the Targets tab provides important insights into how their community unit is performing.</description></item><item><title>Target Widgets</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/target-widgets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/target-widgets/</guid><description>This tutorial will take you through how to build target widgets.
Target widgets provide a summary or analysis of the data in submitted reports.
You will be adding target widgets that will allow Community Health Workers (CHWs) to track various metrics based on assessment reports submitted.
Brief Overview of Key ConceptsTargets is the user dashboard or analytics tab.
Target widgets provide a summary or analysis of the data in submitted reports.</description></item><item><title>targets.js</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/targets-js/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/targets-js/</guid><description>All targets are defined in the targets.js file as an array of objects according to the Targets schema defined below. Each object corresponds to a target widget that shows in the app. The order of objects in the array defines the display order of widgets on the Targets tab. The properties of the object are used to define when the target should appear, what it should look like, and the values it will display.</description></item></channel></rss>