<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Personas on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/</link><description>Recent content in User Personas on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Professionalized Community Health Worker (CHW), Janet</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-janet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-janet/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;It took a while to be trusted. We had to prove our worth, but now we are well appreciated.&amp;rdquo;
AboutJanet is a mother and a farmer. She takes care of her daily BRAC work after finishing her farm work. She has poor eyesight. Janet has a feature phone. She has seen smartphones but never used one. She has no electricity at her home. She charges her phone at her friend’s house.</description></item><item><title>CHW Supervisor, Ann</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-supervisor-ann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-supervisor-ann/</guid><description>“During refresher trainings, when I go there, it takes me 3 hours because I copy from one book to another.”
AboutMarried with two school-aged children Has one year of training in a health-related field Not originally from the community, but communicates effectively with the CHWs Salaried MOH employee Has a personal mobile phone that ranges from a feature phone to a smart phone, used for communication Has an email account primarily accessed via mobile phone</description></item><item><title>Regional Manager, Christina</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/regional-manager-christina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/regional-manager-christina/</guid><description>
“I heard that some branches have already had challenges with mobile phones.”
AboutChristina been working at BRAC for six years. She manages four branches and works closely with the CHW Managers there. She makes sure CHW Managers are monitoring CHWs. She occasionally does random checks, driving out to villages and observing Managers with CHWs.
Values Visionary Integrity Good communication Respect Responsibility Wisdom Empathy Responsibilities Overall responsibility of the Region’s activities Oversees implementation of organisational goals Communicates organisational goals and strategies to CHW managers Liaise and ensure compliance with Ministries, NGO boards and regulatory bodies Promote advocacy efforts of the program Supervises and supports staff to attain their career goals Approval of quarterly logistic plans for CHW managers Reviews and approves CHW’s continuous education programs Evaluates programs impact and advises on key priority areas of focus Realignment of programs to changing ecosystem Budgetary planning for region’s activities Tracking branches’ and CHW manager’s performance Monthly indicators tracking to ensure realization of organisational goals Needs Real time access of data on supervision activities ongoing in their region Access to summary statistics on project indicators Timely submission of monthly reports on retention and turnover rates for CHWs Escalation of CHW retraining needs, challenges and proposed solutions Opportunities to conduct random checks to assess the CHWs perceptions of their managers support Motivations Desire to improve lives of communities Desire to practice community health strategies learnt at school Organisational goals align well with personal goals Strengths and Assets Provided with a company car and computer Has a welcoming heart and accessible to employees Team player</description></item><item><title>Nurse, Mary</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/nurse-mary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/nurse-mary/</guid><description>AboutMary has formal clinical training but a limited ability to conduct complex surgical procedures. She sees +/- 50 patients a day, sometimes in their homes. She is literate in English and understands local dialects. She is sometimes stationed far from her rural town/family in spurts and makes regular trips to districts to hand-deliver reports.
Mary lives on $5/day and depends mostly on solar power at the clinic as she may not have electricity at home.</description></item><item><title>Data Manager, Paul</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/data-manager-paul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/data-manager-paul/</guid><description>“It’s all about training them. The Community Health Workers are just villagers and farmers, so it’s training and more training.”
AboutPaul has worked at BRAC for two years. He’s very focused on his career and has lots of IT projects running. He is responsible for training the branches on how to use the mobile phones. Right now Paul is looking for the right quality of phones. He also wants to understand how the database will ensure reliable syncing.</description></item><item><title>App Builders</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/app-builder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/app-builder/</guid><description>AboutApp builders and technical organizations have in-house or contracted software developers. They deploy health technology solutions for implementing partners such an iNGOs, Governments, UN agencies etc in the community health space. They have limited familiarity with end-users such as CHWs and HCD.
Values Aligned with CHT principles and willing to contribute back to the CHT in the future Believe in building open-source technologies Integrity Likeable personality Open-mindedness Strong work ethic Responsibilities Build and deliver user experiences centered on the CHT Steward the CHT app developer’s experience CHT Capacity Builders Technical support Speak the language of the business Needs Capacity and expertise with the CHT Flexible technology (and tooling) to help build holistic digital health interventions Motivations Build awesome and bug-free user experiences using the CHT Adoption of the CHT as the technology of choice for building community health apps Delivering effective interventions Novel projects or interventions Developing skills Strengths and Assets Diversity in skills sets: HCD, software development, database management, dashboard development Resourcefulness: bend the CHT&amp;rsquo;s capabilities to meet a given need Passion for problem solving An inquisitive mind</description></item></channel></rss>