<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Personas on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/</link><description>Recent content in User Personas on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Professionalized Community Health Worker (CHW), Janet</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-janet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-janet/</guid><description>CHWs are the central users of apps built with the Core Framework. CHWs conduct household visits and are responsible for the health of their community. CHWs are known and trusted locally and typically live in and are chosen by their community. Their degree of health training, responsibilities, and support depends upon their country and program. The majority of CHWs are women, ranging from 25-60 years old.
&amp;ldquo;It took a while to be trusted.</description></item><item><title>CHW Supervisor, Ann</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-supervisor-ann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-supervisor-ann/</guid><description>The CHW supervisor is the person who trains and supports CHWs and helps them meet their monthly goals. Supervisors usually split their time between administrative duties at the local health facility and accompanying CHWs on their community visits.
“During refresher trainings, when I go there, it takes me 3 hours because I copy from one book to another.”
AboutMarried with two school-aged children Has one year of training in a health-related field Not originally from the community, but communicates effectively with the CHWs Salaried MOH employee Has a personal mobile phone that ranges from a feature phone to a smart phone, used for communication Has an email account primarily accessed via mobile phone</description></item><item><title>Regional Manager, Christina</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/regional-manager-christina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/regional-manager-christina/</guid><description>Regional managers provide overall oversight of activities in the region they are assigned. They are employed by technical and implementing partners to oversee and provide general guidance for two or more branches in a region. They troubleshoot and provide support to branch managers to optimise operations. They have limited interactions with end users but provide the link between field operations and the head office.
“I heard that some branches have already had challenges with mobile phones.</description></item><item><title>Nurse, Mary</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/nurse-mary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/nurse-mary/</guid><description>Nurses are stationed at the health facility and spend their days seeing patients. They are typically very busy and may see 50 or more patients a day. At the clinic, they sometimes deal with staff shortages, stock-outs, and poor internet connectivity. They help train and manage CHWs, particularly during monthly meetings at the facility. They are interested in seeing improvements in health metrics for the areas their facility serves.
AboutMary has formal clinical training but a limited ability to conduct complex surgical procedures.</description></item><item><title>Data Manager, Paul</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/data-manager-paul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/data-manager-paul/</guid><description>Data Managers are often based at a regional health facility or a program or administrative unit and serve many local facilities. They are responsible for collating and reporting on community and health system data. Their work often involves following up with supervisors and nurses to verify data and retrieve missing information.
“It’s all about training them. The Community Health Workers are just villagers and farmers, so it’s training and more training.</description></item><item><title>App Builders</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/app-builder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/app-builder/</guid><description>App builders and technical organizations develop and deliver world-class software contextualized to meet their clients’ needs and deliver value to their stakeholders.
AboutApp builders and technical organizations have in-house or contracted software developers. They deploy health technology solutions for implementing partners such an iNGOs, Governments, UN agencies etc in the community health space. They have limited familiarity with end-users such as CHWs and HCD.
Values Aligned with CHT principles and willing to contribute back to the CHT in the future Believe in building open-source technologies Integrity Likeable personality Open-mindedness Strong work ethic Responsibilities Build and deliver user experiences centered on the CHT Steward the CHT app developer’s experience CHT Capacity Builders Technical support Speak the language of the business Needs Capacity and expertise with the CHT Flexible technology (and tooling) to help build holistic digital health interventions Motivations Build awesome and bug-free user experiences using the CHT Adoption of the CHT as the technology of choice for building community health apps Delivering effective interventions Novel projects or interventions Developing skills Strengths and Assets Diversity in skills sets: HCD, software development, database management, dashboard development Resourcefulness: bend the CHT&amp;rsquo;s capabilities to meet a given need Passion for problem solving An inquisitive mind</description></item></channel></rss>