<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Security</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apps: Securing Android Devices</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/security/securing-android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/security/securing-android/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To secure an android device you should enable at least a pin code lock on the device, enable FDE (full disc encryption) and setup remote wiping capabilities by enabling mobile device management.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pin-setup-and-fde">PIN Setup and FDE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Instructions are slightly different per device. Enabling FDE has the added benefit that you must also lock the device with a pin code or password.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-50-or-later">Android 5.0 or later&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Open the &lt;code>Security&lt;/code> menu under settings. On unmodified versions of Android, this
can be found under &lt;code>Settings&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;gt;&lt;/code> &lt;code>Personal&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;gt;&lt;/code> &lt;code>Security&lt;/code>. Choose &lt;code>Encrypt Phone&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Encrypt Tablet&lt;/code>, or &lt;code>Encrypt Device&lt;/code>. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already set a PIN
or passcode for the lock screen, you will be prompted to do so. Remember this
PIN and do not write it down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="encrypt-50.jpg" alt="Screenshot for Android 5.0">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-44-or-earlier">Android 4.4 or earlier&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set up a PIN. Navigate to &lt;code>Settings&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;gt;&lt;/code> &lt;code>Security&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;gt;&lt;/code>
&lt;code>Screen Lock&lt;/code>, and set a numeric PIN for the device of &lt;em>at least&lt;/em> four digits.
Remember this PIN and do not write it down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, open the &lt;code>Security&lt;/code> menu under settings. On unmodified versions of
Android, this can be found under &lt;code>Settings&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;gt;&lt;/code> &lt;code>Personal&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;gt;&lt;/code> &lt;code>Security&lt;/code>.
On some devices, the exact menu layout may have been modified by the hardware
manufacturer. Choose &lt;code>Encrypt Phone&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Encrypt Tablet&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="encrypt-44.jpg" alt="Screenshot for Android 4.4">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-versions-before-30">Android Versions before 3.0&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Android does not support disk encryption in versions earlier than 3.0
(Honeycomb). If you have one of these devices, we recommend that you do not use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mobile-device-management">Mobile device management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Using mobile device management (MDM) software allows administrators to remotely manage mobile devices, which often includes the option to delete apps and data from lost or stolen mobile devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many commercially available MDM tools to evaluate. &lt;a href="https://workspace.google.com/intl/en_us/products/admin/endpoint/">Google Endpoint&lt;/a> is available for organizations using Google Workspace (formerly G Suite), which has free plans for non-profit organizations. Check out the &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/1734200">Endpoint documentation overview&lt;/a> for more information, including &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/7400753">how to enable mobile device management&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/173390">how to remotely wipe a device&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>