<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Features of CHT Applications</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/</link><description>Recent content in Features of CHT Applications on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reports</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Reports tab is where you can access submitted data. Depending on how often you anticipate a user needing to access this tab, you can configure it to show in the main tabs list (preferable for admin users) or in the secondary hamburger menu (preferable for CHW users).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The permissions set for your role and your placement in the hierarchy will determine which reports you’re able to see on this tab. As a rule, you can only view reports submitted by yourself or those below you in the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/workflows/hierarchy/" >hierarchy&lt;/a>. Therefore, CHWs will only see reports that they submitted on this tab, while supervisors will see reports that they submitted as well as those submitted by their CHWs. Advanced configuration options are available for a specific off-line user role to manage what &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/replication/#report-depth" >level of report data&lt;/a> is copied to their device.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-mobile.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-mobile.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-desktop.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-desktop.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2>Main List&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="main-list">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#main-list" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-mobile.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-mobile.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The first line of bold text is the name of the person whom the report is about. The second line of text is the name of the report, and the third line of text is the hierarchy of place to which that person belongs. In the upper right corner, a timestamp displays when the report was submitted. Reports are sorted by submission date, with the most recent reports at the top. If a report is unread, the timestamp will be bold blue and there will be a horizontal blue line above it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apps built with the Core Framework have a “review” feature that allows managers to indicate whether a report has been reviewed and if it contains errors. If a manager has marked a report as “correct,” a green checkmark will show below the timestamp. If a report is marked as “has errors,” a red ‘X’ will show. This same icon is used for invalid SMS messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2>Filters &amp;amp; Search&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="filters--search">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#filters--search" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The toolbar at the top of the page includes filters and search to help users narrow down the list or search for and find a specific report. These filters are configurable and could include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Report Types&lt;/strong> (e.g. pregnancy registration, visits, delivery report)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Places&lt;/strong> (e.g. districts, health centers or CHW areas)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date of Submission&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> (e.g. not reviewed, has errors, correct, valid SMS, invalid SMS)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Using the search box, you can search for reports by patient name, phone number, ID number and more. To reset the filters and view the full list of forms, click on &amp;ldquo;Reset&amp;rdquo; located in the filter sidebar.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-search.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-search.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-search-reset.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-search-reset.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;div class="hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-flex-col hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-4 hx-px-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200">
&lt;p class="hx-flex hx-items-center hx-font-medium">&lt;svg height=16px class="hx-inline-block hx-align-middle hx-mr-2" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M13 16h-1v-4h-1m1-4h.01M21 12a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z"/>&lt;/svg>Note&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7">
&lt;div class="hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0">&lt;p>A new user experience for Filter and Search was introduced in v3.17. The previous version can be re-enabled for users by adding the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/" >permission&lt;/a> &lt;code>can_view_old_filter_and_search&lt;/code> to the user&amp;rsquo;s role; however, the old version should be considered deprecated and will be completely removed in a future release. See &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/updates/feature-flags/" >Feature Flags&lt;/a> documentation for more info&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2>Action Buttons&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="action-buttons">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#action-buttons" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The action buttons at the bottom of the screen are configurable using &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/" >permissions&lt;/a>. Options include submit, edit, delete, review and export reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking on the “Export” button will download a CSV file with all the data from the reports. And clicking the “+ Submit report” button opens a menu of forms a user can choose to complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-desktop.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-desktop.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2>Bulk Delete Reports&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="bulk-delete-reports">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#bulk-delete-reports" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Allows the user to select multiple reports and delete them. &lt;strong>Please Note&lt;/strong>: This action cannot be undone. If in doubt, do not delete! You can restrict a user’s access to this feature by disabling the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/" >permission&lt;/a> &lt;code>can_bulk_delete_reports&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-bulk-mobile.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-bulk-mobile.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-bulk-desktop.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-bulk-desktop.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2>Detail Pages&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="detail-pages">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#detail-pages" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-detail.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/reports/reports-detail.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>You can click on any report to view a report detail page. Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find the name and phone number of the user who submitted the report as well as responses to the questions within it. If the report initiated a schedule of SMS messages, you will see the messages queued to send.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The buttons at the bottom are configurable. The ones you see will depend on your user role, permissions, and hierarchy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Send a Message&lt;/strong>​: Opens the Messages page to send a message to the person who submitted the report&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Review&lt;/strong>: Mark as “correct” or “has errors”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong>: Opens the form to edit it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Delete&lt;/strong>: Deletes a report ( cannot be undone)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2>Defining Forms&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="defining-forms">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#defining-forms" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The reports shown in your app are the completed and submitted &lt;em>forms&lt;/em>. These forms must be defined and included with the application. There are two types of form definitions for reports:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>App forms&lt;/strong>: actions within the app, such as a completed task, or an action on a contact&amp;rsquo;s profile or reports tab. App forms are defined as &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/forms/app/" >XForms&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>JSON forms&lt;/strong>: data coming from external channels such as SMS, or via interoperability with other tools. JSON forms are defined using a &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/forms/" >JavaScript Object Notation schema&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Supervision</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Supervision and workforce management are important aspects to building and maintaining high-performing community health systems. Supervisors help Community Health Workers deliver quality healthcare services to their patients through building CHW care delivery knowledge and skills, fostering a supportive work environment, and supporting continuity of care between home-based care and community health centers or facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The importance of regular and systematic CHW supervision is emphasized by the WHO’s &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241550369" target="_blank" rel="noopener">guidelines&lt;/a> on health policy and system support, which is formulated to optimize community-based health worker programs. Following these guidelines, the CHT is designed to enable Supervisors to provide personalized performance feedback during CHW supervision as well as track aggregate statistics. Data collected from completed &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/concepts/care-guides/" >Care Guides&lt;/a> produce granular information which can be used to provide coaching that promotes compliance with health program standards of practice and closer monitoring of outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>CHW Aggregate Targets&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="chw-aggregate-targets">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#chw-aggregate-targets" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;figure class="right col-7 col-lg-6">&lt;a href="aggregate-supervisor.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/aggregate-supervisor.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For CHW Supervisors, the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/targets/targets-overview/" >Targets&lt;/a> tab provides important insights into their community unit. It presents Supervisors with actionable information about their CHWs, by aggregating data for each of the CHWs that a Supervisor manages and presenting it in an easily digestible format. This enables Supervisors to gain insight into how well their team of CHWs is working together to meet common goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Selecting an aggregate widget opens the detailed view with the data for each individual CHW. If a CHW is performing below the target goal, their value will be highlighted in red, making it easier for Supervisors to know with which CHWs to follow up for coaching and performance management.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-flex-col hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-4 hx-px-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200">
&lt;p class="hx-flex hx-items-center hx-font-medium">&lt;svg height=16px class="hx-inline-block hx-align-middle hx-mr-2" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M13 16h-1v-4h-1m1-4h.01M21 12a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z"/>&lt;/svg>Note&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7">
&lt;div class="hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0">&lt;p>Aggregate targets were introduced in v3.9, and can be configured for both online and offline users. Aggregate targets are based on the widgets seen by CHWs, and dependent on the data that has been synced. If a CHW or the supervisor has not synced, then the aggregate target will not be up to date.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3>Filtering Aggregate Targets&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="filtering-aggregate-targets">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#filtering-aggregate-targets" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The ability for one user to manage multiple areas / facilities was introduced in v4.9.0. With that change it was important for users who manage multiple areas to filter aggregate targets by the respective facilities. The ability for users to filter Aggregate Targets was introduced in v4.10.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following images show the various screens CHW supervisors see in Aggregate Targets. The example user in this illustration manages two facilities: &lt;strong>First Health Facility&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Second Health Facility&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="multi-facility-aggregate-supervisor-landing.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/multi-facility-aggregate-supervisor-landing.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>This is the landing page for the Aggregate Targets for a user who manages multiple areas / facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The name of the facility appears in the breadcrumbs of the aggregate widgets on the Left Hand Side list and underneath the Target Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the Top Right the user can click the &lt;strong>Filter&lt;/strong> button to open the sidebar and change the Aggregate Targets of the other facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="multi-facility-aggregate-supervisor-filter.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/multi-facility-aggregate-supervisor-filter.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Clicking the &lt;strong>Filter&lt;/strong> button opens the sidebar, which allows the user to filter the Aggregate Targets by &lt;strong>Facility&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Reporting Period&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Selecting the Second Health Facility in the filter updates the Facility name in the breadcrumbs of the aggregate widgets on the Left Hand Side list and underneath the Target Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="multi-facility-aggregate-supervisor-period.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/multi-facility-aggregate-supervisor-period.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Filtering the Aggregate Targets by &lt;strong>Reporting Period&lt;/strong> adds the name of the previous month to the breadcrumbs of the aggregate widgets on the Left Hand Side list and in the Target details.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="one-facility-aggregate-supervisor-period.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/one-facility-aggregate-supervisor-period.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Users who manage one area / facility can only filter their Aggregate Targets by &lt;strong>Reporting Period&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The name of the facility &lt;strong>does not&lt;/strong> appear in the breadcrumbs of the aggregate widgets on the Left Hand Side list or underneath the Target Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Filtering the Aggregate Targets by &lt;strong>Reporting Period&lt;/strong> adds the name of the previous month to the breadcrumbs of the aggregate widgets on the Left Hand Side list and in the Target Details.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;div class="hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-flex-col hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-4 hx-px-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200">
&lt;p class="hx-flex hx-items-center hx-font-medium">&lt;svg height=16px class="hx-inline-block hx-align-middle hx-mr-2" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M13 16h-1v-4h-1m1-4h.01M21 12a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z"/>&lt;/svg>Note&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7">
&lt;div class="hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0">&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The list of facilities in the sidebar are sorted in alphabetic order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The default filter option for the facilities filter is the first facility in the sorted &lt;code>array&lt;/code> of user Facilities.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The default filter option for the reporting period is &lt;code>This month&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The facility filter label in this example (Health Facility) is the &lt;code>name_key&lt;/code> of the facility &lt;code>contact_type&lt;/code> configured in the the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/reference/app-settings/hierarchy/" >app-settings&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The reporting period label in this example (Reporting Period) is added as a translation key &lt;code>analytics.target.aggregates.reporting_period&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2>Supervisor Tasks&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="supervisor-tasks">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#supervisor-tasks" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The CHT can be configured to create &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/" >Tasks&lt;/a> for Supervisors to help plan their performance management reviews. Tasks can be generated based on routine CHW supervision interactions, or data-driven based on specific events (e.g. to follow up with health workers whom haven’t submitted any forms in x period of time). Using Supervisor tasks to ensure that the right actions are taken for the right CHWs at the right time strengthens supervisory program design through routine assessments and timely feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Deployment Case Study&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="deployment-case-study">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#deployment-case-study" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.musohealth.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Muso&lt;/a>, a leading community health organization and major contributor to the CHT, has implemented ”360º supervision”, achieving some of the lowest child mortality rates in sub-Saharan Africa. This model provides dedicated mentorship and supportive supervision to CHWs tailored to each CHW&amp;rsquo;s particular strengths and challenges. A key theme of our human-centered approach was the idea of using data to improve one-to-one supervision, rather than using analytics to replace Supervisors. Read more about findings from a recent &lt;a href="https://medic.org/stories/new-study-precision-supervision-and-personalized-feedback-dashboards-improve-chw-performance-in-mali/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">randomized controlled trial&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>User Management&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="user-management">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#user-management" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Supervisors are able to set up users in the CHT without contacting a system administrator. They can &lt;strong>create&lt;/strong> new CHW user accounts or &lt;strong>replace&lt;/strong> CHWs on an existing device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When &lt;em>creating&lt;/em> a new user account, Supervisors fill out the necessary details, including the CHW&amp;rsquo;s phone number, from their own device. They can do this while offline, but must sync before the actual user account is created. Once the Supervisor syncs, the CHT will send an SMS to the new CHW with a &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/concepts/access/#magic-links-for-logging-in-token-login" >magic link&lt;/a> that enables them to login and start using the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When &lt;em>replacing&lt;/em> a CHW, Supervisors access the existing device and provide details about the new CHW. The new CHW can start using the app immediately, even while offline, and will see all of the existing household data. Once the new CHW syncs, the records on the server will be updated to reflect the new CHWs details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be used to manage both CHW and CHW supervisor roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Managing Multiple Areas&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="managing-multiple-areas">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#managing-multiple-areas" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>CHT hierarchies tend to mimic geographical areas but Supervisors often manage CHWs across multiple geographical areas. (Offline) Supervisors who manage multiple areas can see data for all the different areas they manage from one app.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-flex-col hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-4 hx-px-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200">
&lt;p class="hx-flex hx-items-center hx-font-medium">&lt;svg height=16px class="hx-inline-block hx-align-middle hx-mr-2" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M13 16h-1v-4h-1m1-4h.01M21 12a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z"/>&lt;/svg>Note&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7">
&lt;div class="hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0">&lt;p>The ability for one user to replicate data from multiple areas was introduced in v4.9.0. A video demonstration of setting up a multi-facility user and what this looks like from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective can be found &lt;a href="https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/support-for-supervisors-who-need-to-manage-multiple-areas/3497/2?u=michael" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the forum&lt;/a> and in the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/hrhdrzP41gE?si=_7wglk7Nm7CCSFbY&amp;amp;t=606" target="_blank" rel="noopener">June 2024 CHT Round-up&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2>Supervisor Dashboards&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="supervisor-dashboards">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#supervisor-dashboards" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;figure class="right col-7 col-lg-6">&lt;a href="supervisor-dashboards.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/supervision/supervisor-dashboards.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Program dashboards track, visualize, and share health progress with stakeholders more broadly. Supervisors can use program dashboards to help articulate their CHW cohorts activities and how they align with program impact standards and indicators. Summary statistics of CHW service area performance (e.g. number of home visits, number of protocol errors, etc) help to identify areas for continued improvement and deeper audits of care data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The data that can be visualized is highly configurable, and depends on what data fields are configured in a particular CHT app’s forms. Dashboards can be built using any software that supports visualizing data with the widely used PostgreSQL database. Examples include the open source tool &lt;a href="https://superset.incubator.apache.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Superset&lt;/a>, as well as proprietary technologies like &lt;a href="https://www.klipfolio.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Klipfolio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.tableau.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tableau&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>DHIS2 Data Verification&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="dhis2-data-verification">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#dhis2-data-verification" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Supervisors often provide a critical bridge between CHWs and broader health system reporting. Using the CHT’s &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/integrations/dhis2/" >DHIS2 integration&lt;/a>, Supervisors can see the aggregate of each DHIS2 Data Value across all CHWs in their area. By tapping on a target, they can also see each CHW’s contribution towards that total. Once the Supervisor has verified data accuracy with CHWs, they can communicate with Health Records Information Officers to feed data into the national health information system.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200">
&lt;div class="ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2">&lt;div class="hx-select-none hx-text-xl" style="font-family: 'Apple Color Emoji', 'Segoe UI Emoji', 'Segoe UI Symbol';">ℹ️&lt;/div>&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7">
&lt;div class="hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0">DHIS2 integration was introduced in v3.9.&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Universal Health Coverage Mode</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/uhc-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/uhc-mode/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-flex-col hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-4 hx-px-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-indigo-200 hx-bg-indigo-100 hx-text-indigo-900 dark:hx-border-indigo-200/30 dark:hx-bg-indigo-900/30 dark:hx-text-indigo-200">
&lt;p class="hx-flex hx-items-center hx-font-medium">&lt;svg height=16px class="hx-inline-block hx-align-middle hx-mr-2" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M13 16h-1v-4h-1m1-4h.01M21 12a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z"/>&lt;/svg>Important&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7">
&lt;div class="hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0">&lt;p>CHT apps using the &lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em> empower CHWs to provide equitable and timely care to families in their catchment area. This feature was &lt;a href="https://www.musohealth.org/post/new-study-demonstrates-how-digital-health-tools-can-enable-progress-towards-universal-health-care" target="_blank" rel="noopener">codeveloped with Muso&lt;/a>, and showed an increase in household coverage for both rural and peri-urban settings, thereby increasing the effectiveness of CHWs and improving access to care for the populations they serve.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2>UHC with the CHT&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="uhc-with-the-cht">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#uhc-with-the-cht" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Apps built using the Community Health Toolkit can be used in support of community-based services, and increase Universal Health Coverage (UHC) by helping health workers regularly reach all the families that they care for. A Muso study in collaboration with Medic, &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fXruezV7sCo-CtJfi8WDivzgMcKZNdXM/view" target="_blank" rel="noopener">showed an increase in household coverage&lt;/a>: &lt;em>UHC Mode should be considered an effective tool that can improve minimum expected home visit coverage and promote progress towards UHC when implemented in the proactive community case management context.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Prioritizing Households&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="prioritizing-households">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#prioritizing-households" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="UHC.gif">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/uhc-mode/UHC.gif"
alt="UHC Mode screenshot">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="sort-dropdown.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/uhc-mode/sort-dropdown.png"
alt="Contact sorting screenshot">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em> in the CHT allows health workers to see when a household within their care area was last visited, and prioritize visits accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When using the &lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em>, the households in the contact list can be sorted by when they were last visited. The days since the last visit is also shown in the app, along with the number of visits made to a household in a month period.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Configurability&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="configurability">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#configurability" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The last visited date is calculated based on the number of days since an action was taken for that household, and the number of visits reflects the actions taken for that household in the current month. What constitutes as an action for a household, along with the start date for the reporting period, &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/forms/configuring/uhc-mode/" >are configurable&lt;/a> to CHT app developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>App Management</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/admin/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;em>App Management&lt;/em> is an interface for non-technical administrative users. With it you can manage users and make minor changes to the app, such as setting the SMS gateway phone number, and changing the default language for the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>App Management&lt;/strong> pages are a desktop-only interface meant for users with a reliable internet connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure class="col-12 col-lg-10">&lt;a href="admin-roles.png">&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/admin/admin-roles.png">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Page Tabs&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="page-tabs">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#page-tabs" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>These sections of the App can be configured from within the Admin Console:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong>: Change basic settings like gateway phone number &amp;amp; country code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Languages&lt;/strong>: Set default app language, update translations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Forms&lt;/strong>: Upload XML and JSON forms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Import &amp;amp; Export&lt;/strong>: Import and export settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Upgrade Instance&lt;/strong>: Install a newer app version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>: View and edit users of the system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Icons&lt;/strong>: View and edit icons used in the app&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Targets&lt;/strong>: Modify performance or activity targets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Roles &amp;amp; Permissions&lt;/strong>: Fine tuned control of user roles and permissions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2>App Management vs cht-conf&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="app-management-vs-cht-conf">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#app-management-vs-cht-conf" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In general, everything that can be done in the &lt;strong>Admin Console&lt;/strong> can also be done in command line tools, but not everything in the command line tools can be done in the &lt;strong>Admin Console&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Admin Console&lt;/strong> does not track changes. For most app development, using command line tools such as cht-conf and tracking files using a version control system is recommended&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Admin Console But Not Command Line Tools:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>User management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>Upgrades&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Command Line Tools But Not Admin Console:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Most of the JSON settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XLS → Xform conversion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>