<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hosting on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/</link><description>Recent content in Hosting on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHT hosting requirements</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/requirements/</guid><description>For production CHT deployments, Linux is recommended, with Ubuntu the most commonly used. For App Developer Hosting, Linux or macOS may be used. Windows can be used for either, but without recommendation.
Per the Kubernetes vs Docker page, CHT Core can be deployed with either Docker or Kubernetes.
CHT 3.x is End-of-Life and us no longer supported. All requirements below apply to CHT 4.x.
Docker Compose App Developer Hosting 4 GB RAM / 2 CPU / 8 GB SSD Root Access TLS certificates - Docker Helper for 3.</description></item><item><title>Vertical vs Horizontal scaling</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/vertical-vs-horizontal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/vertical-vs-horizontal/</guid><description>IntroductionHorizontally scaling is the ability to add more servers to an application to make it more performant. This often yields better performance than vertical scaling, which is adding more resources like RAM or CPU to a single server.
CHT Core 4.0.0 introduces a new architecture for hosting which gives it the ability to easily scale horizontally. This enables large deployments to support more concurrent users and better utilize the underlying server hardware.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes vs Docker</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/kubernetes-vs-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/kubernetes-vs-docker/</guid><description>Since the release of CHT Core 4.0.0 in late 2022, Medic has been perfecting the hosting for the toolkit to balance the need for high uptimes so CHWs can always deliver care while having an easy and approachable technical back end hosting solution. While initially Docker Compose with an overlay network was thought to be our goto solution, field testing this overlay networks in production has shown them to unreliable.</description></item></channel></rss>