<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributing to the CHT Documentation on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Contributing to the CHT Documentation on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Documentation Workflow</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/docs/workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/docs/workflow/</guid><description>Getting StartedAnyone can contribute to CHT documentation by opening an issue in the cht-docs repo or by using the “Edit this page” or “Create documentation issue” links in the upper right corner of your window.
Basics It is helpful to be comfortable with git and GitHub to contribute to the CHT community. The documentation source is in GitHub. The content pages are in the /content/en/ directory. Documentation is written in Markdown.</description></item><item><title>Documentation Style Guide</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/docs/style-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/docs/style-guide/</guid><description>This style guide provides a set of editorial guidelines for anyone writing documentation for Community Health Toolkit projects. These are guidelines, not rules. Use your best judgment.
Note This documentation site does not involve release management and acceptance testing. Help us maintain the quality of our documentation by submitting a pull request (PR) with any suggested changes. One of the repository&amp;rsquo;s maintainers will review the PR, request additional changes as needed, and merge the PR when it is ready.</description></item></channel></rss>