<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Features of CHT Applications</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/</link><description>Recent content in Features of CHT Applications on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apps: Contacts</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/</guid><description>
&lt;!-- ## Contacts: Person and Family Profiles -->
&lt;!-- TODO Refine screenshots, and add desktop view. -->
&lt;p>“People” is the generic name used for individuals in apps built with the Core Framework. They can be patients, family members, nurses or health workers. Anyone with a profile in your app is a person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Places” is the generic name that represents a level in the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/concepts/hierarchy/">hierarchy&lt;/a>. “People” belong to “places”, and “places” belong to other higher level “places” in the hierarchy. A “place” could be a geographic area, like a district with the &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; associated to it being health officers. A &amp;ldquo;place&amp;rdquo; could also be a structure in the health system, such as a health facility, and the &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; associated to it being nurses. In deployments with CHWs, the lowest &amp;ldquo;place&amp;rdquo; in the hierarchy often represents individual households or families, and the individual members of that household are the &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; associated to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users can access their “people” and “places” from the &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong> tab. The permissions set for your role and your placement in the hierarchy will determine which contacts you’re able to see. Advanced configuration options are available for a specific offline user role to manage what &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/performance/replication/#contact-depth">level of contact data&lt;/a> is downloaded and stored on their device.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="people-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/people-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="people-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/people-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="main-list">Main List&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="sort-dropdown.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/sort-dropdown.png"
alt="Contact sorting screenshot"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="people-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/people-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list view on the leftmost screenshot is what a logged-in CHW would see when they access the “People” tab on a small screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The item at the top of the list is the “place” the user belongs to. Below that is a list of the “places” they serve, represented by families. Individual “people” are not shown here, but will appear in search results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because this list defaults to show the “places” below the user in the hierarchy, a CHW supervisor would see a different view. Instead of families, they might see a list of CHW Areas they manage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New “places” can be added to this level of the hierarchy by clicking on the “Add new +” button at the bottom of the screen. This allows a CHW to add a new family to their list, or a CHW supervisor to add a new Area they manage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/uhc-mode/">&lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em>&lt;/a> configured, the main list of households is displayed as shown on the rightmost screenshot to help health workers ensure that all households are visited regularly.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="searching">Searching&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="search-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/search-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Click on the search icon at the top of the screen to search for a “person” or “place”. The freetext search works on all fields included in the “person” or “place” document such as patient name or patient ID. The exact fields depends on which information you’ve configured your app to collect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After typing a search term, press the &amp;ldquo;Enter&amp;rdquo; key on your keyboard, then the list filters to show matching items. Searching will only return items that are lower than you in the hierarchy and that you have permission to view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To clear the search and return to the default view, click on the arrow icon located to the left of the search box.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="profiles">Profiles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clicking an item on the main list will open a profile where you can see detailed information about that person or place. At the top is general information like name and phone number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re viewing a place profile, you’ll see a list of people or places that belong to this place in the app hierarchy, such as family members. The star signifies the primary contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beneath that, you will find tasks for this person or place. At the very bottom is a history of submitted reports for this person or place.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="container">
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="profile1.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/profile1.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="profile2.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/profile2.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="profile3.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/profile3.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="profile4.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/profile4.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>From profiles, users can edit contact information, take actions, and, if viewing a place profile, add new people and assign a primary contact person. If a place is not at the bottom of the hierarchy, a user can add new places to the level below this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fields">Fields&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="contact-summary">Contact Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The top card on all profiles contains general information for the contact. All the fields shown in this summary card are configurable.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="container">
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-4">&lt;a href="bio1.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/bio1.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-4">&lt;a href="bio2.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/bio2.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;em>See Also&lt;/em>: &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/contact-page/#contact-summary">Defining Contact Summary&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="condition-cards">Condition Cards&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A “condition” card displays data on a profile that’s been submitted in a report about that person or place. Data can be pulled from one report or summarize many reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Condition cards can be permanent or conditional; set to appear only when a specific type of report is submitted. They can also be set to disappear when a condition is resolved or a certain amount of time has passed. You can have as many condition cards as you like, though we recommend keeping the user’s experience in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Configurable elements include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Title&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Label for each data point displayed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data point for the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Icon for the field, if desired&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conditions under which to display&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="container">
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-4">&lt;a href="condition-card1.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/condition-card1.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-4">&lt;a href="condition-card2.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/condition-card2.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;em>See Also&lt;/em>: &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/contact-page/#condition-cards">Defining Condition Cards&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="care-guides">Care Guides&lt;/h2>
&lt;!-- todo: Resolve Care Guides vs Actions -->
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="care-guides.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/contacts/care-guides.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>“Care Guides” are dynamic forms that you can fill out for a person or place. You can access Care Guides by clicking on the + button at the bottom of a profile. For more info, see the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/concepts/care-guides/">Care Guides overview page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’ll see different forms here depending on which person or place you’re viewing. For example, forms for families might include a “Family Survey.” Forms for adult women might include “New Pregnancy.” Forms for adult women who have had a pregnancy report, and no delivery yet reported, would also see “ANC visit.” Forms for children might include “Under-5 Assessment” or “Growth Monitoring.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Health workers can use these Care Guides at any time. If the app has scheduled a care visit or follow up, it will be listed under “Tasks.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>See Also&lt;/em>: &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/contact-page/#care-guides">Defining Care Guides&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;!-- TODO:
## Defining Contact Forms
--></description></item><item><title>Apps: Messaging</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/messaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/messaging/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Messaging is a quick way to coordinate with other health workers. The Messages tab allows users to send a SMS message to any person or group of people in the app. Common uses of messages include asking questions, coordinating care logistics, providing encouragement or confirming training times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main list is a combination of both outgoing and incoming messages. Messages exchanged with the same person or group are organized into a thread, similar to messages in a phone’s messaging app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The features on the Messages tab are best supported on desktop and most often used by someone in a supervisor role.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="messages-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/messaging/messages-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="messages-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/messaging/messages-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="main-list">Main List&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="messages-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/messaging/messages-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>On the main list of messages, the first line of bold text is the name and / or phone number of the sender. The second line is an excerpt from the most recent message, and the third line, if applicable, is the place(s) that the sender belongs to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the upper right corner, a timestamp displays when the most recent message was sent. An unread message is indicated by a blue line and bold blue timestamp. Messages are sorted by date with the most recent at the top of the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To send a new message that starts a brand new conversation thread, select the “Send Message +” button at the bottom of the screen. On the new message screen, enter the phone number you would like to send the message to or select a person in the app from the drop-down list. Then, type out your message text.
&lt;br clear="all">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="detail-page">Detail Page&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="messages-detail.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/messaging/messages-detail.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Clicking on a message in the main list will take you to a detail tab where you can see the full text of the conversation. Underneath each individual message in the conversation, you will see the message status which tells you whether or not the message was successfully delivered or received and at what time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To reply to a message, tap or click in the box at the bottom of the conversation that says “Reply to…” and start typing. Each message is limited to 160 characters but you may send more than one message if necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also possible to configure auto-responses and for schedules of personalized, automated messages to be triggered upon submission of a form (e.g., a pregnancy registration triggers a schedule of personalized Antenatal care messages).
&lt;br clear="all">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: Reports</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Reports tab is where you can access submitted data. Depending on how often you anticipate a user needing to access this tab, you can configure it to show in the main tabs list (preferable for admin users) or in the secondary hamburger menu (preferable for CHW users).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The permissions set for your role and your placement in the hierarchy will determine which reports you’re able to see on this tab. As a rule, you can only view reports submitted by yourself or those below you in the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/concepts/hierarchy/">hierarchy&lt;/a>. Therefore, CHWs will only see reports that they submitted on this tab, while supervisors will see reports that they submitted as well as those submitted by their CHWs. Advanced configuration options are available for a specific off-line user role to manage what &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/performance/replication/#report-depth">level of report data&lt;/a> is copied to their device.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="main-list">Main List&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The first line of bold text is the name of the person whom the report is about. The second line of text is the name of the report, and the third line of text is the hierarchy of place to which that person belongs. In the upper right corner, a timestamp displays when the report was submitted. Reports are sorted by submission date, with the most recent reports at the top. If a report is unread, the timestamp will be bold blue and there will be a horizontal blue line above it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apps built with the Core Framework have a “review” feature that allows managers to indicate whether a report has been reviewed and if it contains errors. If a manager has marked a report as “correct,” a green checkmark will show below the timestamp. If a report is marked as “has errors,” a red ‘X’ will show. This same icon is used for invalid SMS messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="filters--search">Filters &amp;amp; Search&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The toolbar at the top of the page includes filters and search to help users narrow down the list or search for and find a specific report. These filters are configurable and could include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Report Types&lt;/strong> (e.g. pregnancy registration, visits, delivery report)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Places&lt;/strong> (e.g. districts, health centers or CHW areas)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date of Submission&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> (e.g. not reviewed, has errors, correct, valid SMS, invalid SMS)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Using the search box, you can search for reports by patient name, phone number, ID number and more. To reset the filters and view the full list of forms, click on &amp;ldquo;Reset&amp;rdquo; located in the filter sidebar.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-search.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-search.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-search-reset.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-search-reset.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
A new user experience for Filter and Search was introduced in v3.17. The previous version can be re-enabled for users by adding the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/">permission&lt;/a> &lt;code>can_view_old_filter_and_search&lt;/code> to the user’s role; however, the old version should be considered deprecated and will be completely removed in a future release. See &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/updates/feature-flags/">Feature Flags&lt;/a> documentation for more info
&lt;/div>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="action-buttons">Action Buttons&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The action buttons at the bottom of the screen are configurable using &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/">permissions&lt;/a>. Options include submit, edit, delete, review and export reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking on the “Export” button will download a CSV file with all the data from the reports. And clicking the “+ Submit report” button opens a menu of forms a user can choose to complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="bulk-delete-reports">Bulk Delete Reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Allows the user to select multiple reports and delete them. &lt;strong>Please Note&lt;/strong>: This action cannot be undone. If in doubt, do not delete! You can restrict a user’s access to this feature by disabling the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/">permission&lt;/a> &lt;code>can_bulk_delete_reports&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-bulk-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-bulk-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="reports-bulk-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-bulk-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="detail-pages">Detail Pages&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="reports-detail.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/reports-detail.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>You can click on any report to view a report detail page. Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find the name and phone number of the user who submitted the report as well as responses to the questions within it. If the report initiated a schedule of SMS messages, you will see the messages queued to send.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The buttons at the bottom are configurable. The ones you see will depend on your user role, permissions, and hierarchy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Send a Message&lt;/strong>​: Opens the Messages page to send a message to the person who submitted the report&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Review&lt;/strong>: Mark as “correct” or “has errors”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong>: Opens the form to edit it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Delete&lt;/strong>: Deletes a report ( cannot be undone)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="defining-forms">Defining Forms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The reports shown in your app are the completed and submitted &lt;em>forms&lt;/em>. These forms must be defined and included with the application. There are two types of form definitions for reports:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>App forms&lt;/strong>: actions within the app, such as a completed task, or an action on a contact&amp;rsquo;s profile or reports tab. App forms are defined as &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/forms/app/">XForms&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>JSON forms&lt;/strong>: data coming from external channels such as SMS, or via interoperability with other tools. JSON forms are defined using a &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/forms/">JavaScript Object Notation schema&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Apps: Supervision</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Supervision and workforce management are important aspects to building and maintaining high-performing community health systems. Supervisors help Community Health Workers deliver quality healthcare services to their patients through building CHW care delivery knowledge and skills, fostering a supportive work environment, and supporting continuity of care between home-based care and community health centers or facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The importance of regular and systematic CHW supervision is emphasized by the WHO’s &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241550369">guidelines&lt;/a> on health policy and system support, which is formulated to optimize community-based health worker programs. Following these guidelines, the CHT is designed to enable Supervisors to provide personalized performance feedback during CHW supervision as well as track aggregate statistics. Data collected from completed &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/concepts/care-guides/">Care Guides&lt;/a> produce granular information which can be used to provide coaching that promotes compliance with health program standards of practice and closer monitoring of outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="chw-aggregate-targets">CHW Aggregate Targets&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-7 col-lg-6">&lt;a href="aggregate-supervisor.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/aggregate-supervisor.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For CHW Supervisors, the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/">Targets&lt;/a> tab provides important insights into their community unit. It presents Supervisors with actionable information about their CHWs, by aggregating data for each of the CHWs that a Supervisor manages and presenting it in an easily digestible format. This enables Supervisors to gain insight into how well their team of CHWs is working together to meet common goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Selecting an aggregate widget opens the detailed view with the data for each individual CHW. If a CHW is performing below the target goal, their value will be highlighted in red, making it easier for Supervisors to know with which CHWs to follow up for coaching and performance management.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
Aggregate targets were introduced in v3.9, and can be configured for both online and offline users. Aggregate targets are based on the widgets seen by CHWs, and dependent on the data that has been synced. If a CHW or the supervisor has not synced, then the aggregate target will not be up to date.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="supervisor-dashboards">Supervisor Dashboards&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-7 col-lg-6">&lt;a href="supervisor-dashboards.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/supervisor-dashboards.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Program dashboards track, visualize, and share health progress with stakeholders more broadly. Supervisors can use program dashboards to help articulate their CHW cohorts activities and how they align with program impact standards and indicators. Summary statistics of CHW service area performance (e.g. number of home visits, number of protocol errors, etc) help to identify areas for continued improvement and deeper audits of care data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The data that can be visualized is highly configurable, and depends on what data fields are configured in a particular CHT app’s forms. Dashboards can be built using any software that supports visualizing data with the widely used PostgreSQL database. Examples include the open source tool &lt;a href="https://superset.incubator.apache.org">Superset&lt;/a>, as well as proprietary technologies like &lt;a href="https://www.klipfolio.com">Klipfolio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.tableau.com">Tableau&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dhis2-data-verification">DHIS2 Data Verification&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Supervisors often provide a critical bridge between CHWs and broader health system reporting. Using the CHT’s &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/integrations/dhis2/">DHIS2 integration&lt;/a>, Supervisors can see the aggregate of each DHIS2 Data Value across all CHWs in their area. By tapping on a target, they can also see each CHW’s contribution towards that total. Once the Supervisor has verified data accuracy with CHWs, they can communicate with Health Records Information Officers to feed data into the national health information system.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
DHIS2 integration was introduced in v3.9.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="supervisor-tasks">Supervisor Tasks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The CHT can be configured to create &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/">Tasks&lt;/a> for Supervisors to help plan their performance management reviews. Tasks can be generated based on routine CHW supervision interactions, or data-driven based on specific events (e.g. to follow up with health workers whom haven’t submitted any forms in x period of time). Using Supervisor tasks to ensure that the right actions are taken for the right CHWs at the right time strengthens supervisory program design through routine assessments and timely feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;h3 id="deployment-case-study">Deployment Case Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.musohealth.org">Muso&lt;/a>, a leading community health organization and major contributor to the CHT, has implemented ”360º supervision”, achieving some of the lowest child mortality rates in sub-Saharan Africa. This model provides dedicated mentorship and supportive supervision to CHWs tailored to each CHW&amp;rsquo;s particular strengths and challenges. A key theme of our human-centered approach was the idea of using data to improve one-to-one supervision, rather than using analytics to replace Supervisors. Read more about findings from a recent &lt;a href="https://medic.org/stories/new-study-precision-supervision-and-personalized-feedback-dashboards-improve-chw-performance-in-mali/">randomized controlled trial&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="user-management">User Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Supervisors are able to set up users in the CHT without contacting a system administrator. They can &lt;strong>create&lt;/strong> new CHW user accounts or &lt;strong>replace&lt;/strong> CHWs on an existing device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When &lt;em>creating&lt;/em> a new user account, Supervisors fill out the necessary details, including the CHW&amp;rsquo;s phone number, from their own device. They can do this while offline, but must sync before the actual user account is created. Once the Supervisor syncs, the CHT will send an SMS to the new CHW with a &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/concepts/access/#magic-links-for-logging-in-token-login">magic link&lt;/a> that enables them to login and start using the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When &lt;em>replacing&lt;/em> a CHW, Supervisors access the existing device and provide details about the new CHW. The new CHW can start using the app immediately, even while offline, and will see all of the existing household data. Once the new CHW syncs, the records on the server will be updated to reflect the new CHWs details.&lt;br>
This can be used to manage both CHW and CHW supervisor roles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: Tasks</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Tasks help CHWs plan their day by prompting them to complete follow-up visits and other activities. The list might include upcoming scheduled ANC or Immunization visits, treatment or referral follow-ups, or other required activities such as a household survey.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="tasks-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="tasks-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="main-list">Main List&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="tasks-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>On the Tasks tab is a consolidated list of tasks for all people and families that the user looks after. The task definition determines how long the task will show on this list before and after it is due.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each task has an icon on the left side which indicates which type of task it is. The first bold line of text is the person or family that the task is about. The second line of text is the name of the task. The due date for the task is located in the upper right-hand corner. If a task is overdue, the due date will be red.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tasks are listed in order of due date. Tasks that are past due will appear at the top of the list. CHWs should strive to complete tasks before they are overdue. Many programs add targets to track task completion and timeliness.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h2 id="care-guides">Care Guides&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When a CHW clicks on a task, the care guide configured for that task displays. CHWs are then guided through questions for that specific workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="container">
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="tasks-care1.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-care1.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="tasks-care2.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-care2.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="tasks-care3.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-care3.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="tasks-care4.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-care4.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>For more information on Care Guides, see the “&lt;a href="">Decision Support for Care Guides&lt;/a>” section of this overview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the user completes the care guide, the task will be cleared from the Tasks tab, and the report will be accessible from the Reports page or on the profile of the person or place whom the report is about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="household-tasks">Household Tasks&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-household.png"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Alternatively, there is an option to configure Household Tasks. When this &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/user-permissions/">permission&lt;/a> is enabled, once a CHW has completed a task, they are taken to the Other Household Tasks page. This page shows the CHW all the additional outstanding tasks within the same household in which the initial task was completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHWs are able to complete tasks directly from this page, or exit by tapping on the “X”. If the household has no additional tasks, they will return directly to the main task list.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="profile-page">Profile Page&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/tasks/tasks-profile.png"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Tasks are also accessed from a the People tab in the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tasks for a particular person or place can be viewed on the contact’s profile in the “Tasks” section. Filters allow you to choose how many tasks you’d like to view for each due date.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all"></description></item><item><title>Apps: Targets</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/</guid><description>
&lt;!-- ## Targets: Performance Dashboards -->
&lt;p>&lt;em>Targets&lt;/em> is the user dashboard or analytics tab. The widgets on this tab provide a summary or analysis of the data in submitted reports. These widgets can be configured to track metrics for an individual CHW, for a Supervisor overseeing a group of CHWs, or for an entire health facility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For CHWs, the &lt;strong>Targets&lt;/strong> tab provides a quick summary of their progress towards their individual goals. For Supervisors, Nurses, and facility-based users, the &lt;strong>Targets&lt;/strong> tab provides important insights into how their community unit is performing.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left col-3 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="targets-mobile.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/targets-mobile.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="targets-desktop.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/targets-desktop.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
Targets or goals can be configured for any user that has offline capabilities. A user must have access to the report in order to generate the widget with its data.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="types-of-widgets">Types of Widgets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are two basic types of widgets: count and percent. &lt;em>Count widgets&lt;/em> display a numeric sum while &lt;em>percent widgets&lt;/em> display progress towards achieving a target.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The text, icon, goal, and time frame of each widget is easily configured. The time frame is set per widget, and set to show values for &amp;ldquo;this month&amp;rdquo; (resets back to zero at the beginning of each month) or &amp;ldquo;all time&amp;rdquo; (a cumulative total).&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;h3 id="count-widgets">Count Widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="right col-7 col-lg-4">&lt;a href="targets-count.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/targets-count.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Count widgets show a tally of a particular report that has been submitted or data within a report that matches a set of criteria. For example, a count can be done for the number of new pregnancies, the number of facility-based deliveries, or the number of households registered that month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A count without a goal displays a simple green number count. A count with a goal displays the value of the goal on the right side and a colored count in the center indicating progress towards achieving the goal. Progress is displayed in green if the count is equal to or above the goal, or in black if the count is below the goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="percent-widgets">Percent Widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="right col-7 col-lg-4">&lt;a href="targets-percentage.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/targets/targets-percentage.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Percent widgets display a ratio, which helps to provide insight into the proportion that matches a defined criteria. For example, the proportion of newborns delivered in a facility can be presented as a percent with respect to all registered deliveries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An optional goal can be set, such as “100% of patients with a fever should be given a malaria Rapid Diagnostic Test (mRDT),” to visualize progress towards achieving a target. Widget styling is configured to show green if the goal has been met and black if the goal has not been met. Next to the percent with a goal, the count of reports used in the calculation are shown (e.g. “16 of 20 with mRDT”). CHWs have found this helpful in interpreting target information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: Training</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/training/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/training/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Training Cards&lt;/em> help health workers learn about changes to CHT apps remotely, directly in their app. Training content might include information about a newly deployed feature, changes to a &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/concepts/care-guides/">care guide&lt;/a>, or simply a reminder about an underused feature or workflow. They are perfect for training on a very specific topic and are not meant to replace a comprehensive onboarding program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/training/training-cards-resources/">Template training content&lt;/a> for new CHT features is made available from time to time. These templates can be customized to the local context.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="col-12 col-lg-10">&lt;a href="training-deck.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/training/training-deck.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="accessing">Accessing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When health workers open or reload their app, configured training cards will automatically show on top of all other content in the app. If it is not a convenient time to complete the training, they can cancel out at any time and will be prompted again later whenever they open or reload their app (training will start from the beginning).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
If there are multiple training sets configured to start on the same day, the CHT will determine the order alphabetically based on the form ID. Subsequent training sets will only be displayed once the previous ones are either completed or no longer valid AND the app is opened or reloaded again.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="completing">Completing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Health workers read through each card one by one in a predefined sequence, tapping “Next” on each card. When they are finished reading all cards, they tap “Submit” on the last card. The training set is now considered complete and they can continue using their app. Completed training sets show up on the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/#main-list">main list&lt;/a> of the Reports tab and they won’t be asked to complete this set again. If there are additional training sets to complete, they will be shown the next time the app is opened or reloaded.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="monitoring">Monitoring&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As mentioned above, completed training sets will show up on the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/reports/#main-list">main list&lt;/a> of the Reports tab. These reports are available in &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/#supervisor-dashboards">analytics&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/#chw-aggregate-targets">aggregate targets&lt;/a> , and can trigger supervision workflows and &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/supervision/#supervisor-tasks">tasks&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configurability">Configurability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Training cards can be shown to any user associated to a contact. A “set” of training cards represents a collection of individual training cards, generally covering a single training topic. The list below highlights some of the key areas of customization:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of sets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of cards in a set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content of each individual card (text, images, etc…)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When health workers will start seeing a set (specific start date)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How long the set will be available (# of days, relative to the start date)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Which users will see the set (based on user roles)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Apps: Muting</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/muting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/muting/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Muting is a way for CHWs to temporarily silence notifications about Contacts (people and places) and is commonly used when a person or family has temporarily relocated or refused services. When a Contact is muted, they will appear differently on the People tab and CHWs will no longer receive tasks or SMS about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To start receiving notifications about a Contact again, CHWs can &lt;em>unmute&lt;/em> them. When a Contact is unmuted, tasks and SMS schedules will resume, but notifications that would have been sent while they were muted will not.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mute-a-contact">Mute a Contact&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To mute a Contact, CHWs typically submit a &amp;ldquo;Mute&amp;rdquo; form about them. This can be done either from the People tab or the Reports tab. When a person is muted, in addition to their notifications being silenced, their icon turns grey and a &amp;ldquo;Muted&amp;rdquo; status is displayed beneath their name. While a person or place is muted, CHWs and Nurses can still submit other forms about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class=" right col-9 col-lg-9">&lt;a href="muted_person.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/muting/muted_person.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Some changes are observed in the UI when a family or a person is muted to make the muted status clear and easily recognizable. The person&amp;rsquo;s or family&amp;rsquo;s icon turns grey and a status of “Muted” displays on the second line below the person&amp;rsquo;s or family&amp;rsquo;s name. Any actions that were previously available on the family or person remain available on the profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a place is muted, all places and people beneath it will automatically be muted as well. For example, if a family is muted, all individuals in that family will automatically be muted. It is not possible to have a muted family with some family members that are not muted. This means that if a new person is added to a muted family, that person will automatically be muted when they are created.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="unmute-a-contact">Unmute a Contact&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To unmute a Contact, CHWs typically submit an &amp;ldquo;Unmute&amp;rdquo; form. This will remove the &amp;ldquo;Mute&amp;rdquo; styling, resume notifications, and also unmute all places above them in the hierarchy. For example, if a family member is unmuted, the entire family will automatically be unmuted since it is not possible to have an unmuted person in a muted family.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="configurability">Configurability&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While it&amp;rsquo;s most common to have dedicated mute and unmute forms, any form can be set up to mute or unmute a Contact. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to set up verification flows for muting whereby mute/unmute requires a Supervisor to verify before the mute/unmute happens. And like the rest of the CHT, all text is customizable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="muting-vs-death-reporting">Muting vs Death Reporting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A project may support both death reporting and muting - they are not mutually exclusive. Death reporting moves the deceased person to a different part of the family members list and does not allow actions. Muting keeps the person in the family members list, allows actions and disables schedules.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Death reporting&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Muting&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Permanent state&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Temporary state&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Only allowed at the individual level&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Place, family, or individual level&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Removes schedules&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>“Quiets” notifications for schedules&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>A deceased individual is removed from the family list&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>A muted individual is not removed from the family list&lt;br>&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>&lt;p>No new actions can be performed&lt;/p>&lt;p>except for one - reverse the death&lt;/p>&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>New actions may be performed, but no tasks or notifications will be sent&lt;br>&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Manager confirmation configurable&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;p>&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Manager confirmation configurable&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Apps: Universal Health Coverage Mode</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/uhc-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/uhc-mode/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>CHT apps using the &lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em> empower CHWs to provide equitable and timely care to families in their catchment area. This feature was &lt;a href="https://www.musohealth.org/post/new-study-demonstrates-how-digital-health-tools-can-enable-progress-towards-universal-health-care">codeveloped with Muso&lt;/a>, and showed an increase in household coverage for both rural and peri-urban settings, thereby increasing the effectiveness of CHWs and improving access to care for the populations they serve.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="uhc-with-the-cht">UHC with the CHT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Apps built using the Community Health Toolkit can be used in support of community-based services, and increase Universal Health Coverage (UHC) by helping health workers regularly reach all the families that they care for. A Muso study in collaboration with Medic, &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fXruezV7sCo-CtJfi8WDivzgMcKZNdXM/view">showed an increase in household coverage&lt;/a>: &lt;em>UHC Mode should be considered an effective tool that can improve minimum expected home visit coverage and promote progress towards UHC when implemented in the proactive community case management context.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prioritizing-households">Prioritizing Households&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="UHC.gif">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/uhc-mode/UHC.gif"
alt="UHC Mode screenshot"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-3">&lt;a href="sort-dropdown.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/uhc-mode/sort-dropdown.png"
alt="Contact sorting screenshot"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em> in the CHT allows health workers to see when a household within their care area was last visited, and prioritize visits accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When using the &lt;em>UHC Mode&lt;/em>, the households in the contact list can be sorted by when they were last visited. The days since the last visit is also shown in the app, along with the number of visits made to a household in a month period.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configurability">Configurability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The last visited date is calculated based on the number of days since an action was taken for that household, and the number of visits reflects the actions taken for that household in the current month. What constitutes as an action for a household, along with the start date for the reporting period, &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/uhc-mode/">are configurable&lt;/a> to CHT app developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apps: App Management</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/admin/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;em>App Management&lt;/em> is an interface for non-technical administrative users. With it you can manage users and make minor changes to the app, such as setting the SMS gateway phone number, and changing the default language for the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>App Management&lt;/strong> pages are a desktop-only interface meant for users with a reliable internet connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="col-12 col-lg-10">&lt;a href="admin-roles.png">
&lt;img src="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/admin/admin-roles.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="page-tabs">Page Tabs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These sections of the App can be configured from within the Admin Console:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong>: Change basic settings like gateway phone number &amp;amp; country code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Languages&lt;/strong>: Set default app language, update translations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Forms&lt;/strong>: Upload XML and JSON forms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Import &amp;amp; Export&lt;/strong>: Import and export settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Upgrade Instance&lt;/strong>: Install a newer app version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>: View and edit users of the system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Icons&lt;/strong>: View and edit icons used in the app&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Targets&lt;/strong>: Modify performance or activity targets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Roles &amp;amp; Permissions&lt;/strong>: Fine tuned control of user roles and permissions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="app-management-vs-cht-conf">App Management vs cht-conf&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In general, everything that can be done in the &lt;strong>Admin Console&lt;/strong> can also be done in command line tools, but not everything in the command line tools can be done in the &lt;strong>Admin Console&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Admin Console&lt;/strong> does not track changes. For most app development, using command line tools such as cht-conf and tracking files using a version control system is recommended&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Admin Console But Not Command Line Tools:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>User management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~Upgrades~&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Command Line Tools But Not Admin Console:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Most of the JSON settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XLS → Xform conversion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Apps: Integrations</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/integrations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/features/integrations/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>