<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Health Toolkit – Features of CHT Applications</title>
    <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features of CHT Applications on Community Health Toolkit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Contacts</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/contacts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;!-- ## Contacts: Person and Family Profiles --&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO Refine screenshots, and add desktop view. --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People” is the generic name used for individuals in apps built with the Core Framework. They can be patients, family members, nurses or health workers. Anyone with a profile in your app is a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Places” is the generic name that represents a level in the hierarchy. “People” belong to “places” and “places” belong to other higher level “places” in the hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the context, a “place” might be a health facility and the “people” who get created at that level might be nurses. Most often for CHWs, these “places” are families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can access their “people” and “places” from the People tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-list&#34;&gt;Main List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-main-list.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-main-list.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view on the right is what a logged-in CHW would see in when they access the “People” tab on a small screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The item at the top of the list is the “place” the user belongs to. Below that is a list of the “places” they serve, represented by families. Individual “people” are not shown here, but will appear in search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because this list defaults to show the “places” below the user in the hierarchy, a CHW supervisor would see a different view. Instead of families, they might see a list of CHW Areas they manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New “places” can be added to this level of the hierarchy by clicking on the “Add new +” button at the bottom of the screen. This allows a CHW to add a new family to their list, or a CHW supervisor to add a new Area they manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;searching&#34;&gt;Searching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click in the search area at the top of the screen to search for a “person” or “place”. The freetext search works on all fields included in the “person” or “place” document such as patient name or patient ID. The exact fields depends on which information you’ve configured your app to collect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After entering a search term, the list filters to show matching items. Searching will only return items that are lower than you in the hierarchy and that you have permission to view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clear the search and return the default view, click on the refresh icon located to the right of the search box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;profiles&#34;&gt;Profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking an item on the main list will open a profile where you can see detailed information about that person or place. At the top is general information like name and phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-profile-1.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-profile-1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-profile-2.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-profile-2.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-profile-3.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-profile-3.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-profile-4.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-profile-4.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re viewing a place profile, you’ll see a list of people or places that belong to this place in the app hierarchy, such as family members. The star signifies the primary contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beneath that, you will find tasks for this person or place. At the very bottom is a history of submitted reports for this person or place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From profiles, users can edit contact information, take actions, and, if viewing a place profile, add new people and assign a primary contact person. If a place is not at the bottom of the hierarchy, a user can add new places to the level below this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fields&#34;&gt;Fields&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top card on all profiles contains general information for the contact. All the fields shown in this summary card are configurable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See Also:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/reference/contact-page/#contact-summary&gt;Defining Contact Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;condition-cards&#34;&gt;Condition Cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “condition” card displays data on a profile that’s been submitted in a report about that person or place. Data can be pulled from one report or summarize many reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-condition-card-1.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-condition-card-1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-condition-card-2.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-condition-card-2.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Condition cards can be permanent or conditional; set to appear only when a specific type of report is submitted. They can also be set to disappear when a condition is resolved or a certain amount of time has passed. You can have as many condition cards as you like, though we recommend keeping the user’s experience in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configurable elements include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label for each data point displayed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data point for the field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Icon for the field, if desired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditions under which to display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See Also:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/reference/contact-page/#condition-cards&gt;Defining Condition Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;care-guides&#34;&gt;Care Guides&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!-- todo: Resolve Care Guides vs Actions --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;contacts-care-guides.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;contacts-care-guides.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Care Guides” are dynamic forms that you can fill out for a person or place. You can access Care Guides by clicking on the + button at the bottom of a profile. For more info, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/concepts/care-guides/&#34;&gt;Care Guides overview page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll see different forms here depending on which person or place you’re viewing. For example, forms for families might include a “Family Survey.” Forms for adult women might include “New Pregnancy.” Forms for adult women who have had a pregnancy report, and no delivery yet reported, would also see “ANC visit.” Forms for children might include “Under-5 Assessment” or “Growth Monitoring.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health workers can use these Care Guides at any time. If the app has scheduled a care visit or follow up, it will be listed under “Tasks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See Also:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/reference/contact-page/#care-guides&gt;Defining Care Guides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO:
## Defining Contact Forms
--&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Messaging</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/messaging/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Messaging is a quick way to coordinate with other health workers. The Messages tab allows users to send a SMS message to any person or group of people in the app. Common uses of messages include asking questions, coordinating care logistics, providing encouragement or confirming training times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main list is a combination of both outgoing and incoming messages. Messages exchanged with the same person or group are organized into a thread, similar to messages in a phone’s messaging app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The features on the Messages tab are best supported on desktop and most often used by someone in a supervisor role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-list&#34;&gt;Main List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;messages-main.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;messages-main.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the main list of messages, the first line of bold text is the name and / or phone number of the sender. The second line is an excerpt from the most recent message, and the third line, if applicable, is the place(s) that the sender belongs to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the upper right corner, a timestamp displays when the most recent message was sent. An unread message is indicated by a blue line and bold blue timestamp. Messages are sorted by date with the most recent at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To send a new message that starts a brand new conversation thread, select the “Send Message +” button at the bottom of the screen. On the new message screen, enter the phone number you would like to send the message to or select a person in the app from the drop-down list. Then, type out your message text.
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;detail-page&#34;&gt;Detail Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;messages-detail.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;messages-detail.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on a message in the main list will take you to a detail tab where you can see the full text of the conversation. Underneath each individual message in the conversation, you will see the message status which tells you whether or not the message was successfully delivered or received and at what time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reply to a message, tap or click in the box at the bottom of the conversation that says “Reply to…” and start typing. Each message is limited to 160 characters but you may send more than one message if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to configure auto-responses and for schedules of personalized, automated messages to be triggered upon submission of a form (e.g., a pregnancy registration triggers a schedule of personalized Antenatal care messages).
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Reports</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/reports/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Reports tab is where you can access submitted data. Depending on how often you anticipate a user needing to access this tab, you can configure it to show in the main tabs list (preferable for admin users) or in the secondary hamburger menu (preferably for CHW users).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The permissions set for your role and your placement in the hierarchy will determine which reports you’re able to see on this tab. As a rule, you can only view reports submitted by yourself or those below you in the hierarchy. Therefore, CHWs will only see reports that they submitted on this tab, while supervisors will see reports that they submitted as well as those submitted by their CHWs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-list&#34;&gt;Main List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reports-main.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;reports-main.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first line of bold text is the name of the person whom the report is about. The second line of text is the name of the report, and the third line of text is the hierarchy of place to which that person belongs. In the upper right corner, a timestamp displays when the report was submitted. Reports are sorted by submission date, with the most recent reports at the top. If a report is unread, the timestamp will be bold blue and there will be a horizontal blue line above it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps built with the Core Framework have a “review” feature that allows managers to indicate whether a report has been reviewed and if it contains errors. If a manager has marked a report as “correct,” a green checkmark will show below the timestamp. If a report is marked as “has errors,” a red ‘X’ will show. This same icon is used for invalid SMS messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;filters--search&#34;&gt;Filters &amp;amp; Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reports-search.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;reports-search.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toolbar at the top of the page includes filters and search to help users narrow down the list or search for and find a specific report. These filters are configurable and could include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report Types&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. pregnancy registration, visits, delivery report)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Places&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. districts, health centers or CHW areas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date of Submission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. not reviewed, has errors, correct, valid SMS, invalid SMS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the search box, you can search for reports by patient name, phone number, ID number and more. To reset the filters or the search and view  the full list of forms, click on the reset icon on the right side of the toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;action-buttons&#34;&gt;Action Buttons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reports-bulk.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;reports-bulk.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action buttons at the bottom of the screen are configurable. Options include adding or completing a care guide, bulk select &amp;amp; export.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking the “+” button opens a menu of forms a user can choose to complete. “Bulk Select,” represented by a checkmark icon within a circle, allows you to bulk select and delete multiple reports at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Bulk delete cannot be undone. If in doubt, do not delete! You can restrict a user’s access to this feature in the permissions for their role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the “Export” button will download a CSV file with all of the data from the reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;detail-pages&#34;&gt;Detail Pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reports-detail.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;reports-detail.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can click on any report to view a report detail page. Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find the name and phone number of the user who submitted the report as well as responses to the questions within it. If the report initiated a schedule of SMS messages, you will see the messages queued to send.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buttons at the bottom are configurable. The ones you see will depend on your user role, permissions, and hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send a Message&lt;/strong&gt;​: Opens the Messages page to send a message to the person who submitted the report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark as “correct” or “has errors”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: Opens the form to edit it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete&lt;/strong&gt;: Deletes a report ( cannot be undone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-forms&#34;&gt;Defining Forms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reports shown in your app are the completed and submitted &lt;em&gt;forms&lt;/em&gt;. These forms must be defined and included with the application. There are two types of form definitions for reports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App forms&lt;/strong&gt;: actions within the app, such as a completed task, or an action on a contact&amp;rsquo;s profile or reports tab. App forms are defined as &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;XForms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JSON forms&lt;/strong&gt;: data coming from external channels such as SMS, or via interoperability with other tools. JSON forms are defined using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/reference/app-settings/json-forms/&#34;&gt;JavaScript Object Notation schema&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Tasks</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/tasks/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Tasks help CHWs plan their day by prompting them to complete follow-up visits and other activities. The list might include upcoming scheduled ANC or Immunization visits, treatment or referral follow-ups, or other required activities such as a household survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-list&#34;&gt;Main List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tasks-main.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;tasks-main.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Tasks tab is a consolidated list of tasks for all people and families that the user looks after. The task definition determines how long the task will show on this list before and after it is due.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each task has an icon on the left side which indicates which type of task it is. The first bold line of text is the person or family that the task is about. The second line of text is the name of the task. The due date for the task is located in the upper right hand corner. If a task is overdue, the due date will be red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasks are listed in order of due date. Tasks that are past due will appear at the top of the list. CHWs should strive to complete tasks before they are overdue. Many programs add targets to track task completion and timeliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;care-guides&#34;&gt;Care Guides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a CHW clicks on a task, the care guide configured for that task displays. CHWs are then guided through questions for that specific workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tasks-care1.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;tasks-care1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tasks-care2.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;tasks-care2.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tasks-care3.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;tasks-care3.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tasks-care4.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;tasks-care4.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on Care Guides, see the “&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Decision Support for Care Guides&lt;/a&gt;” section of this overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the user completes the care guide, the task will be cleared from the Tasks tab, and the report will be accessible from the Reports page or on the profile of the person or place whom the report is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;profile-page&#34;&gt;Profile Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;tasks-profile.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks are also accessed from a the People tab in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasks for a particular person or place can be viewed on the contact’s profile in the “Tasks” section. Filters allow you to choose how many tasks you’d like to view for each due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Targets</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/targets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/targets/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;!-- ## Targets: Performance Dashboards --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targets is a user dashboard or analytics tab. These widgets provide a summary or analysis of the data in reports that have been submitted. These widgets can be configured to track metrics for an individual CHW or for an entire health facility. Currently, the user must have access to the report in order to generate the widget with its data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For CHWs, the Targets tab can provide a quick summary of their progress towards their goals. For supervisors, nurses, and other facility-based users, these widgets might display important insights into how their community unit is performing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targets can be configured for any user that has offline access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-widgets&#34;&gt;Types of Widgets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;right col-6 col-lg-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;targets-main.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;targets-main.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two basic types of widgets: counts and percentages. Count widgets display a number while percentage widgets display a horizontal bar that represents 100%. Every element is configurable, including the text, the icon, the presence of a goal (or not), the value of the goal, the time frame, and the total number of widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data for both widgets is calculated as either “this month” (resets back to 0 at the beginning of each month) or “all time” (a cumulative total). The time frame is per widget level so there can be a mix of date ranges on the Targets page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, each widget can have a goal and there can be a mix of widgets with and without goals. If goals are set, the widgets have conditional color styling to show whether a goal is unmet (red) or met (green) based on configured rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;count-widgets&#34;&gt;Count Widgets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The count widget shows a tally of a particular report that’s been submitted or data within a report that matches a set of criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you could count the number of active pregnancies, the number of facility-based deliveries, or the number of households or people registered that month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Counts without a goal display a simple black number count. Counts with a goal display the value of the goal on the right side and a colored count (green if the count is above the goal, or red if the count is below the goal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;percent-widgets&#34;&gt;Percent Widgets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Percentage widgets provide insight into how much data matches a specific criteria against data that does not. This is calculated based on a true / false statement. This is often configured to represent accomplishment. For example, newborns should be visited within the first three days of life (“true”) can be displayed next to newborns that were not visited within the first three days (“false”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to the percentage, the count of reports used in the calculation are shown (e.g. 16 of 20 [newborn visits] on-time). CHWs have found this helpful in interpreting this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An optional goal can be set, such as “70% of newborns should be visited within the first three days.” Conditional styling can be configured to show green if a goal has been met and red if the goal has not been met.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: App Management</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/admin/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;App Management is an interface for non-technical administrative users. With it they can manage users and make minor changes to the app, such as setting the SMS gateway phone number, and changing the default language for the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The App Management pages are a desktop-only interface meant for users with a reliable internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;col-12 col-lg-8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;admin-roles.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;admin-roles.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;page-tabs&#34;&gt;Page Tabs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These sections of the App can be configured from within the Admin Console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt;: Change basic settings like gateway phone number &amp;amp; country code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages&lt;/strong&gt;: Set default app language, update translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forms&lt;/strong&gt;: Upload XML and JSON forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Import &amp;amp; Export&lt;/strong&gt;: Import and export settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrade Instance&lt;/strong&gt;: Install a newer app version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt;: View and edit users of the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Icons&lt;/strong&gt;: View and edit icons used in the app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Targets&lt;/strong&gt;: Modify performance or activity targets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roles &amp;amp; Permissions&lt;/strong&gt;: Fine tuned control of user roles and permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;app-management-vs-medic-conf&#34;&gt;App Management vs medic-conf&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, everything that can be done in the Admin Console can also be done in command line tools, but not everything in the command line tools can be done in the Admin Console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Admin Console does not track changes. For most app development, we recommend using command line tools such as medic-conf and tracking files using a version control system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Admin Console But Not Command Line Tools:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~Upgrades~&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Command Line Tools But Not Admin Console:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the JSON settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XLS → Xform conversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Integrations</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/features/integrations/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
