<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tracking and Improving Performance on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/</link><description>Recent content in Tracking and Improving Performance on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Purging</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/purging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/purging/</guid><description>Only available in 3.7.0 and above
Purging is a tool that allows you to increase performance and available disk space for offline users (eg CHWs) by removing unneeded documents from their device.
As users continually generate new reports their performance may naturally degrade as a result. You can use purging to remove older documents that are no longer relevant from their devices. Purging only removes documents from user&amp;rsquo;s devices: these reports are still available for online analytics and impact metrics.</description></item><item><title>CouchDB replication</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/replication/</guid><description>Replication is what we call it when users download a copy of the data on to their device.
Restricting replicationIf the user has an online role they can access all the data, otherwise they will get restricted access to the data.
Restriction by placeThe most common restriction is by place. This is where we check the user&amp;rsquo;s facility_id property, and allow access to all contacts that are descendants of that place, and all reports and messages that are about one of those descendants.</description></item><item><title>User telemetry</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/performance/telemetry/</guid><description>Introduced in v3.4.0
The app collects performance data on certain user actions which is then aggregated each day and replicated to the server. This can be used to evaluate the performance of the code and configuration and to evaluate where improvements can be made.
The aggregate doc for the previous day is created when the first telemetry item is recorded each day. This is stored in the medic-user-&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;-meta database on the device and replicated to the server when an internet connection is available.</description></item></channel></rss>