<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Core Framework Releases</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Core Framework Releases on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Core: Feature Releases</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/feature_releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/feature_releases/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To build and iterate on new features at a pace that is faster than our regular release cycle, some features are released in a &lt;em>Feature Release&lt;/em>. Feature Releases are based on the most recent release and only include improvements related to a feature being developed. These releases are tested to be production-ready so that new features can be studied with CHT partners in a live deployment, with the aim of getting the feature ready for wider use in an upcoming release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-names">Release names&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Feature Release can easily be identified by its version, which follows the pattern of &lt;code>{BASE-RELEASE-NUMBER}-FR-{FEATURE-NAME}&lt;/code>. For example, if the latest release is &lt;code>3.10.1&lt;/code> then the Feature Release for speedier upgrades would be &lt;code>3.10.1-FR-speedier-upgrades&lt;/code>. When this feature is found to be successful and ready for wider distribution it will be included in the next release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="upgrades">Upgrades&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once the feature is ready for widespread use it will be included in a regular CHT release. Projects using the feature version can be upgraded as soon as practical to get back on to a fully supported release.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 0.x release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/0.4.15-and-earlier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/0.4.15-and-earlier/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="0415">0.4.15&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>March 2, 2017&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed potential race condition with medic-gateway. Issue: medic-projects/issues/1243&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bumped libphonenumber to make phone number validation more up to date. Issue: medic-projects/issues/1005&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0414">0.4.14&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>December 16, 2016&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bug fix for medic-gateway sending scheduled messages. Issue: #2535&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0413">0.4.13&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>October 21, 2016&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Option to set birthdate using days old instead of weeks. Issue: #2756&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The week/month is off by 2 in the Reporting Rates analytics dashboard. Issue: #2781&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove socket limit in medic-api. Issue: #2632&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0412">0.4.12&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>July 21, 2016&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed bug in reporting rates for weekly time unit. #2429&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Log warnings in sentinel when ID collisions happen. #1898&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support integration with &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-gateway">medic-gateway&lt;/a> for sending and receiving SMS medic-api#69&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0411">0.4.11&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>February 4, 2016&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Security fix for leaking auth info.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0410">0.4.10&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Nov 16, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added support for Outgoing Deny List, a comma separated list of phone numbers
or strings to deny outgoing service to. #750&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug in records export. #1273&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bugs in uniqueWithin validation. medic-sentinel#74&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added link to Help page in main menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="049">0.4.9&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Aug 26, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug on node 0.12 in felix-couchdb. #1145&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Improved error handling when notifications (start/stop) configs are
misconfigured. #1144&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug in &lt;code>exists&lt;/code> validation where it fails on some unicode characters. #1147&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed Reporting Rates interface that was neglected and broken. #1030&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug in exporting data by date, it&amp;rsquo;s now inclusive. #1104&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="048">0.4.8&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>July 14, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added SMS parser fixes from dev branch:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>parse string fields with exclamation marks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>compact textforms format handles quotes in quotes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed export bug when using lowercase form codes. Please re-upload your forms
so they are formatted correctly. #998&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where exporting yields same result with or without date
filter. #1059, #1031&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="047">0.4.7&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>June 16, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed ODK forms list bug when the list is empty. Issue #886&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed compact textforms parser bug with exclamation points. Issue #989&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug in compact textforms parser we ignored fields with uppercase
letters in the key of the form definition. Issue #991&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug when creating record with empty message. Issue #990&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Moved raw message to bottom of report body. Issue: #927&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="046">0.4.6&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>June 4, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Improved boolean expression evaluation in registration configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="045">0.4.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>May 28, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug in schedules editor for LMP (last menstrual period) based
schedules. #973&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Initial support for messages, records and forms API. See
&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-api/blob/master/API_v1.md">https://github.com/medic/medic-api/blob/master/API_v1.md&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="044">0.4.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>May 21, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added support for a new messages parser we&amp;rsquo;re calling Javarosa prefixed with
the &lt;code>J1&lt;/code> format code.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="043">0.4.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>February 26, 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Major UI enhancements #370&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Inbox Style with advanced search bar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Admin Panels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile device support&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Configurable date format #577&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Built-in ANC Analytics #586&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Easy user feedback mechanism #19&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added help and tour&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Refactored build process, added grunt, bower and jshint.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>No forms are included by default. You must upload your forms. As usual
configuration (settings and forms) persists through upgrades.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added new translations&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Default auto-replies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are now two ways to export stuff: 1) from the reports screen click on
export, or 2) on the Configuration &amp;gt; Export screen. The former is simplified
and has no way of changing facility, form, or file format. The latter is
functionally equivalent to 0.4.2.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="upgrade-notes">Upgrade Notes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>CouchDB Lucene &amp;gt;= 1.0.2&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Gardener &amp;gt;= 1.1.0&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>New &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-os/blob/3aedf0622eb0669aee2e5bbfba95a42faf05b9da/platform/packages/medic-core/settings/medic-core/nginx/nginx.conf">Nginx configuration&lt;/a>, close or redirect port 5984, proxy all requests through medic-api.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="042">0.4.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>September 4, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed bug: When searching for a patient identifier using the free-text search feature, results were not returned properly. Index the field appropriately.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="041">0.4.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>July 31, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Minor UI clean up.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allow hash symbol to separate form code and data in structured textform message.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modified build to bundle npm dependencies with attached node modules.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="040">0.4.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>July 10, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-features">New Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>User interface for common settings and translations #484&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>User interface to configure basic ANC messaging workflows #487&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nodejs module for API calls and to handle audit transactions&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Better language support on messages throughout configuration. e.g. you can
define a reminder schedule using multiple languages and the right language
will be used based on the locale of the message. #486&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added support to configure locales through settings screen #491&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added support for custom forms and uploading JSON form definitions #283&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Supporting old/obsolete settings via migrations during restore #501&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Support minute setting for scheduled hours configuration&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reduced files size of design doc by minifying javascript and combining files&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added support for unique validations across multiple fields. #412&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>External IDs can be added to facilities on the facility page. #503&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added &lt;code>columns&lt;/code> query parameter to allow callers to messages and data_records
exports to retrieve specific columns in a specific order. #503&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Patient ID field to default data record export&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allow specifying of task columns in message export.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To include the group column, include the parameter &lt;code>columns=[&amp;quot;task.group&amp;quot;]&lt;/code>
(and any other columns you need, eg: &lt;code>patient_id&lt;/code>). #432&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allow range searches on number fields in lucene. #481&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug stopping district admins from being able to delete documents. #509&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Corrected language Nepalese to Nepali&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed too many requests for app_settings #511&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed saving user password, was getting reset/wiped #509&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Render facilities controls on all facilities tabs. #338&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="deprecated-and-backwards-incompatible-changes">Deprecated and Backwards Incompatible changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>deprecated &lt;code>exclude_cols&lt;/code> parameter for export integrations. Migrate
applications to use the &lt;code>columns&lt;/code> parameter instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>No forms are included by default, you must upload your forms. As usual
configuration (settings and forms) persists through upgrades.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0311">0.3.11&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>June 19, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where scheduled messages were out of order on Chrome #527&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where app settings was ignored, and the app reverted to defaults. #524&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added delivery form to generic ANC forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modified behavior of patient reports when &lt;code>silence_for&lt;/code> option is empty we
clear the entire schedule instead of a group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed notifications to add the configured response #508&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug and added support for multiple schedules in schedule silencing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When &lt;code>silence_for&lt;/code> is specified we should only silence/clear one group, I
introduced a bug a few commits ago that would ignore the group and
silence/clear based on date. Use the &lt;code>silence_for&lt;/code> window to match and
clear the first group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also added support for comma separate string on &lt;code>silence_type&lt;/code> option.
In the MCH case we have two schedules that can be generated depending on
the form submission/registration: ANC Reminders and ANC Reminders LMP.
Now both schedules can be cleared with a single ANCV settings entry.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0310">0.3.10&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>June 12, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>updated intrahealth-senegal forms&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="039">0.3.9&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>May 22, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>fixed a bug in settings parser, to conform to the latest app-settings
changes, otherwise configs never get triggered.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="038">0.3.8&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>May 22, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>fixed bug in messages export filters to include all data records,
unstructured messages were being ignored. #502&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>added support for app-settings kanso package.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saving settings in dashboard was too slow for use because entire ddoc was
being updated. Using app-settings API fixes that.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="037">0.3.7&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>May 13, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Modified KEMRI form fields to be ordered the same as KEMR form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="036">0.3.6&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>April 28, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed bug in updating duplicate scheduled reports #483&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="035">0.3.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>April 16, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Major bug fix that was introduced in 0.3.3 where visit reports do not get processed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fixed accept_patient_reports transition so it calls db for readonly actions
instead of audit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allow analytics role to download messages and forms. Issue: #477&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Updated user management to show role for analytics user. Issue: #478&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Initial version of forms for Miraclefeet India&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="034">0.3.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>April 14, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>translate strings on user mgmt facilities select list #474&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Change ordering of messages export format for better readability based on
when the state is triggered. #475&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From: Received, Sent, Pending, Scheduled Cleared, Muted
To: Received, Scheduled, Pending, Sent, Cleared, Muted&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="033">0.3.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>April 10, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed spreadsheet keyboard navigation. #448&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Validate &amp;lsquo;Everyone at x&amp;rsquo; for at least one valid phone number. #333&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Audit support for data records and facility data #415&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also includes support for export of audit data as XML or CSV file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: Only new records and record edits will have an audit log entry. So
this means your audit log will only contain changes to records after the
upgrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similarly browsing old revision will stop working for old records because
they lack audit log entries. If this is a major problem for you let us
know and we can add backwards compatible revision browsing in the next
release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This has been released as a standalone re-useable module for Node and
browser environments: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/couchdb-audit">https://github.com/medic/couchdb-audit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added support for compact version of TextForms format #428&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In compact Textforms fields are delimited by spaces and determined by order.
So no hashes or field keys are required like in classic TextForms format.
If your field value has spaces in it then it must be surrounded by quotes
unless it is the last field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> REG 4165550000 John Smith
REG &amp;quot;John Smith&amp;quot; 4165550000
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Include state change timestamps and patient_id in messages export #453&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Old Columns:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Record UUID, Reported Date, From, Clinic Contact Name, Clinic Name, Health
Center Contact Name, Health Center Name, District Hospital Name, Message
Type, Message State, Message Timestamp/Due, Message UUID, Sent By, To
Phone, Message Body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New Columns:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Record UUID, Patient ID, Reported Date, Reported From, Clinic Contact Name,
Clinic Name, Health Center Contact Name, Health Center Name, District
Hospital Name, Message Type, Message State, Received Timestamp, Sent
Timestamp, Pending Timestamp, Scheduled Timestamp, Cleared Timestamp, Muted
Timestamp, Message UUID, Sent By, To Phone, Message Body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: These are the default column labels and they are configurable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Disable facility select and show loading message until data is loaded. #452&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Updated font-awesome to 3.2.1 to get extra icons&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed Help button on the spreadsheet. #455&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed spreadsheet duplicate rendering when quickly switching tabs. #362 #450&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added permissions checks to export lists functions. #456&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where facility spreadsheet update records when field value is
unchanged. #457&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where registrations was not using db-wide unique IDs. medic-sentinel#54&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed duplicate records on ID search #430&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>User Management UX refactor #385, #380, #462, #380, #379, #378, #377, #429&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug on facilities screen where delete functions would stack up and
inadvertantly delete a facility. #469&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="032">0.3.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>_March 11, 2014 _&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>fixed facilities spreadsheet bug #451 in Chrome&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>minor user interface tweaks on deletion of facilities modal&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="031">0.3.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>_March 3, 2014 _&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed a bug where the facilities spreadsheet was holding focus so sending a message doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. #440&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Bulk Messaging support, so you can send messages to multiple recipients. #333&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug to include incoming messages in messages export. #436&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where it is possible to send a message twice by double clicking the submit button&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed bug where we failed to retrieve settings on port 80 #438&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was experienced when proxying to couchdb because http proxying will
decode the URL including docid of the show parameter, so the show
returns 404. Solution is to always double URL encode if the show docid
contains special characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Confirm with user before deleting facility so they can&amp;rsquo;t be deleted by accident. #371&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added unique Patient ID validation support. #411 medic-sentinel/pull/50&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use unique(&amp;lsquo;patient_id&amp;rsquo;) in your registration validation rules to validate
new form submissions that are setting the patient ID values via forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Validation rules may consist of Pupil.js rules and custom rules. These
cannot be combined as part of the same rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not OK:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> rule: &amp;quot;regex('[0-9]{5}') &amp;amp;&amp;amp; unique('patient_id')&amp;quot;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>OK:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> rule: &amp;quot;regex('[0-9]{5}') &amp;amp;&amp;amp; max(11111)&amp;quot;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If for example you want to validate that patient_id is 5 numbers and it
is unique (or some other custom validation) you need to define two
validation configs/separate rules in your settings. Example validation
settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>[
{
property: &amp;#34;patient_id&amp;#34;,
rule: &amp;#34;regex(&amp;#39;[0-9]{5}&amp;#39;)&amp;#34;,
message: &amp;#34;Invalid: Patient ID {{patient_id}} must be 5 numbers.&amp;#34;
},
{
property: &amp;#34;patient_id&amp;#34;,
rule: &amp;#34;unique(&amp;#39;patient_id&amp;#39;)&amp;#34;,
message: &amp;#34;Invalid: Patient ID {{patient_id}} must be unique.&amp;#34;
}
]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Conditional Alerts feature. #437 medic-sentinel/issue/52&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Configure the Alerts section of the App Settings to send a message when an
incoming message meets the configured condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="030-beta39-bugfix">0.3.0-beta.39 (bugfix)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>February 25, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed textforms whitespace parser bug when using form list field types. #431&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Textforms parser wasn&amp;rsquo;t trimming space correctly on a field value, so if
you had a list defined using those values they would never get matched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Textforms was only matching numeric values of length 2 or more, so if
you submitted a one digit number you would not get a numeric match.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also if the value didn&amp;rsquo;t match numeric or a date format then the
whitespace was not being trimmed correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="030-beta38-debug">0.3.0-beta.38 (debug)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>February 13, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>added logging calls to help debug and identify whitespace parsing bug #431&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="030-beta37">0.3.0-beta.37&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>January 21, 2014&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixes to user roles (@marc)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matches Transitional V2 in
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/a/medicmobile.org/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ao9l2yegOFn7dEJRTEw1Z3RmZm0wTEo4Nk92NjVocnc">https://docs.google.com/a/medicmobile.org/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ao9l2yegOFn7dEJRTEw1Z3RmZm0wTEo4Nk92NjVocnc&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added support for Kemri Muvuku Form (KEMR)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added exclude_cols query param to csv/xml form exports. #421&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example inlude &lt;code>exclude_cols=1,5&lt;/code> in your query parameters to
remove the first and fifth column of an export.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>bugfix on export query params and UX adjustments&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Made English CSV export default. SpreadsheetML can be a little buggy
because we&amp;rsquo;re using HTML entities (not valid XML).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disabled default month value in exports screen since record count does
not reflect the export row totals displayed. It&amp;rsquo;s probably better UX to
have the user set the date knowing they are doing something than having a
default that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense with the totals on the screen and having
to guess why that is.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added timezone support to exports #394&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Render page contents first and then load the fields data since that was
holding up the page load.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indexing _id as &lt;code>uuid&lt;/code> in field index so you can search for
&lt;code>uuid:10366976d62ab9a31257b2fad16113ee&lt;/code> now and it shows up in avaialble
fields index. For some reason I think underscore prefixed fields do
show up in fields listing on Lucene for some reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed poor loading on search help #422&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>added timezone support to exports #394&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now dates in the exported spreadsheet should include your locale timezone. Controlled by the &lt;code>tz&lt;/code> query param.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added new Messages Export and removed message data from Forms Export&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New http endpoint &lt;code>/export/messages&lt;/code> to get messages export. Records are
always latest first (reverse cronological). Message export will include
all records (valid and invalid), the point of the messages export is to
give you access to all your message data, including outgoing error
messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning&lt;/strong>: the following URLs are no longer supported:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>/{form}/data_records.csv
/{form}/data_records.xml
/form_data_records.xml
/form_data_records.csv
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Use &lt;code>/export/forms/{form}&lt;/code> path instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning&lt;/strong>: Existing form data export format has changed. Included UUID of
the related record so data among the two spreadsheets (messages and form
data) can be correlated if need be. Also removed the message
data/columns from form data export. A record can be found via UUID by
using &lt;code>uuid:&amp;lt;the uuid string&amp;gt;&lt;/code> in the search box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Changed default column name of &amp;ldquo;From&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Reported From&amp;rdquo;. Note if this
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t change if you have an existing install since it is generated
based on your translation settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code> The NEW columns (added UUID column and removed message data):
Record UUID
Reported Date
Reported From
Clinic Contact Name
Clinic Name
Health Center Contact Name
Health Center Name
District Hospital Name
[columns for form fields data depending on form]
The OLD columns:
Reported Date
From
Clinic Contact Name
Clinic Name
Health Center Contact Name
Health Center Name
District Hospital Name
[columns for form fields data depending on form]
Incoming Message
Responses
Outgoing Messages
Scheduled Tasks
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h2 id="0122">0.1.22&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Major improvements in scheduled reminder support in Sentinel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for Twilio in Sentinel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minor refactor of records screen:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>added counters to show sent/scheduled messages in records rows.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>displaying scheduled tasks in records expanded view&lt;/li>
&lt;li>added RC Code column&lt;/li>
&lt;li>combined facility data into one column&lt;/li>
&lt;li>improved contact info column, made more prominent by moving clinic contact info and phone together and into second column.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed auto-reply messages from form submission that use sentinel/scheduler so only one response is sent on a new form submission.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug: Only update records of type &amp;lsquo;data_record&amp;rsquo; on records screen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preserve css (expando visibility) when row is replaced in records.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use serial_number instead of patient_id for ohw_registration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug in textforms parser where 01234 was parsed as 1234 and added test.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed unit tests for ONOT and ORPT form updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed/Added tests for ohw emergency report (OEMR) responses.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added PNC test for ohw emergency report (OEMR).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed ohw notifications transition to set correct muted value.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed OHW birth report (OBIR) logic and added tests.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0121">0.1.21&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed bug: regression from error handling refactor where assigning a record a new facility did not clear &lt;code>facility_not_found&lt;/code> errors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug: months based reporting valid value was not being passed through view.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed regression: returning &lt;code>form_invalid&lt;/code> response when &lt;code>form_invalid_custom&lt;/code> error is found.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed NYAA form custom validation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ability to do bulk deletes and facility updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where record is created as valid if callback request is not completed due to disconnection or phone running out of battery. Records are initialized as invalid.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0120">0.1.20&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>HTTP callbacks refactor, now records are created on first HTTP POST.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tests refactor, replaced some redundant/large tests with more specific ones.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Error handling refactor, now clients should not get system messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated JSON forms to include Carlos Slim test forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SMSSync 2.0 support: parsing of new timestamp format.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bundled SMSSync 2.0.1-hcb (&lt;a href="https://github.com/mandric/SMSSync/wiki/HTTP-Callbacks">http-callbacks&lt;/a>) build.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;rsquo;null&amp;rsquo; form key in filters to find records without a form definition.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Upgrade Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you upgrade the gateway without upgrading Kujua the timestamps from the messages will not get parsed. So messages will get a timestamp assigned to them by Kujua, which reflect the time the record was created in Kujua rather than the actual time the report/message was sent.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0119">0.1.19&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed wifi lock bug in SMSSync #54.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated docs with new SMSSync build instructions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed labels names and stat placement on Health Center and District reporting screens.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added help panel to spreadsheet to explain key bindings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form revisions for OHW and CDC Nepal&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0118">0.1.18&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed bug in records screen where 1 row was not getting rendered until a scroll.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refactored messaging, supporting &lt;code>messages_task&lt;/code> in json forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where non-districts showing up in districts filter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep Kujua Reporting files in-tact so it can be activated with config.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added validations, messages and ref id labels to forms on gateway testing doc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added autocomplete=off to error missing phone form in records screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added css for pointer hover to icon-exclamation-sign.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed &lt;code>use-sentinel&lt;/code> to &lt;code>use_sentinel&lt;/code> to be consistent in JSON forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added basic unstructured message support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug in records during edit row function where reported date get munged.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added spreadsheet feature so children get updated when a parent facility is changed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where using wrong label on main analytics screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Always create records, even on empty or unstructured messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SMS response messaging refactor, added response messages to gateway testing doc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed hard coded URL paths in reporting tests.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0117">0.1.17&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Renamed &lt;code>reference_field&lt;/code> property on forms to &lt;code>facility_reference&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow phone number to match on any facility type not just clinics.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0116">0.1.16&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tell user to login on 403 template.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added record detail to analytics screen expand div.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added configuration entries for reporting rates/analytics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Made labels more configurable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Kujua Sentinel support for reminders and alerts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated spreadsheet columns to use config for labels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added support for form_invalid_custom error codes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduced &lt;code>reference_field&lt;/code> on forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed kujua reporting views to better handle undefined clinic object in facility data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make it clear in HC reporting screen that contact name/phone is undefined.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use &lt;code>__dirname&lt;/code> in sentinel so it can be launched from any directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added page for reminder logs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed district filtering support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added lockRows option to spreadsheet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug in XML spreadsheet output where true boolean value shows as 0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added support in sentinel to update children when a facility is edited.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug on delete and editRow modal window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hide all nav items except docs when logged out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed console references and added JSON.stringify to logger call.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="0115">0.1.15&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Saving responses to record and displaying in records screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added timezone offset to reported date in exports and data records screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added datepicker to filter exports by date.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added support for custom form validation functions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show better error message for other codes like missing_fields&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed buttons in data records screen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Kujua Reporting package for easy switching of analytics features&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved test coverage for missing fields, cleaned/fixed up tests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed form parsing for fields defined as sub-objects and boolean parsing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added cases for sms responses when form is undefined&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display tooltip on input element focus in spreadsheet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added delete on facilities spreadsheet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make en/xls default export format&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom labels via config.js configuration doc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for records to key on any facility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nepalese responses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>VPD field updates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>added additional form definitions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="010-pre4">0.1.0-pre.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Parsing refactor to allow for better unstructured and textforms support, #106, #79&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add validation to spreadsheet with first cut of phone validation. fixes #104&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Direct support for json-form definitions #76&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added textforms support for tiny labels in form definition&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generating example messages automatically in Gateway Testing doc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed textforms parser for Couchbase on OSX #46&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using complete field keys instead of tiny labels in textforms data record creation #79&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better generic localized message handling #79&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added delete feature to spreadsheet rows #97&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated install docs to include require_valid_user steps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Various spreadsheet fixes #103, #98&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better localized string support in form definitions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Include national office data to districts on save&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="010-pre3">0.1.0-pre.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Quick Install Doc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed kujua-export to kujua-base #88&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added dropdown health centers and districts to spreadsheet #99, #66&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Various facilities spreadsheet bug fixes #92, #91, #94&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added CouchDB security steps to intall doc #88, #66&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed authorization passthrough for tasks pending #87&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Various data records screen fixes #84, #83, #56&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated gateway/SMSSync binary and added S3 link to install docs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Export branding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Started on functional tests using zombie.js and vows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added health centers and districts spreadsheet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added facilties section and spreadsheet editor #63&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assert forms that pass validation gets saved #78, #75, #46&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where form submission fails if it has extra fields #75&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed 24-hour time display bug&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added close button to login window #70&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed bug with scroll listener binding to other pages #69&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="010-pre2">0.1.0-pre.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Better textforms support including validation #46&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added optional required field to form defs, all field definitions are required by default.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close dropdown menus when clicking anywhere on the site #53&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stream export data instead of collecting it in memory #57&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added validation step to all new form submissions #73&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added records filtering by form #56&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved data records code to module #69&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="010-pre1">0.1.0-pre.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>added facility columns to export formats #54&lt;/li>
&lt;li>added fr translations for facility names. #54&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The server will not send a response unless a form is recognized.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Filtering on Districts support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Records section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed reported date on re-imports, so the dates are preserved based on sent timestamp in sms message.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added infinite scroll for viewing records on one page instead of paging.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Marking empty fields with question marks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Marking errors on records that have referral tasks with no recipient defined.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Real-time updates via changes feed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.10.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use reference to translation keys in app_settings. Issue: #3127&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add date of birth to person created by SMS. Issue: #3100&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configure the max number of SMS in multipart SMS. Issue: #3095&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Load messages script fails to use https. Issue: #3081&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot access all fields for contact in select2. Issue: #3069&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configurable contact summary cards. Issue: #3037&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display additional information in contact profile. Issue: #2914&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support additional context for hiding/showing actions. Issue: #2913&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update Tour. Issue: #2212&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Targets aren&amp;rsquo;t updated when no longer relevant. Issue: #3207&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Task issues for restricted user when a report is deleted on the server. Issue: #3189&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When navigating to the targets tab, I see a flash of the &amp;ldquo;no analytics modules configured&amp;rdquo; message. Issue: #3177&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update reports when loading the tab. Issue: #3178&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Error after submitting form. Issue: #3157&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deleted message persists until refresh. Issue: #3003&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Single delete and bulk delete does not immediately remove items from LHS in Reports tab. Issue: #3001&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tasks list says &amp;ldquo;no tasks found&amp;rdquo; before it&amp;rsquo;s loaded. Issue: #1935&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Labels not translated for generated report fields. Issue: #3154&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting 502s after submitting task; Tasks not cleared until refresh. Issue: #3111&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do not know if patient ID is valid when processing Registrations/Report Actions. Issue: #3082&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Patient contact creation should happen if a patient contact doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist. Issue: #3115&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Task schedules created using the &lt;code>reported_date&lt;/code> of a report do not show/hide at the expected time. Issue: #3097&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Patients reports accepted even if no person has the &lt;code>patient_id&lt;/code>. Issue: #3075&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Registrations that clear previous registrations also clear themselves. Issue: #3074&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure useful commands is on medic-os $PATH by default. Issue: #2750&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Family Members section header shows on person&amp;rsquo;s profile. Issue: #3108&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uncaught exception triggers 500 response for subsequent requests. Issue: #3099&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Broken links in app settings. Issue: #3088&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit function not working for reports sent by unknown number. Issue: #3087&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SMS reports do not show name in summary. Issue: #3084&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto replies and Scheduled SMS are truncated to fit in single SMS. Issue: #3083&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bubble task count not showing on browser refresh. Issue: #3028&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scheduled messages not showing accurate date. Issue: #3012&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SMS API sets messages to &lt;code>scheduled&lt;/code> on POST. Issue: #3011&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scheduled messages not being sent. Issue: #3010&lt;/li>
&lt;li>JavaRosa Parser should give a better error message when form definition on the web app is mismatched with the submitted message using medic collect. Issue: #2638&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contact &lt;code>person&lt;/code>s don&amp;rsquo;t show up in their places. Issue: #2385&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>setup_complete&lt;/code> is set too fast, so setup wizard is likely to be skipped. Issue: #2376&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submitting a family survey doesn&amp;rsquo;t clear the task. Issue: #2265&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ages of children showing up strangely. Issue: #2191&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forms and icons fail to replicate on slow connections. Issue: #2113&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Clickable portion of action is smaller than item. Issue: #3104&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Targets&amp;rdquo; tab blank for admin users. Issue: #3029&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Action button items get lost in RHS. Issue: #3005&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Action button should always be left-most button in FAB. Issue: #3004&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Up&amp;rdquo; button at bottom of place/person pages. Issue: #2894&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Status icon for &lt;code>delivered&lt;/code> is orange instead of green. Issue: #2752&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display format for phone numbers. Issue: #1930&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>medic-api migration to remove couchmark. Issue: #3068&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract XML forms into attachments. Issue: #3009&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.10.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sending a message from the Messages tab creates a message with uuid equal to database URL. Issue: #3242&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.10.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sentinel somehow infinitely loops and continually writes to its metadata file. Issue: #3275&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API crashes after &lt;code>/medic/_bulk_docs&lt;/code> gets called. Issue: #3268&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.10.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.10.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Unicode support for storing enketo xml. Issue: #3308&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support negative values in xform fields better. Issue: medic/medic-projects#1624&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trigger enketo calc updates when option names are changed. Issue: #3281&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Household button missing. Issue: #3132&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change report form language without requiring refresh. Issue: #3174&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Corrupted translation strings. Issue: #3305&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show report subject name on patient page. Issue: #3309&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translate task schedule group titles. Issue: #3283&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add additional supported moment locales. Issue: #3282&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translate contact forms. Issue: #3323&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.11.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="migration-notes">Migration notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3230">#3230&lt;/a> changes patient ID generation so it automatically increases the length as needed, up to 13 digits. If you are validating incoming patient_ids in Sentinel, be sure to remove or correct any length restrictions, e.g. &lt;code>^[0-9]{5}$&lt;/code> would become &lt;code>^[0-9]{5,13}$&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3166">#3166&lt;/a> adds a new transition that adds patient_ids to every created person: &lt;code>generate_patient_id_on_people&lt;/code>. Enable this transition if you want to send SMS about patients that may be created through the webapp.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drop id_format app setting in favour of auto-lengthening ids. Issue: #3230&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for Nepali number characters. Issue: #3192&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show XForm in User&amp;rsquo;s language. Issue: #3174&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sentinel needs to support these patient_id use cases. Issue: #3166&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable users to export, even if they do not have permission to configure. Issue: #3113&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support &lt;code>required_message&lt;/code> and &lt;code>required_message&lt;/code> translations in Enketo. Issue: #3056&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>namespace-form-fields migration causing Express toString fail. Issue: #3371&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot use Collect with username/password fields. Issue: #3118&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No permissions available for configuration on first run. Issue: #3251&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix outdated npm shrinkwrap entry for enketo-core. Issue: #3352&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set user-agent header in Medic Collect. Issue: #3334&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buttons in LHS FAB disappear. Issue: #3321&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analytics tab Hindi text is not aligning properly. Issue: #3297&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Relative times are not translated. Issue: #3282&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submitting feedback no longer works. Issue: #3273&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Full access users cannot create users, even when they have the appropriate permissions. Issue: #3262&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sending a message from the Messages tab creates a message with uuid equal to database URL. Issue: #3242&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API does not check if &lt;code>COUCH_NODE_NAME&lt;/code> is set at startup. Issue: #3226&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support Nepali calendar in outgoing SMS. Issue: #3219&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New reports for same time period do not replace previous ones. Issue: #3160&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API is picky about trailing slashes for SMS endpoint. Issue: #3152&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Couchdb&amp;rsquo;s startup.log does not include timestamps. Issue: #3131&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exporting feedback crashed api and it didn&amp;rsquo;t come back. Issue: #3107&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export server logs from webapp does not work. Issue: #3089&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Requesting audit log makes server unresponsive. Issue: #1789&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unrecognized input type found when trying to reset. Issue: #1655&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Contact profile fields collapse on mobile. Issue: #3306&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disable cancel buttons when saving. Issue: #1650&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>enketo-core package.json is included in inbox.js bundle. Issue: #3293&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use enketo xml cache for contact forms too. Issue: #3325&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.11.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Cannot report via SMS about people who are registered in the web app. Issue: #3401&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Results page CSS messed up in v2.11. Issue: #3369&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The user needs an associated contact to create a contact. Issue: #3394&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Error when adding Place with new person. Issue: #3420&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Error after canceling and re-opening any contact creation form. Issue: #3448&lt;/li>
&lt;li>namespace-form-fields migration : report bulk errors. Issue: #3371 (second part)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.11.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Slow initial replication for users with lots of docs. Issue: #3508&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.11.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.11.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The namespace-form-fields migration conflicts itself. Issue: #3534&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the create-patient-contacts migration provide a more complete list of potential patient_name locations. Issue: #3372&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.12.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add sync status indicator for offline users. Issue: #3357&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add gateway message delivery statuses. Issue: #3073&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a replication_date property to records. Issue: #2180&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change patient id generation to store the length of id it&amp;rsquo;s generating. Issues: #3505&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow form upload through Form Configuration UI. Issue: #3433&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>On small screen, cannot re-open date filter in history tab. Issue: #3467&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debug section of the About screen has some weird extra text. Issue: #3463&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Medic Gateway runs into document update conflicts while trying to upload sms status. Issue: #3443&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop &lt;code>maintain_info_doc&lt;/code> transition from writing sentinel metadata. Issue: #3424&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webapp does not supply XML forms (XForms) to Collect. Issue: #3390&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot render form in Firefox. Issue: #3354&lt;/li>
&lt;li>False positive error uploading translations. Issue: #3350&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exporting server logs fails with api 500. Issue: #3209&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AWS EC2 AMI Regression: Does not currently boot. Issue: #3173&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form exits on Refresh/Reload in Tasks tab. Issue: #3090&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Facility reference code fails to match when using integers and textforms. Issue: #1058&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bullet displayed incorrectly. Issue: #3020&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File chooser for importing translations should filter for .properties files. Issue: #3474&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show loading progress when app is starting. Issue: #3384&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.12.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Improved error messages for SMS endpoint. Issue: #3587&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow for empty SMS message Content. Issue: #3656&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement 500 item max for bulk delete. Issue: #3605&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="security">Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed kanso packages that inadvertently cached credentials. Issue: #3648&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.12.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accept patient reports for patients created in app. Issue: #3740&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop accept_patient_reports transition clearing messages for unrelated registrations. Issue: #3742&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.12.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accept messages with empty from or content. See: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-api/pull/185">https://github.com/medic/medic-api/pull/185&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.12.4 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.4/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix issue with /api/v1/records. Issue: #3770&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.12.5 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.12.5/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix bug where id generation wouldn&amp;rsquo;t automatically increase id length when it ran out of ids. Issue: #3790&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="migration-notes">Migration notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/2635">#2635&lt;/a> changes the context available to the configured contact summary script. The &lt;code>contact&lt;/code> parameter no longer has information about parents. This information is now in an array called &lt;code>lineage&lt;/code>. More information is available in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-docs/blob/master/configuration/contact-summary.md">configuration documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3546">#3546&lt;/a> changes the implementation of the &lt;code>contact_summary&lt;/code> so instead of declaring the output on the last line of the script, now you have to return the output. Usually this is as easy as adding a return on the last line, so &lt;code>output;&lt;/code> becomes &lt;code>return output;&lt;/code>. More information is available in the &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/contact-page/#contact-summary">configuration documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>multi_report_alerts transition added to sentinel. See the documentation in &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/transitions/">cht-docs&lt;/a>. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3416">#3416&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Specify which forms can be downloaded using Collect. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3607">#3607&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Validate sentinel transition configs at transition load time. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3585">#3585&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Information from the contact-summary is now available as input to forms. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3413">#3413&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow users to enter Bikram Sambat dates in Enketo forms on Android phones. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3513">#3513&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow users to enter Bikram Sambat dates in Enketo forms in the web app. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3404">#3404&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Registration of a person from a report/action form is now possible. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/2912">#2912&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Couch responds with 200 when a bad app_settings file is uploaded. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3674">#3674&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select All in bulk delete doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3646">#3646&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only serve collect-specific XML forms to collect. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3642">#3642&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exporting when filtered by report type exports more reports than are displayed in the web app. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3615">#3615&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bulk delete fails when deleting more than a few hundred records. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3605">#3605&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exporting reports filtered by place results in an empty xml. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3593">#3593&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Requesting forms should respond with 4xx on client error. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3569">#3569&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can&amp;rsquo;t view contacts for restricted user. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3517">#3517&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bad error message when associated contact is not available in the local DB. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3499">#3499&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gardener bug on startup when module_name is undefined. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3481">#3481&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reports list showing when user doesn&amp;rsquo;t have proper permission. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3452">#3452&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>select2 in a repeat group does not work as expected in an Xform. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3430">#3430&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>{{patient_name}} not found when patient was created by xform. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3419">#3419&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Search doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in Nepali or with accented characters. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3392">#3392&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove nested contacts. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/2635">#2635&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sync status cut off in mobile view. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3703">#3703&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hide Collect XForms from filter list in History tab. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3625">#3625&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Split the form configuration page into JSON and XML tabs. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3559">#3559&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wrap text in tasks list. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3525">#3525&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Task summary screen looks ugly on desktop. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3521">#3521&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Send Report dropdown menu items are misaligned. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3469">#3469&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disable tasks tour for admins. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3144">#3144&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirmation popup should not show on &amp;lsquo;Error loading form&amp;rsquo;. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3045">#3045&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;May lose data&amp;rsquo; warning displayed when form has no fields. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/1601">#1601&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Remove modules.js attachment. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3684">#3684&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use alternative pagination method for running batched migrations. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3553">#3553&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The read status of documents is now stored in a user specific database to reduce unnecessary doc updates. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/2418">#2418&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="security">Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Password validation so when creating or updating users the new passwords have to be at least 8 characters long and reasonably complex. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/1472">#1472&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t eval() user input. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3546">#3546&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set &lt;code>Secure&lt;/code> setting on AuthSession cookie for HTTPS pages. Issue: &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3182">#3182&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix bug in extract-person-contacts migration introduced in 2.13.0 &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4031">#4031&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the now invalid erlang migrations &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4033">#4033&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Force outputs to recalc on form load &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4111">#4111&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="improvements">Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bump libphonenumber to the latest&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.4 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.4/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="improvements">Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bump libphonenumber for Nepal Smart Telecom.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.5 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.5/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Update Notification transition crashes sentinel if the patient id is misconfigured. &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4121">#4121&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.6 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.6/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drastically improve performance of form loading when the patient context is used, and that context is very large (e.g. you&amp;rsquo;re including lineages). &lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4430">#4430&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.13.7 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.13.7/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Various PouchDB performance improvements were backported from 2.14. This includes increasing the PouchDB version and removing our use of pouchdb-worker.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.14.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.0/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Additional release notes are available &lt;a href="../images/2.14.0.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="migration-notes">Migration notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3449">#3449&lt;/a>: We included a feature which makes it unnecessary to use a &lt;code>repeat-relevant&lt;/code> node in Enketo forms to workaround a bug which created an empty child. This node should now be removed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3629">#3629&lt;/a>: We added more configurable text to the target widgets. Also, configuring an array of target titles is now deprecated in favor specifying a single translation key. Reconfigure your targets to specify values for &lt;code>translation_key&lt;/code>, &lt;code>subtitle_translation_key&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>percentage_count_translation_key&lt;/code> properties. &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/targets/">Full documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3818">#3818&lt;/a>: We changed the way groups of scheduled messages are silenced when using &lt;code>silence_for&lt;/code>. Previously, only the first group found to be in the silence window was silenced. Now, all groups are.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4134">#4134&lt;/a>: Review use of &lt;code>calculate=&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;&lt;/code> in all forms. If you have any XForm with with &lt;code>calculate=&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;&lt;/code> you will need to modify the corresponding XLSForm, reconvert, and upload. The changes to make are:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>From &lt;em>type&lt;/em> &lt;code>calculate&lt;/code> to &lt;code>string&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure the &lt;em>calculation&lt;/em> column is &lt;strong>empty&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have the &lt;em>appearance&lt;/em> as &lt;code>hidden&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;em>label&lt;/em> can be &lt;code>NO_LABEL&lt;/code> to avoid warnings and bloat in the form&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3096">#3096&lt;/a>: Allow users to take a photo while filling in an xform in Enketo and upload the photo with the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3459">#3459&lt;/a>: Add format-date-tr() to our custom xpath functions to support translations of days and months in xforms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3450">#3450&lt;/a>: Show the logout button in the hamburger menu for android users who have the new &lt;code>can_log_out_on_android&lt;/code> permission set.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3944">#3944&lt;/a>: Unread reports bubble not working with deleted docs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3563">#3563&lt;/a>: Sentinel scheduling EDDs on a Sunday for all ANC registrations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3821">#3821&lt;/a>: Export api doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle errors during export gracefully.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4111">#4111&lt;/a>: Enketo or-output never shows initial value.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4166">#4166&lt;/a>: People created via sentinel transitions are not replicated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4200">#4200&lt;/a>: Sentinel nulls out parent when multiple docs generated from one form submission.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4201">#4201&lt;/a>: PNC schedule is not generated when a delivery report is submitted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3945">#3945&lt;/a>: Update the icons used for contacts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3904">#3904&lt;/a>: Make &lt;code>user type&lt;/code> required in the edit user screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3758">#3758&lt;/a>: Title of form is misaligned in list of reports and reports detail pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3736">#3736&lt;/a>: Configurable profile field UI changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3735">#3735&lt;/a>: Reports content row improvements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3734">#3734&lt;/a>: Tasks content row improvements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3732">#3732&lt;/a>: Message content row improvements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3731">#3731&lt;/a>: Update content row UI for consistency &amp;amp; improved readability.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3720">#3720&lt;/a>: Improve display of icons in configurable profile cards.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3719">#3719&lt;/a>: Person &amp;amp; place profile page UI changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3704">#3704&lt;/a>: Improve password strength validation error messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3629">#3629&lt;/a>: Update target widget cards and targets page layout.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3597">#3597&lt;/a>: Update fonts to Noto.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3561">#3561&lt;/a>: Display required fields when creating a &amp;ldquo;restricted to a place&amp;rdquo; user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/2522">#2522&lt;/a>: Percentage target values are confusing.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3950">#3950&lt;/a>: Remove stats collection in API as it&amp;rsquo;s no longer used.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3913">#3913&lt;/a>: Sentinel&amp;rsquo;s fetchHydratedDoc function should use only fetch contacts that aren&amp;rsquo;t already present in the lineage list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4174">#4174&lt;/a>: Remove WebWorker for improved client database performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="security">Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3873">#3873&lt;/a>: Escape output to defend against javascript injection.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3239">#3239&lt;/a>: Accessing webapp without logging in is possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.14.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4430">#4430&lt;/a>: Drastically improve performance of form loading when the patient context is used, and that context is very large (e.g. you&amp;rsquo;re including lineages).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.14.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3099">#3099&lt;/a>: Uncaught exception triggers 500 response for subsequent requests.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.14.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.14.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4457">#4457&lt;/a>: The z-score enketo widget is not usable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4460">#4460&lt;/a>: Uncaught Exception: write after end error.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.15.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.15.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.15.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s New&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="view-clinic-places-in-places-filter">View &amp;lsquo;clinic&amp;rsquo; Places in Places Filter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You might have noticed that for SMS projects, CHW areas went missing from the places filter in the Reports tab. Good news! They are back.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we started having CHWs log into the Medic app and register families, the places filter on the reports page became crowded with thousands of families, creating a performance issue. To get around that issue, we removed &lt;code>'clinic'&lt;/code> level places from this filter drop-down so that users would only see health centers and CHW areas, no families. This meant that no one could filter by family, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a needed feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="filter-bar-place-filter-highlighted">Filter bar, place filter highlighted&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3902-1.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, as we started using version 2 with our SMS projects, we needed the ability to filter by CHW area. In those projects, CHW areas are the &lt;code>'clinic'&lt;/code> level places. In order to avoid further performance issues for projects that register families, we made this a configurable option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3902-2.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default is to show only the &lt;code>district_hospital&lt;/code> and &lt;code>health_center&lt;/code> levels in the places filter. If you only want to see those two levels, there is no need to change your config. However, if you want to see the &lt;code>clinic&lt;/code> places as well, you will need to add the following anywhere in your &lt;code>app_settings.json&lt;/code> file:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code> &amp;#34;place_hierarchy_types&amp;#34;: [&amp;#34;district_hospital&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;health_center&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;clinic&amp;#34;],
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>&lt;strong>DO NOT&lt;/strong> display &lt;code>clinic&lt;/code> places if your project is registering families as this will cause performance issues with admin or program manager (full access) users rendering the reports page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3902">#3902&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="just-in-time-messages">Just-in-Time Messages&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Just-in-time messages are available just in time for you to get those messages to that CHW who changed her phone number last week. And if she got any messages in the wrong language, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, the phone number and outgoing message language were set at the time that a schedule was created. If a CHW changed her phone number, only new registrations would go to the new phone number. Any schedules that were ongoing would still send messages to her old phone number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this new feature, any updates to phone numbers are reflected in real time for any scheduled messages that are not yet pending or sent. In addition, if there are messages in your schedule going to the nurse or a CHW supervisor and they have to change their phone number, any messages in existing schedules that are going to be sent to them in the future will go to the new numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3627-1.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After updating Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s phone number, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the following. Note that the auto-reply will have been sent to her old phone number because it was sent immediately after registration. If you look at the outgoing messages, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that all have been updated to use Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s new number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3627-2.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This improvement also affects outgoing message language. If the outgoing message language is changed, all future messages, including those in ongoing schedules, will be sent in the new language. So if a CHW registers a pregnancy and the outgoing messages are generated in English initially, if the project changes the outgoing language to Swahili, any remaining messages will be sent out in Swahili.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3627-3.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These changes will occur as soon as you reload the report(s) affected by the update. You should see the new phone number appear as the recipient of any future scheduled messages. The future scheduled messages should also be in the new language for outgoing messages, if you&amp;rsquo;ve updated that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order for this feature to work for both phone number and translation updates, you must make sure your config:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Uses only translation keys for ALL outgoing messages&lt;/strong>, including scheduled messages, auto-replies, and notifications. You must remove ALL message arrays and replace with translation keys.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Uses the correct alias for each message recipient for all scheduled messages&lt;/strong>. We are no longer recommending that you use &lt;code>reporting_unit&lt;/code> as the message recipient for message schedules. Instead, use &lt;code>clinic&lt;/code> (to send to the patient&amp;rsquo;s CHW), &lt;code>health_center&lt;/code> (to send to the nurse / primary contact of the health center), or &lt;code>district&lt;/code> (to send to the primary contact at the district level). This will help ensure that phone numbers are updated in real time. Using &lt;code>reporting_unit &lt;/code>for auto-replies and notifications is completely fine as these go out immediately after a report is received. The exception to this might be in cases where both nurses and CHWs are confirming visits and/or deliveries via SMS and you want to notify the CHW.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#improved-nurse-enabled-workflows-on-sms">More on this below&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your config will look something like this (**See the Standard &lt;code>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-projects/blob/master/standard/app_settings.json">app_settings.json&lt;/a>&lt;/code> file for a full example)&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>{
&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;ANC Reminders LMP&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;translation_key&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;schedule.anc_lmp&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;summary&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;start_from&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;lmp_date&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;messages&amp;#34;: [
{
&amp;#34;translation_key&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;messages.schedule.anc.reminder&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;group&amp;#34;: 1,
&amp;#34;offset&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;12 weeks&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;send_day&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;monday&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;send_time&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;09:00&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;recipient&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;clinic&amp;#34;
},
{
&amp;#34;translation_key&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;messages.schedule.anc.followup&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;group&amp;#34;: 1,
&amp;#34;offset&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;13 weeks&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;send_day&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;monday&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;send_time&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;10:00&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;recipient&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;clinic&amp;#34;
}, …
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3627">#3627&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="reports-tab-shows-patient-name">Reports Tab Shows Patient Name&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Have you been wondering why your CHW has been pregnant 58 times? Now you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see the patient name associated with the pregnancy from the main list of the Reports tab.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, the Reports tab displayed the name of the person who submitted a particular report. We received feedback that it was more useful to display the name of the patient, so we have updated the reports list and the report detail page to show the patient&amp;rsquo;s name at the top.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the reports list, we show the patient&amp;rsquo;s name first so that a CHW or manager can easily see which patient the report is about. Next is the type of form, which is the same as in previous versions. Below the name of the form, we have included the patient&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy so that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see at a glance which CHW area that patient belongs to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-4053-1.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you then click on a report, you get to the report detail view, which again shows the patient&amp;rsquo;s name at the top. Below is the name of the form, which is the same as in previous versions. After the form name is the patient&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy, so it&amp;rsquo;s clear which CHW area the patient belongs to. Finally, we list the person who sent the report and that person&amp;rsquo;s phone number. In this case it&amp;rsquo;s the CHW, Brandon Bone, but it could also be a nurse or another person in the health system. If the phone number does not match anyone in the Medic system, it will simply show the phone number of the person who submitted the report with no name listed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-4053-2.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4053">#4053&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="export-to-csv">Export to CSV&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Ever use our export to XML feature? Nope? We didn&amp;rsquo;t either. Now you can export to CSV for all of your data analysis needs. Get your pivot table on!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting in 2.15.0, you can now export data directly from the Medic webapp in CSV format. You can choose to export all records or you may use the filters on the reports page to export a subset of reports. Whatever is appearing when you click Export is what will download, so if some filters have been applied before clicking Export, then your CSV will only include the reports that fit your filter criteria. Every export will include all forms and all fields, so if you download more than one type of form, you may find that you have a lot of columns, but this is just to ensure that we have a column for each field in each form since forms have different field names. Only admins can export because exporting returns all reports so it&amp;rsquo;s only available to users who are allowed to access all data. \&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that after you click Export, it may take 10 seconds or so before the Export starts downloading, so be patient! [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3594">#3594&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="fine-grained-time-on-reports-list">Fine-Grained Time on Reports List&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>At 15:02 on June 6th, we made it possible for you to see the exact time your reports came in.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting in 2.15.0, reports received today show the exact time. This makes it easier to see how many reports have come in today at a glance. This way you can see if the gateway is working properly. Once you get to the next day, reports will use relative times and dates as they had prior to this change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3613.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3613">#3613&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updated-styling-for-tasks-due-today">Updated Styling for Tasks Due Today&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Now you have no excuse not to complete your tasks, especially if you hate the color blue.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made a small update to the Tasks list so that tasks due today are easier to find in the list. Starting in 2.15.0, tasks due today now have bold, blue due dates. This helps to distinguish them from tasks due in the past, which are bold and red, and tasks due in the future, which are still gray and regular weight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-4000.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4000">#4000&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updated-icon-for-chw-area">Updated Icon for CHW Area&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Wondering what that petri dish icon was for? We&amp;rsquo;re experimenting with a new icon for CHW areas.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please swap out for your projects! The new icon is available in medic-projects and we&amp;rsquo;ll be shipping it as the default icon starting in 2.16.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-chw-area-icon.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-date-filter">New Date Filter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Now you can format dates on condition cards in the way that most of the world talks about them: date then month. Up next: how to get the US on the metric system?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We added a new date filter to provide more flexibility in how dates are displayed in condition cards. Now you can display dates like birthdates or EDDs in the format shown below (DD Month). This makes the date easier to read at a glance. If you want your date to show up in this format, use the &lt;code>dayMonth&lt;/code> filter for date fields in your &lt;code>contact-summary.js&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3721.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3721">#3721&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="improved-nurse-enabled-workflows-on-sms">Improved Nurse-Enabled Workflows on SMS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Nurses are busy and can&amp;rsquo;t always sit down in front of the webapp. We&amp;rsquo;re now able to notify a CHW of when a nurse submits a patient report via SMS.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature is an enhancement for SMS workflows where nurses are confirming visits or deliveries using Textforms or Collect. We&amp;rsquo;ve made it possible for the CHW to receive an SMS notification when a nurse confirms a visit or delivery via SMS. The diagram below describes how the messages would flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3412.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To help make configuration easier, we have some new aliases available (&lt;a href="#just-in-time-messages">mentioned earlier in this doc&lt;/a>). The new aliases are &lt;code>clinic&lt;/code>, &lt;code>health_center&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>district&lt;/code> and they are calculated off of the patient. The &lt;code>clinic&lt;/code> is the CHW area, so the message goes to the CHW; &lt;code>health_center&lt;/code> is the facility level, so the message goes to the primary contact of the health facility; and &lt;code>district&lt;/code> is the district hospital level, so the message goes to the primary contact of the district hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your project has both the CHW and the nurse confirming visits, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to send only an auto-reply when the CHW reports a visit but you&amp;rsquo;ll want to send both an auto-reply and a notification when the nurse reports a visit so that the nurse knows the visit report was received and the CHW knows the patient went to the facility. You can use a &lt;code>bool_expr&lt;/code> on the CHW notification so that it only goes out when it&amp;rsquo;s a nurse sending in the visit confirmation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3412">#3412&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updated-enketo-ui">Updated Enketo UI&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>UI fairy dust alert! We made forms prettier.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting in 2.15.0, Enketo forms have a larger font for the questions, more space between questions, and larger clickable areas for radio buttons and checkboxes. On Desktop, all forms have a header that persists for all pages of the form so that the user knows which form she is filling in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3961-1.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="before">Before&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3961-2.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="after">After&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3961-3.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3961">#3961&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="allow-users-to-compare-translations-to-translation-keys">Allow Users to Compare Translations to Translation Keys&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We&amp;rsquo;re making it easier to keep track of what you&amp;rsquo;re translating so we&amp;rsquo;re all speaking the same language, even when we&amp;rsquo;re not.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2.15.0, we added an option to the left side drop-down so that you can display the translation keys. This makes it easier to know what you are translating and where it will appear in the app. It also allows PMs to more easily update translations for scheduled messages, targets, and tasks titles, among other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3022.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3022">#3022&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="death-reporting">Death Reporting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>More than a feature, we&amp;rsquo;re now supporting death reporting workflows which allow a user to report a death, another user to confirm that death, and all users to see which family members are deceased on both person and household profiles. Also includes the ever-popular &amp;ldquo;resurrection&amp;rdquo; feature which allows us to undo a death.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our app now supports an expanded workflow for death reporting. The sketch below outlines the basic death reporting workflow that can be done on SMS or in our app, or with a combination of both app and SMS. Some health systems may not require a confirmation of the death by someone other than the CHW, or the person doing the confirmations may not be a user of our tools. In that case, the workflow can be simplified to just step one, where the CHW reports the death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step one (death report) can be submitted by the CHW via SMS or the mobile app. Once the death report is submitted, the manager or nurse can get an SMS notification or a task to follow up with the community to confirm the death (until the supervisor app is built, the manager/nurse would need access to patient reports in order to get this task). The manager or nurse would then confirm the death and submit a death confirmation report. Once the death is confirmed, the person is marked as deceased in the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3956-1.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few things that can happen when someone is marked as deceased. First, the app can update a person&amp;rsquo;s profile to make it clear the person is deceased. It can also automatically update the family (or CHW area for SMS projects) profile to separate any deceased people from other people in the family or area. Finally, any deceased people will appear at the bottom of search results. &lt;strong>Tech leads&lt;/strong>: make sure you also configure all tasks so that they are cleared when a person is confirmed to be deceased. The app will add a &lt;code>date_of_death&lt;/code> field to the person&amp;rsquo;s doc once the death is confirmed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3956-2.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens if a death is confirmed but it turns out to have been done in error? We also support a workflow for undoing a death. A CHW can request a correction and if the nurse or manager agrees that a correction is needed, she can undo the death. This reverses all of the profile changes noted above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To configure a death reporting workflow, you will need:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Death report form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Death confirmation form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Request correction form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Undo death form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Task or SMS notification for nurse or manager to confirm the death&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Task or SMS notification for nurse or manager to undo the death&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New configuration for all person-level tasks so that they clear as soon as the death confirmation form is submitted if that form indicates the person is actually deceased&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable the &lt;code>death_reporting&lt;/code> Sentinel transition&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;code>death_reporting&lt;/code> property in &lt;code>app_settings&lt;/code> so that you can indicate which form should confirm deaths and which form should undo deaths&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what you would add to &lt;code>app_settings&lt;/code> to get the profile updates to work:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>&amp;#34;transitions&amp;#34;: {
&amp;#34;death_reporting&amp;#34;: true
},
&amp;#34;death_reporting&amp;#34;: {
&amp;#34;mark_deceased_forms&amp;#34;: [
&amp;#34;death_confirmation&amp;#34;
],
&amp;#34;undo_deceased_forms&amp;#34;: [
&amp;#34;undo_death&amp;#34;
]
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The Sentinel transition simply adds a date of death of the person to their profile doc. Currently, it will be the &lt;code>reported_date&lt;/code> of the death confirmation form. This is not currently customizable, but you can choose to display the date the CHW entered as the date of death on the person&amp;rsquo;s profile. We are planning to improve this in 2.16.0 by allowing you to use a &lt;code>date_of_death&lt;/code> field in your death confirmation form as the date that is transferred to the person&amp;rsquo;s doc. If you want to record dates of death for people but not have the profiles update, just use the transition and don&amp;rsquo;t add the &lt;code>death_reporting&lt;/code> property to &lt;code>app_settings&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3956">#3956&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="report-linkages">Report Linkages&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Please accept our apology&amp;hellip; We know you loved showing off your SQL skills, but we&amp;rsquo;ve made it easier to link certain forms together in PostgreSQL with the addition of a few new fields.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve added some new fields to reports to help make it easier to write queries in analytics. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to run sentinel transitions for these to work. All of these fields can be added to SMS forms and some can be added to app forms. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of what&amp;rsquo;s been added:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Any report that runs the &lt;code>registration&lt;/code> transition and invokes the &lt;code>add_patient&lt;/code> (or deprecated &lt;code>add_patient_id&lt;/code>) trigger will create a patient doc with a &lt;code>source_id&lt;/code> field referencing the report and a &lt;code>created_by&lt;/code> field referencing the ID of the contact who submitted the report.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This makes it possible to know who created each person and links the person to the form used to register them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any report that clears a schedule either via the &lt;code>accept_patient_reports&lt;/code> transition or the &lt;code>clear_schedule&lt;/code> trigger in the &lt;code>registration&lt;/code> transition will have the ID of the latest matching registration recorded in the &lt;code>registration_id&lt;/code> field.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you register a pregnancy and then submit a V form, the V form will have a &lt;code>registration_id &lt;/code>which is the ID of the most recent pregnancy registration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you submit a D form for a pregnancy that was previously registered, the D form will have a &lt;code>registration_id&lt;/code> which is the ID of the most recent pregnancy registration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This also applies to any other schedule that is generated by registering a patient (PNC, Immunizations, etc.). Any visit form will have the ID of the most recent registration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any scheduled message that is cleared before being sent will have a &lt;code>cleared_by&lt;/code> field with the report that caused the task to be cleared.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you register a pregnancy and receive the first visit reminder (Please remind Janet to go to the clinic for ANC), then submit a V form, the second reminder (Did Janet attend her visit?) would be cleared. That reminder would have a &lt;code>cleared_by&lt;/code> field which is the ID of the V form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you register a pregnancy and then send in a D form, all remaining reminders are cleared. Each of the reminders would have a &lt;code>cleared_by&lt;/code> field which is the ID of the V form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This also applied to any other scheduled messages that are cleared - we will always know which report cleared the message.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3959">#3959&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="permissions-to-showhide-call-and-message-buttons">Permissions to Show/Hide Call and Message Buttons&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Call me, maybe.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve added two new permissions to our list so that you can determine whether users should see the call and message buttons when they are viewing a person&amp;rsquo;s profile. These buttons will appear by default, but you can remove a user type&amp;rsquo;s access to them, in case you want to prevent CHWs from having the call or message options, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.15.0-3657.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/3657">#3657&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="contact-pagination-fixed-for-restricted-users">Contact Pagination Fixed for Restricted Users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Call off the search party, your missing families have been found!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You might have noticed that some contacts were not appearing on the people tab. Turns out we had a pagination bug. Sorry for those who couldn&amp;rsquo;t find their missing families! This is now fixed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4085">#4085&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.16.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.16.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.16.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s New&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="view-date-last-visited-for-places-on-the-people-tab">View date last visited for places on the people tab&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Because knowing where you&amp;rsquo;ve been helps you know where you&amp;rsquo;re going next! - Medic proverb&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to help CHWs achieve full coverage of every family or household they care for, we&amp;rsquo;ve added an optional feature to update the list of families or areas to display the date that family or area was last visited. You can use any patient- or family-level form or forms to update the date last visited. You may run into performance issues if you configure this to look at forms submitted very frequently. For example, we expect five forms submitted only once a month to work better than two forms submitted every day. Make sure you test!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4526-1.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to see the date last visited instead of the primary contact, make sure you give your CHWs (or whichever users need to see date last visited) the &lt;code>can_view_last_visited_date&lt;/code> permission. Once that permission is enabled, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to display the date the family was last visited in the list. Make sure you have this permission enabled in &lt;code>app_settings&lt;/code> to avoid overwriting the permission when you upload your config:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>{
&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;can_view_last_visited_date&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;roles&amp;#34;: [
&amp;#34;chw&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;district_admin&amp;#34;
]
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>When you first implement this, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a long list of &amp;ldquo;Last visit unknown&amp;rdquo;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to indicate which forms should be included in the calculation for the date last visited. You can use forms at the person or family level, though it is preferable to limit the number of forms included to the minimal number to avoid performance issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indicating that a form should be included in the calculation for the date last visited is as simple as adding a field called &lt;code>visited_contact_uuid&lt;/code> to your form. This should be a &lt;code>calculate&lt;/code> field that contains the family/household (&lt;code>clinic&lt;/code> level place) UUID. Make sure this is a top-level field (not in any group and will be in &lt;code>doc.fields.visited_contact_uuid&lt;/code> when you submit). To test, upload your form with this field, fill it out and submit, and your people list will update with the correct relative date. Note that you may need to refresh the people tab by either clicking refresh or navigating to another tab and then back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example XLSForm (this is a patient-level form):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4526-2.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4526">#4526&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sort-places-by-date-last-visited">Sort places by date last visited&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Puts the households who haven&amp;rsquo;t been seen in the longest time at the top, because you know how you hated it in school when the kids whose last names ended in &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; always got to be first in line?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you enable the permission to see the date last visited in the people tab list, you will notice that a new icon appears in the top bar. This icon is for sorting the list of people. The default sort is alphabetical, as you have probably noticed. The new icon allows you to sort your families or households by the date last visited. You will need to enable the permission for viewing the date last visited and configure one or more forms to be included in the calculation of the last visit date for each family (&lt;a href="#view-date-last-visited-for-places-on-the-people-tab">see previous section&lt;/a>). Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done that, the sort will just work. By default, when you sort by &amp;ldquo;date last visited,&amp;rdquo; the households you saw &lt;em>least&lt;/em> recently will be at the top, gradually increasing to those you saw most recently. Because you know, you should prioritize the households who haven&amp;rsquo;t been seen in the longest amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fun fact: We drew this feature for the first time while chatting about visit practices in a workshop with LG CHPs in Uganda. See the drawings on the lower right that shows a family list being reordered by date, with those visited least recently at the top.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4524-1.jpg" alt="Image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4524-2.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4524">#4524&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="toggle-universal-health-coverage-mode-on-and-off">Toggle Universal Health Coverage mode on and off&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We&amp;rsquo;re not trying to play bi-partisan politics, we&amp;rsquo;re just trying to test some new features.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Showing the date last visited and being able to sort contacts by the date they were last visited by a CHW are the first two features designed to achieve Universal Health Coverage (UHC). While the world is quickly catching onto the importance of this, we know that not all programs are ready to implement this approach. Feature #4525 makes it possible to turn these UHC features on or off. It&amp;rsquo;s still very early in our UHC design process so we&amp;rsquo;ll be closely monitoring these features and conduct feedback sessions, so the UHC features previously described may still undergo some iteration. Check on the status of these features before implementing them in your project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#view-date-last-visited-for-places-on-the-people-tab">As was described earlier&lt;/a>, enabling UHC mode is as simple as giving a user the permission &lt;code>can_view_last_visited_date&lt;/code>. This will give the user the last visit date in the people list and the ability to sort by the last visit date. Make sure you add the needed field to the forms you want to include as part of the last visit date calculation to avoid having a long list of &amp;ldquo;Last visit unknown&amp;rdquo;. Once CHWs start submitting these forms, the dates on the list will slowly update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4525.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4525">#4525&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="expand-use-of-the-verify-button-for-manager-review-of-chw-reports">Expand use of the verify button for manager review of CHW reports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The exciting world of data cleaning just got better.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve created a new and improved verification workflow for managers. Before, we just had two states for each report, verified and unverified. A report was verified by clicking the verify button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4529-1.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the new feature, clicking on the verify button opens a small menu with two options: Correct and Has errors. This allows a manager to review a report and mark it correct if it looks good and mark it as having errors if they need to follow up with the CHW for further verification. The status will also be synced to the CHW&amp;rsquo;s phone so they can see which reports were marked correct by their manager and which were marked as having errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#ability-to-add-more-user-roles">With our new configurable roles&lt;/a>, it is also possible for managers to have the ability to review reports while preventing CHWs from having this option, even if both are restricted/offline-first users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature was built to support the mRDT error-checking workflow for the Muso Innovation Network. Supervisors must log in to view photos of the mRDTs (&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1uXSqntenhxlGOeFtP7ScLcFmoid3kagPYn-EDoodP3s/edit#heading=h.4bwl8oo2mtpi">built in 2.14.0&lt;/a>) and check that the diagnosis reported by the CHW matches the photos. If the supervisor sees an error, they can now use this feature to mark it as such. Error rates are part of the CHW&amp;rsquo;s performance metrics so supervisors can see which CHWs are in need of additional training on implementing mRDTs. To complement this workflow, we built a widget on the CHP&amp;rsquo;s Targets page to accompany this workflow that tracks their monthly error rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4529-2.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4529">#4529&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="allow-supervisors-to-review-specific-patient-reports">Allow supervisors to review specific patient reports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We call this feature Super-Vision! Supervisors now have the magical ability to see reports about patients without being able to view the patients themselves. #superpowers-for-supervisors&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from Standard, where we have very small numbers of users, supervisors are not able to view all patient reports due to device storage limits and app performance issues. However, there may be times when there are specific reports about patients that supervisors need to see, review, or take action on. This feature is not meant to allow supervisors to view all patient reports about every patient and it does not give supervisors the ability to see patient profiles. It is meant to better support workflows like reviewing mRDT images or confirming death reports. Currently, if a supervisor wanted to review an mRDT image in a patient assessment form or get a death confirmation task, she would need to have access to the patient. With this new feature, the supervisor only needs access to the patient assessment form or the death report form in order to do the review or receive the task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below you&amp;rsquo;ll see the Reports page from the supervisor&amp;rsquo;s view. In this example, the supervisor has access to families and family reports, but does not have access to patients. Using this feature, we&amp;rsquo;ve configured it so that the supervisor &lt;strong>does&lt;/strong> have access to patient assessment forms so that they can be reviewed, even though she doesn&amp;rsquo;t have access to the patients themselves. As you can see in the screenshots below, the CHW has access to all patient- and family-level reports while the supervisor has access to all family-level reports AND the patient assessment report, but no other patient-level reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4591-1.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want a report submitted by the CHW about a patient to be viewable by the supervisor, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make sure that the supervisor has access to families (&lt;code>replication_depth&lt;/code> of 2 in most cases) but no access to patients. You will also need to add a field to the patient-level form that the supervisor needs access to. The field should be a &lt;code>hidden&lt;/code> field called &lt;code>needs_signoff&lt;/code> that must be set to true in cases where the report needs to be reviewed by a manager. For example, if you only wanted a manager to review patient assessments where an mRDT was conducted, come up with a conditional statement to set the variable to true only for assessments where the mRDT was done. This hidden field must be a top-level field (not in any group and will be in &lt;code>doc.fields.needs_signoff&lt;/code> when you submit). To test, upload your form with this field, fill it out and submit. Log in as a user who is the supervisor of the CHW who submitted the form and make sure you are able to see the form you just submitted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example XLSForm:
&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4591-2.png" alt="XLSForm">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4591">#4591&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="add-new-statuses-to-the-status-filter-on-the-reports-page">Add new statuses to the status filter on the reports page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Because even Superheros could use some help organizing their Inbox.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the &lt;a href="#expand-use-of-the-verify-button-for-manager-review-of-chw-reports">new feature that allows managers to review reports&lt;/a>, we&amp;rsquo;ve updated the status filter to help managers easily find reports they need to review or reports they marked as having errors that need follow up. With these changes, we have retained the ability to filter by valid and invalid SMS reports. Here&amp;rsquo;s what happens when you select each of these filter options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Manager review - &amp;ldquo;Not reviewed&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong> displays all valid reports (SMS and app) that have not been marked as correct or having errors by a manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Manager review - &amp;ldquo;Reviewed: errors&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong> displays all reports (app or SMS) that were marked as having errors by a manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Manager review - &amp;ldquo;Reviewed: correct&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong> displays all reports (app or SMS) that were marked as correct by a manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMS validity - &amp;ldquo;Valid SMS&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong> displays all SMS reports that were valid when received (regardless of whether they are &amp;ldquo;Not reviewed&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Reviewed: errors&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;Reviewed: correct&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMS validity - &amp;ldquo;Invalid SMS&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong> displays all SMS reports that were invalid when received and have red dots (applied automatically)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For example, if a manager wanted to review any recent patient assessments that they might have access to, she would filter by the patient assessment form type and the &amp;ldquo;Manager review - Not reviewed&amp;rdquo; status filter. This would give a list of assessment forms that have not yet been reviewed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4577-1.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="before">Before&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4577-2.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="after">After&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4577-3.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4577">#4577&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="use-family-equity-score-in-tasks-and-actions-about-family-members">Use family equity score in tasks and actions about family members&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Jokes aside, this features is an important step in being able to deliver a preferential option for the poor. Read more about this here: &lt;a href="https://www.pih.org/article/in-the-company-of-the-poor">https://www.pih.org/article/in-the-company-of-the-poor&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year, we began implementing an equity survey in Kenya that determines a household&amp;rsquo;s wealth quintile based on a number of questions about their home, possessions, and access to safe drinking water, among other things. Although the wealth quintile could be used to generate tasks for the household, we wanted to make the equity quintile useful in targeting interventions at the patient level. With this feature, we&amp;rsquo;re now able to use the equity score to generate specific tasks about patients, such as increasing the number of pregnancy follow-ups for women in poorer households. We&amp;rsquo;re also able to display specific notes or questions within forms for patients in lower wealth quintiles, such as asking additional questions about children in poorer households when they are being screened for malnutrition. This feature makes the equity score more usable in patient workflows and is the first step toward greater targeting of services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re still learning how to deliver this feature well. We&amp;rsquo;ve heard from CHWs that they resist the approach that some families in their community would be &amp;ldquo;labeled&amp;rdquo; as poor in the app, even if they acknowledge that they prioritize these families differently in their daily workflows. Though this feature allows that &amp;ldquo;labeling&amp;rdquo; to happen on the backend, it may be helpful and important for a CHW to know why a family or patient has been asked these additional questions or given more frequent home visits. The Impact and Design teams are currently getting feedback on appropriate options. Please consult your designer and share back what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking and trying so we can all learn together!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The feature works by pulling specific fields from a form filled at the family level and copying them to the profile of each family member in the household. For now, we are limited to the national quintile and the urban quintile. We don&amp;rsquo;t pull the raw scores, just the quintiles, which are easier to use in tasks and forms. To make sure your quintiles get copied, simply make sure that you have fields called &lt;code>NationalQuintile&lt;/code> and &lt;code>UrbanQuintile&lt;/code> defined as top-level fields in the form you&amp;rsquo;re using at the household level. These must end up at &lt;code>doc.fields.NationalQuintile&lt;/code> and &lt;code>doc.fields.UrbanQuintile&lt;/code> for this feature to work correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="sample-xlsform">Sample XLSForm&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4700.png" alt="XLSForm">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4600">#4600&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ability-to-add-more-user-roles">Ability to add more user roles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Because CHW Janet, CHW Supervisor Ann, and Paul the Data Guy don&amp;rsquo;t wear the same hat in real life and now they don&amp;rsquo;t have to in the app, either.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to make it possible to show the UHC mode features for some CHWs and not others, we decided to go ahead and implement configurable user roles. Up until now, we were limited to one user role for users that need offline access to their data. You have probably heard of the &amp;ldquo;restricted&amp;rdquo; user - this is the user type that allowed a CHW or manager to access data offline. However, this was limiting because every user that had offline data access had to have the same set of permissions. So, for example, a CHW and a supervisor had to have the same set of permissions, requiring both to have the permission to do something (such as delete reports) or neither would have permission to do it. This led to restrictions in what supervisors could do in order to avoid giving too many permissions to CHWs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With 2.16.0, we now have configurable roles! This means that a CHW and a supervisor can both access data offline but can have unique roles so that they can have different permissions. For example, a CHW might not be able to delete data, review reports, or bulk delete, but a supervisor could be given the ability to do one or more of these actions without affecting the permissions of the CHW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New roles can be created in the configuration pages. Instead of a permissions page, we now have a roles &amp;amp; permissions page. On this page we have a new tab for creating and managing user roles. Creating a new user role is as simple as creating a name and translation key for the user role and making sure you select the &amp;ldquo;Offline&amp;rdquo; checkbox if this user type needs access to data offline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4525-1.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The permissions page has also been updated to better accommodate a greater number of roles. We&amp;rsquo;ve changed the layout to a new format. This layout is temporary for now and we expect to improve it later in the year. You can see in this example that we now have roles for Supervisor, CHW and Online User, but you can create as many roles as you need, both for users that need access to data offline and for those accessing the app online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4525-2.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4525">#4525&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="changed-use-of-colored-dot-on-the-reports-page">Changed use of colored dot on the reports page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Seeing spots? Or do we mean dots? Either way, you&amp;rsquo;re about to see a whole lot less of them. If they don&amp;rsquo;t go away, consult a tech lead or your family eye doctor.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our use of the controversial &amp;ldquo;green dot&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;red dot&amp;rdquo; on the reports page hearkens back to the days when 100% of Medic users where using SMS. It was a quick way to see which reports were valid and which were not. Once we started having users on the mobile app, this feature became less useful because every single report was valid. This is because we have more control over how the data is entered and do not rely on the end user entering a valid Medic ID. We decided to modernize our use of red and green dots so that they make more sense across our SMS and app projects. Here&amp;rsquo;s our new approach:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ve removed the green dot completely from valid incoming reports. No dot = all good here = no attention needed. This is regardless of whether it came from the mobile app, a TextForm, or Medic Collect.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Without green dots on every report, red and green dots now have more meaning. Using our new manager review feature (#4529), a manager can now use a green dot to indicate that a form is correct, and a red dot if it contains an error.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We also know that it&amp;rsquo;s important to be able to see invalid reports coming in over SMS, either TextForms or Collect forms. For these invalid SMS reports, the red dot with an &amp;ldquo;x&amp;rdquo; is automatically applied. You can filter to see all invalid SMS reports by using the status filter dropdown. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of how the red and green dots now work:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4574-1.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at the reports list so you can see the before and after:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4574-2.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The screenshot on the left shows the current use of dots for an SMS project. On a mobile app project, there&amp;rsquo;s a green dot on every report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the screenshot on the right, we&amp;rsquo;ve removed the green dots from valid reports. The green dot can be applied when a supervisor has reviewed a report and marked it correct. The red dot for invalid SMS reports is still automatically applied. Additionally, a supervisor can review a report and apply the red dot if the report has errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The supervisor review feature is optional and should only be encouraged if it&amp;rsquo;s part of their workflow. It&amp;rsquo;s also perfectly fine for supervisors to use it selectively - to only mark reports with errors or to only review certain reports (such as mRDT, but not child assessments). The intention isn&amp;rsquo;t to give supervisors more review work but to reduce the noise on the Reports page and make the information that gets shown there more meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4574">#4574&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updated-header-for-reports">Updated header for reports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>UI fairy dust alert! We made viewing reports on mobile prettier.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve updated the header when you&amp;rsquo;re viewing reports in the Reports page. The new design works much better on smaller screens:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ve removed the detailed date&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ve moved the relative date to the left side, below the sender name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you hover over the relative date, the full date and exact time the report was received will appear. If you&amp;rsquo;re on a touchscreen, do a long tap on the relative date to see the detailed date.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If a manager has reviewed this report and marked it correct or marked it as having errors, the green or red dot would appear at the top right.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4576-1.png" alt="Comparison">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="before-1">Before&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4576-2.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="after-1">After&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4576-3.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4576">#4576&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="allow-death-confirmation-form-to-specify-the-date-of-death">Allow death confirmation form to specify the date of death&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Because the only thing worse than getting your birthday wrong is…&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2.15.0, &lt;a href="./2.15.0.md#death-reporting">we added support for death reporting workflows&lt;/a>. One glitch we realized was that the date of death was being set to the date that the death confirmation form was submitted. With 2.16.0, we&amp;rsquo;ve added an improvement to the workflow. It&amp;rsquo;s now possible to set a specific date of death in your death confirmation form. This makes the workflow more flexible by allowing a nurse to enter the confirmed date of death in the death confirmation form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to include a user-selected date of death as the official date of death listed in the Medic app, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make sure there is a field in the death confirmation form that lists the exact date of death and then indicate in your &lt;code>app_settings&lt;/code> that this field should be used for the date of death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example XLSForm with &lt;code>date_of_death&lt;/code> field:
&lt;img src="../images/2.16.0-4636.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example &lt;code>app_settings&lt;/code> configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>&amp;#34;transitions&amp;#34;: {
&amp;#34;death_reporting&amp;#34;: true
},
&amp;#34;death_reporting&amp;#34;: {
&amp;#34;mark_deceased_forms&amp;#34;: [
&amp;#34;death_confirmation&amp;#34;
],
&amp;#34;undo_deceased_forms&amp;#34;: [
&amp;#34;undo_death&amp;#34;
],
&amp;#34;date_field&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;fields.date_of_death&amp;#34;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4636">#4636&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="updated-google-libphonenumber">Updated google-libphonenumber&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Now you can change your number to avoid your ex without missing a single Medic reminder.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve updated to the latest google-libphonenumber to make sure our app will accept new phone numbers across all of the countries where we work. The current version is 3.1.8. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4665">#4665&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="fixed-a-performance-issue-with-loading-contacts">Fixed a performance issue with loading contacts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>CHWs see a lot of people every day. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of searching! We&amp;rsquo;ve improved search performance by 30% which really adds up.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Loading contacts is now done with an &lt;code>allDocs&lt;/code> request instead of using custom views. This improves performance of searching on the people tab and on the reports tab. It&amp;rsquo;s a workaround for now as we look further into the root cause of the slowness. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4666">#4666&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.16.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.16.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.16.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s New&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="show-an-icon-next-to-families-or-areas-that-are-overdue-for-a-visit">Show an icon next to families or areas that are overdue for a visit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>As the ICONic Britney Spears once sang, &amp;ldquo;Show me a siiiiiign… [visit] me, baby, one more time!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to help CHWs achieve full coverage of every family or household they care for, we added a feature &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1pPk6FAuLUPKUYnCRgruPk6Lh5IeWzu6IPD1KTFOi6YQ/edit#heading=h.1mauws8bn005">in 2.16&lt;/a> to update the list of families or areas to display the date that family or area was last visited. Now, we&amp;rsquo;ve added an icon next to families that were visited more than a month ago to help CHWs quickly spot whom they might visit. Currently, the time frame of &amp;ldquo;more than a month ago&amp;rdquo; is not configurable. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4747">#4747&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.16.1-4747.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.17.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.17.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.17.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s New&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="show-pictures-in-the-report-view-history-tab">Show pictures in the report view (History tab)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Your selfies are safe with us (and now visible in the Reports tab).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photos uploaded by CHWs are now visible in the Reports view, or History tab. This is currently being used in the mRDT workflow by supervisors to confirm that CHWs read the mRDT test results correctly. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4742">#4742&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.17.0-4742.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="improve-styling-of-mrdt-enketo-widget">Improve styling of mRDT Enketo widget&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;OK, but make it pretty.&amp;rdquo; Fine, here you go: ✨ UI fairy dust ✨&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve improved styling by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Moving the &amp;ldquo;Take Photo&amp;rdquo; button **above ** where the photo is;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adding a space between the photo and the &amp;ldquo;Take Photo&amp;rdquo; button;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.17.0-4745.png" alt="Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4745">#4745&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="include-mrdt-in-an-android-release">Include mRDT in an android release&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We made changes in the Android container to make mRDT-related features available. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4744">#4744&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="include-mrdt-in-a-webapp-release">Include mRDT in a webapp release&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We included mRDT-related features in a webapp release. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4743">#4743&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.18.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.18.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.18.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s New&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="make-people-page-default-sort-configurable-uhc-mode">Make People page default sort configurable (UHC mode)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously, the default sort for the People page list was alphabetical. We&amp;rsquo;ve now made the default sort configurable. For UHC mode, this would likely mean sorting by last visited date. In the future, it could include sorting by number of visits this month or another value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable default contact sorting to be based on last visited date, you need to configure it in app_settings. &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/">Please visit the following documentation in cht-docs to learn how&lt;/a>. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4752">#4752&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="add-display-of-visit-counts-and-conditionally-style-them-uhc-mode">Add display of visit counts and conditionally style them (UHC mode)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We added visit count numbers to the right side of each family row. The visit count will display a count of the number of times that family has been visited so far within the current month. The exact definition of the calendar month is configurable. This is because some partners may follow the Western calendar literally, while other partners have different definitions of a month (ex: Muso counts from the 26th of one month until the 25th of the next month). Whatever forms have been configured to calculate &amp;ldquo;Date last visited&amp;rdquo; will be the same forms used to calculate &amp;ldquo;Visits this month.&amp;rdquo; Please note this will be a straightforward count of forms submitted and cannot be configured to only include a max number of forms in a particular time frame, such as &amp;ldquo;per day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These visit counts are also available to be conditionally styled. If the partner has no specific goals, just like with Targets, the text is normal black. If the partner does have specific goals, we use red to indicate &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo;, yellow to indicate &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; and green to indicate &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;goal met.&amp;rdquo; It is also possible to display an icon next to the count number. This icon is only available as an option if the partner has a goal. If the partner does not have a goal, there will never be an icon. The icon is positioned to the left of the count number on the same baseline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: We removed the red warning icon by the date last visited text that we implemented in 2.16.1. The new functionality and location of the icon as described here replaces what we did in 2.16.1. It used to be tied to date last visited. It is now tied to visits this month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/2.18.0-4758.png" alt="Screenshots">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable the specific goal (which color codes the number of visits), you need to configure it in app_settings. &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/reference/app-settings/#optional-settings">Please visit the following documentation in cht-docs to learn how&lt;/a>. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4758">#4758&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improvements">Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="lhs-list-doesnt-update-out-of-page-items">LHS list doesn&amp;rsquo;t update &amp;ldquo;out of page&amp;rdquo; items&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>LiveList and Search webapp services previously did not support sorting items by fields/values that are likely to change (e.g. by last visited date). Now, when the list is multiple pages long and it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely loaded, if an existent item receives a change that would push it lower than the current number of loaded items, it will refresh and move to appropriate position in the list. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4782">#4782).&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="there-are-view-generation-errors">There are view generation errors&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4612">#4612&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.18.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.18.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.18.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s New&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="count-two-visits-on-the-same-day-as-one-visit">Count two visits on the same day as one visit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If a family is visited twice on the same day it now only counts as one visit in UHC mode. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4897">#4897&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="inputs-group-not-saved-when-its-relevance-is-set-to-false">Inputs group not saved when its relevance is set to false&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Form inputs are now always saved on the reports even when they are marked as not relevant to help with analytics and editing forms. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/medic/medic-webapp/issues/4875">#4875&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.6.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.0/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This release contains breaking changes from 0.x versions. Updating from 0.x versions may result in the application no longer operating as expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The app can now be used offline and synced back to the server later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added an android app for accessing the webapp from mobile.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tasks feature for rich event scheduling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forms can now be provided in XForm format for rich form UIs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added a configurable Target analytics module.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.6.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.1/</guid><description>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>User&amp;rsquo;s fullname is not showing up in /configuration/users. Issue: #2200&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deleted documents cause sentinel log spam. Issue: #1999&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disable nools for unrestricted users. Issue: medic-projects#149&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update libphonenumber and use strict validation. Issue: #2159 #2196&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contacts export response garbled. Issue: #2187&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.6.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.2/</guid><description>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Update PouchDB to improve replication reliability and performance. Issue: #2134 #2167&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When editing a CHP Area, previously set values for CHP, Branch, and Supervisor do not show up. Issue: #2223&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dropdowns in CHP Area create and edit forms have no blank option. Issue: #2227&lt;/li>
&lt;li>allow-new appearance in Enketo doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; option appear. Issue: #2251&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve performance of Enketo db-object-widget. Issue: #2161&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure roles are always available on user-settings. Issue: #2199&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form type filter doesn&amp;rsquo;t include all forms. Issue: #1409&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added APIs for creating Users, People, and Places. Issue: #2046&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.6.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.6.3/</guid><description>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;console not defined&amp;rdquo; error when loading page. Issue: #2277&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pouch doesn&amp;rsquo;t update seq unless something has changed. Issue: #2288&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Snackbar showing all the time. Issue: #2306&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support external_id property on user-settings docs. Issue: #2310&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.7.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bulk delete reports. Issue: #1000&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Report list item summaries aren&amp;rsquo;t translated. Issue: #2100&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix form type filter. Issue: #1409&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Replication performance. Issue: #2286&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve search performance. Issue: #2302&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t fetch form titles for each Contact report. Issue: #2300&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only fetch relevant data for the Users service. Issue: #2262&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove clinics from the Facility filter dropdown. Issue: #2218&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize admin bandwidth concerns. Issue: #2211&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We request facilities from the server over and over again. Issue: #2210&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t audit _local docs. Issue: #2366&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All requests to CouchDB time out after 10 seconds. Issue: #2325&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Long delay loading contact dropdowns. Issue: #2326&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.7.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Creating user via fails due to invalid reported_date. Issue: #2449&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>App takes minutes to load a person dropdown. Issue: #2445&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot load Configuration Users page. Issue: #2444&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.7.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Connection refused when trying to load app. Issue: #2476&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.7.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.7.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Remove maxSockets limit to allow more concurrent connections. Issue: #2492&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.8.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pass user&amp;rsquo;s info to rule to customize Tasks per user type or location. Issue: #2408&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add context to target types and goals. Issue: #2409&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update default translations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add ageInDays and ageInMonths functions to the XML forms context utilities. Issue: #2650&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Users can now only access an optionally configured number of hierarchy levels below their facility. Issue: #2648&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Android back button doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as expected. Issue: #2600&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In date filter for Reports tab, the selected dates are being offset by 1 day. Issue: #2185&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;New Contact&amp;rsquo; option does not appear without a search. Issue: #2516&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place contact should be a child of the place. Issue: #1710&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Geolocation information is not included in submitted form. Issue: #2450&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot update a contact&amp;rsquo;s phone number without an error. Issue: #2420&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.8.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If initial sync fails without syncing anything subsequent syncs get no results. Issue: #2770&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initial sync fails if server doesn&amp;rsquo;t respond within 30 seconds. Issue: #2771&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Targets tab is blank on first access. Issue: #2739&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Adding a space to a contact search term performs poorly. Issue: #2769&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local DB grows without limit. Issue: #2434&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.8.2 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ensure PouchDB doesn&amp;rsquo;t mis-label TECNO phones as devices running Safari. Issue: #2797&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.8.3 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Remove traffic statistics collection. Issue: #2886&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.8.4 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.4/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Debounce form submissions to stop duplicate submissions. Issue: #2909&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.8.5 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.8.5/</guid><description>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No changes, only a bump in version number to trigger a new release.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.9.0 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.9.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.9.0/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Redesign of People tab to introduce patient centric workflows.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create Task and Target based on reports using short &lt;code>patient_id&lt;/code> format. Issue: #2986&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Calculate Z-Score within app workflow form. Issue: #2915&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transitions do not run for XForms. Issue: #2864&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CHWs should not be able to edit their own area. Issue: #2844&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow for people-centric SMS workflows. Issue: #2700&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unique &amp;ldquo;add person&amp;rdquo; forms to a place. Issue: #2693&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Store GPS failure. Issue: #2670&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Progressive Web App. Issue: #2626&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove XML parsing and replace it with JSON views. Issue: #2432&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lowercase all user ids. Issue: #2369&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New person and new place buttons should add person/place to the part of the hierarchy in which they are clicked. Issue: #2335&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create default Edit Place forms that allow users to edit a family&amp;rsquo;s primary contact. Issue: #2333&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initial replication feedback. Issue: #2279&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make it easy to add translation keys. Issue: #1333&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="uiux-improvements">UI/UX improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show parent place after deleting a place/person. Issue: #2936&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clean up labels and translations. Issue: #2888&lt;/li>
&lt;li>First load: briefly displays &amp;ldquo;No people found&amp;rdquo; on the people and places tab even if you have contacts. Issue: #2835&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add icons to forms. Issue: #2794&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forms in Submit Report menu aren&amp;rsquo;t sorted. Issue: #2760&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reported Date is show in ms since epoch. Issue: #2699&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add basic sync status to about page. Issue: #2415&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display &amp;lsquo;your place&amp;rsquo; card upon login. Issue: #2342&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only show places you directly manage in LHS unless searching. Issue: #2339&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lock &amp;lsquo;Your Place&amp;rsquo; at top of left pane. Issue: #2337&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove all filters in Contacts. Issue: #2336&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display &amp;ldquo;disabled for admins&amp;rdquo; message in tasks and targets page. Issue: #2292&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rerun transitions on change if the previous run failed. Issue: #2978&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow replication of JSON reports. Issue: #2979&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On upgrade existing reports are not associated to person/place. Issue: #2970&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Queries from ANC Analytics do not work. Issue: #2975&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set new permissions to the application default when updating. Issue: #2951&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>db-object&lt;/code> fields show as editable when &lt;code>readonly=&amp;quot;true()&amp;quot;&lt;/code>. Issue: #2910&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Calling the &lt;code>doc_summaries_by_id&lt;/code> view results in an audit record being created. Issue: #2895&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can&amp;rsquo;t create new person as primary contact to existing place. Issue: #2884&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mute button does not work. Issue: #2878&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot fully replicate dbs behind medic-api due to badly named document. Issue: #2876&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deregister Changes callbacks. Issue: #2870&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Non admins can edit translations. Issue: #2868&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Error when completing a task. Issue: #2851&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editing a report from a person doesn&amp;rsquo;t pre-populate the person. Issue: #2845&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forms appear on the History page when they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, based on configuration. Issue: #2837&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When I click on a report from a contact profile, I see a flash of the History tab before getting to the report view. Issue: #2834&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When resources change all icons disappear. Issue: #2830&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use default revs_limit. Issue: #2787&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ContactsContent controller modifies doc on render. Issue: #2782&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alerts to &lt;code>reporting_unit&lt;/code> not working. Issue: #2779&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Correct form not displayed when going to Submit Report. Issue: #2758&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Validations and Auto-Replies not triggered for Notifications. Issue: #2755&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sending message from Reports tab doesn&amp;rsquo;t prefill the modal. Issue: #2748&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Selecting a person&amp;rsquo;s Report or Task doesn&amp;rsquo;t load the actual item. Issue: #2718&lt;/li>
&lt;li>select2 form fields are not being prepopulated. Issue: #2703&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exporting Feedback crashes API. Issue: #2692&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot associate a user with a place. Issue: #2683&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Missing patient ids and CHW names. Sentinel not fully running on Strong Minds instance. Issue: #2675&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot update a contact&amp;rsquo;s phone number without an error. Issue: #2661&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add recipients doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Issue: #2659&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sometimes changes feed is told the wrong ID for user doc. Issue: #2640&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submitting a report with an invalid ref id crashes sentinel. Issue: #2636&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Always use the same pouchdb configuration. Issue: #2625&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Branch Manager is not getting forms downloaded. Issue: #2620&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can crash API with call to /api/v1/users. Issue: #2602&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TypeError on Messages tab. Issue: #2588&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>context_by_type_freetext&lt;/code> view seems to run with no search term. Issue: #2584&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once viewing a stock report, clicking the area name makes area stats disappear. Issue: #2580&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Missing option to change time unit in reporting rate analytics. Issue: #2576&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Missing &amp;ldquo;district&amp;rdquo; selector in Reporting rates Analytics in v2.x. Issue: #2575&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rename &amp;ldquo;stock&amp;rdquo; widget to &amp;ldquo;reporting rates&amp;rdquo;. Issue: #2574&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No title shown for analytics stock table. Issue: #2573&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No loader showing when loading data on analytics stock report. Issue: #2572&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No loader shown when loading locations on Analytics Stock widget. Issue: #2566&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back button is broken on analytics stock widget. Issue: #2565&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stock widget shows time-period selector before a place has been selected. Issue: #2564&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Icons wrong on analytics stock widget. Issue: #2563&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No text labels displayed in analytics stock widget. Issue: #2562&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analytics stock widget breaks on error. Issue: #2561&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No loading animation is displayed when waiting for list of locations on analytics stock widget. Issue: #2559&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analytics page should not show menu if there is only one module. Issue: #2557&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot choose one of the analytics modules. Issue: #2556&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reporting Rates has changed name to Stock Monitoring. Issue: #2555&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analytics screen has no information on it. Issue: #2554&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By default gateway users don&amp;rsquo;t have the &lt;code>can_access_gateway_api&lt;/code> permission. Issue: #2549&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot view Targets configuration. Issue: #2548&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Send message uses a badly performing API. Issue: #2547&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Document conflict on starting sentinel. Issue: #2542&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bad error when not authed for SMS api. Issue: #2540&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editing your own user settings wipes out security settings. Issue: #2539&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot send messages to unknown numbers. Issue: #2536&lt;/li>
&lt;li>medic-api doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to correctly expose all pending messages. Issue: #2535&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Outgoing messages are not well formatted in the report view. Issue: #2532&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SMS from medic-gateway do not appear in Messages tab. Issue: #2530&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Phantom SMS message response to invalid textform message. Issue: #2525&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sentinel keeps processing the same backlog. Issue: #2521&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Errors starting sentinel with DB name other than &amp;lsquo;medic&amp;rsquo;. Issue: #2513&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You need to restart medic-api for new translations to make it through. Issue: #2511&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API connection refused. Issue: #2476&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Login page not translated. Issue: #2466&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Language dropdown is empty when adding or editing a user. Issue: #2462&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Language select modal is blank. Issue: #2459&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Broken migrations should prevent API from starting. Issue: #2456&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Geolocation information is not exposed in JSON. Issue: #2450&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Creating user fails due to invalid &lt;code>reported_date&lt;/code>. Issue: #2449&lt;/li>
&lt;li>App takes minutes to load a &lt;code>person&lt;/code> dropdown. Issue: #2445&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User can&amp;rsquo;t change their own password. Issue: #2440&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When switching between reports in History, the &amp;ldquo;No report selected&amp;rdquo; page appears momentarily. Issue: #2433&lt;/li>
&lt;li>\u0000 cannot be converted to text. Issue: #2426&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The tour keeps popping up on mobile. Issue: #2423&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In select mode, clicking on a report on the LHS to check the box also marks the report as read. Issue: #2422&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DeleteDocs modifies the given array. Issue: #2417&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DeleteDocs fails if the parent&amp;rsquo;s contact is null. Issue: #2416&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After clicking &amp;ldquo;delete&amp;rdquo; on the RHS of bulk delete, reports do not disappear from the LHS. Issue: #2414&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using &amp;ldquo;select all&amp;rdquo; when attempting to bulk delete, the number of records on the RHS doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the LHS. Issue: #2411&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Logout option no longer works on the MM Android app. Issue: #2407&lt;/li>
&lt;li>national-admins should be able to edit contacts. Issue: #2395&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initial replication gets stuck on Tecno. Issue: #2394&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot have more than one repeat group that creates people within the same form. Issue: #2393&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Targets tab doesn&amp;rsquo;t show correct progress. Issue: #2388&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contacts tab takes forever to load on mobile. Issue: #2378&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RangeError: Maximum call stack size exceeded. Issue: #2377&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t audit docs that match &lt;code>_local/*&lt;/code>. Issue: #2366&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix changes proxy to support heartbeat. Issue: #2363&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.4 analytics page crashes &lt;code>develop&lt;/code> API. Issue: #2352&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Admin can&amp;rsquo;t submit report (permissions). Issue: #2351&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DeleteDoc service breaks replication. Issue: #2331&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Phones with poor internet connections get an error page when trying to update. Issue: #2328&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigating straight to &lt;code>medic/_design/medic/_rewrite/#/configuration/user&lt;/code> breaks editing. Issue: #2294&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cannot select contact after bad search. Issue: #2252&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incoming message not attributed to contact. Issue: #2230&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form recognized, but label in list not updated. Issue: #2215&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forms not showing in filter. Issue: #2214&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Schedule not assigned to registration form. Issue: #2213&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In date filter for Reports tab, the selected dates are being offset by 1 day. Issue: #2185&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exceptions when indexing (presumably) views. Issue: #2173&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form title disappears on page reload. Issue: #2156&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User configuration UI doesn&amp;rsquo;t correctly load the attached contact / locale. Issue: #2116&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display: block in or-appearance-h2 is overriding the disabled class. Issue: #2101&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verify/Unverify button falls out of sync with left pane after being clicked. Issue: #1939&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place contact should be a child of the place. Issue: #1710&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Default &amp;ldquo;New Person&amp;rdquo; form doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow editing the parent place. Issue: #2704&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make medic-audit&amp;rsquo;s view generation 8-∞ times faster. Issue: #2879&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deregister Changes callbacks. Issue: #2870&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve free text search views. Issue: #2853&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Admin performance on lg.app has regressed. Issue: #2744&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve application performance for high-utilization CHPs. Issue: #2665&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create migration to remove obsolete ddocs. Issue: #2597&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Send message uses a badly performing API. Issue: #2547&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consider refactoring how sentinel views are compiled. Issue: #2537&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sentinel duplicate views. Issue: #2534&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove XML parsing and replace it with JSON views. Issue: #2432&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increase stability by looping over changes . Issue: #2430&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replication since gets reset when new documents added. Issue: #2404&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use db view pagination where possible. Issue: #2371&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t audit docs that match &lt;code>_local/*&lt;/code>. Issue: #2366&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a client side ddoc. Issue: #2206&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Store translations in a separate doc. Issue: #1706&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove empty parents migration scalability. Issue: #2629&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Core: 2.9.1 release notes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.9.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/core/releases/2.9.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added a migration to fix scheduled messages so they can be sent by medic-gateway. Issue: #3015&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>