<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Managing Databases on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/</link><description>Recent content in Managing Databases on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contact Muting in SQL queries</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/muting_in_dashboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/muting_in_dashboards/</guid><description>When a contact gets muted, two of many things happen:
The target contact and all of its descendants have a muted property set equal to the date they were muted an entry is added to the contact&amp;rsquo;s muting_history in sentinel&amp;rsquo;s info docs When building dashboards on Superset, Klipfolio, or other data visualization platforms, you might need to exclude these muted contacts from the visualized data. An easy way to do this is to check the contact&amp;rsquo;s muted property which when present has the date value of when the contact was muted and when absent means that the contact is not muted.</description></item><item><title>Fixing couch2pg Memory Errors</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/couch2pg-oom-errors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/couch2pg-oom-errors/</guid><description>Some times when couch2pg is replicating documents to postgres, it encounters very large info docs that are larger than the memory allocation of the document sync array and causes out-of-memory errors. To fix this, we need to delete this document so that couch2pg can proceed. Below are steps to follow to achieve this.
Reduce the size of the replicated docs to a value of say 4 in the couch2pg.conf file so that you can get within the range of the failing document.</description></item><item><title>CouchDB Authentication</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/couchdb-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/couchdb-authentication/</guid><description>To invalidate a session in couchdb, there are two options: Change the session signing certificate on the server Change the password and/or salt for the user whose session should be invalidated There are drawbacks to note with each. Option 1 will invalidate all sessions; option 2 will invalidate all sessions for that user, and also their password.
Because of the nature of couch&amp;rsquo;s session management, there is no way to see a list of active/open sessions.</description></item><item><title>Database Conflicts</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/database-conflicts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/database-conflicts/</guid><description>Conflicts are a natural and unavoidable part of working in a distributed system.
Conflicts occur when one client (eg PouchDB) attempts to replicate to another (eg CouchDB), and the document that the first has does not have the same tree of changes that the second one has.
An example To make it clear what&amp;rsquo;s happening, let&amp;rsquo;s walk through an example. If you already understand conflicts feel free to skip this section.</description></item><item><title>Querying Apdex Telemetry Data</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/querying_apdex_telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/querying_apdex_telemetry/</guid><description>Added in 4.7.0, CHT now records the Apdex (Application Performance Index) that is an open standard for measuring performance of software applications.
Since Apdex is part of the telemetry system, it is possible to view Apdex data directly from CouchDB. However, it is more useful when aggregated across many users, interactions, and/or days. With this in mind, it is typically easier to query the data using SQL from an analytics database.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to RDBMS from MacOS</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/rdbms-from-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/rdbms-from-mac/</guid><description>Follow these steps on a Mac to generate your public/private keys and access the PostgreSQL server.
Access Terminal Terminal (Terminal.app) is the terminal emulator included in the macOS operating system. You can use this application to generate your SSH key.
Open a new Finder window Navigate to the Applications folder Navigate to the Utilities folder Open the Terminal app Generate Key From Terminal, follow these instructions (see screenshot below):
Type: ssh-keygen -t rsa Hit return to use the default file / location Enter a passphrase Enter your passphrase again Type: cat ~/.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to RDBMS from Windows</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/rdbms-from-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/database/rdbms-from-windows/</guid><description>Connecting to RDBMS, the PostgreSQL server, is pretty stratightforward in nix systems. In Windows there are a couple of things you need to do to get it up and running.
SSH Key Generation and Importing Download Puttygen from here
Run Puttygen Go to Windows Start menu → All Programs → PuTTY→ PuTTYgen.
Create a new key pair for your computer.
Convert the key generated from ssh2 format to openssh. Puttygen supports this.</description></item></channel></rss>