<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHT Tasks on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/</link><description>Recent content in CHT Tasks on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/tasks-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/tasks-overview/</guid><description>Tasks help CHWs plan their day by prompting them to complete follow-up visits and other activities. The list might include upcoming scheduled ANC or Immunization visits, treatment or referral follow-ups, or other required activities such as a household survey.
Main List On the Tasks tab is a consolidated list of tasks for all people and families that the user looks after. The task definition determines how long the task will show on this list before and after it is due.</description></item><item><title>Building A Simple Task</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/simple-tasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/simple-tasks/</guid><description>Tasks prompt users to complete activities on a programmatic schedule. This guide will explain how to write a task which prompts CHW users to complete an assessment app form for new patients within 7 days of registration.
Creating a straight-forward task Running and testing that task Prerequisites Complete the App Forms Tutorial - Tasks prompt users to complete activities by opening an app form. The app forms tutorial produces an assessment app form which we will use here.</description></item><item><title>Building A Complex Task (Optional)</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/complex-tasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tasks/complex-tasks/</guid><description>Tasks prompt users to complete activities on a programmatic schedule. This tutorial will guide you through the development of an advanced task. This is an optional tutorial and is not required to get started with CHT Application development.
Create a task with a complex follow-up schedule Use a 3rd party JavaScript library luxon to make Date/Time calculations easier Pass information from the task into the action app form Custom logic for resolving a task Prerequisites Building a simple task Maternal and Newborn Health Reference App ScenarioThis scenario is loosely based on the Pregnancy Visit Task from the Maternal and Newborn Health Reference App.</description></item></channel></rss>