<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interoperability on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/</link><description>Recent content in Interoperability on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuring CHT applications for interoperability workflows</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/cht-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/cht-config/</guid><description>OverviewCHT has an interoperability tool which supports building FHIR workflows. You can see more details of the tool in the cht-interoperability repository. The following FHIR resources are supported:
Sending Patient data from the CHT to interoperating systems. Sending reports as Encounters with Observations from the CHT to interoperating systems. Sending Patient data created in interoperating systems to CHT applications. Sending health information represented as Encounters with Observations from interoperating systems to CHT applications.</description></item><item><title>OpenHIM Mediators</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/openhim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/openhim/</guid><description>OverviewThe components and reference information for interoperability used in CHT Interoperability project are:
OpenHIE defines the architecture for an interoperability layer. OpenHIM is a middleware component designed to ease interoperability between systems. HL7 FHIR is a messaging format to allow all systems to understand the format of the message. Interoperability with the CHTThe structure of documents in the CHT database reflects the configuration of the system, and therefore, does not map directly to a FHIR message format.</description></item><item><title>Loss To Follow-Up reference workflow</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/ltfu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/ltfu/</guid><description>Workflow TestingThis section outlines the steps for testing the Loss To Follow-Up (LTFU) workflow, in addition to documenting the various endpoints available on the mediator. It provides a comprehensive guide on navigating the LTFU workflow and utilizing the endpoints to facilitate the necessary actions.
EnvironmentsThe section includes placeholders for URLs. Replacing these placeholders with the appropriate endpoints for your specific environment is essential to utilize the guide correctly. Below are the endpoints provided for each available environment.</description></item><item><title>OpenMRS Interoperability</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/openmrs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/interoperability/openmrs/</guid><description>OpenMRS is an open-source electronic medical record system used in dozens of countries. Integrating CHT apps with OpenMRS can open up opportunities to improve health outcomes for patients by promoting better coordination of care. For example, referrals by CHWs in the community can be sent electronically to health facilities using OpenMRS so that nurses and clinicians can prepare for their visit and have full access to the assessment done by a CHW.</description></item></channel></rss>