<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Designing on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/</link><description>Recent content in Designing on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mapping Users on the CHT Hierarchy</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/mapping-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/mapping-hierarchy/</guid><description>This section will take you through mapping of users on CHT hierarchy, including:
defining the hierarchy (reporting structure) defining user roles mapping user personas to the CHT hierarchy Brief Overview of Key ConceptsA user persona is a generalized character that embodies a particular type of user.
User roles are the activities that the user personas are expected to carry out.
A hierarchy represents the reporting structure.
Prerequisites/Required ResourcesPersonas.
Steps1. Define the HierarchyIdentify the reporting structure of the user personas in order to have a flawless flow of data from one level to another.</description></item><item><title>Configuration Best Practices</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/best-practices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/best-practices/</guid><description>This section covers the configuration best practices of forms, tasks, targets, and contact profiles when building your own community health app.
FormsWe use forms to build the Tasks, Care Guides, and Reports that take health workers through care protocols and provide decision support for their interactions with patients.
In this context, a form is any document with questions and blank spaces or selectable options for answers. Forms can be found in many parts of your app including the Tasks, People, and Reports tabs</description></item></channel></rss>