<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Design System</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design System on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design: The Professionalized Community Health Worker (CHW), Janet</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-janet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-janet/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="chw.png" alt="CHW">&lt;/p>
&lt;br>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It took a while to be trusted. We had to prove our worth, but now we are well appreciated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="about">About&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Janet is a mother and a farmer. She takes care of her daily BRAC work after finishing her farm work. She has poor eyesight.
Janet has a feature phone. She has seen smartphones but never used one. She has no electricity at her home. She charges her phone at her friend’s house.
Janet has a trusted boda driver who she uses to help her deliver drugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Life: believes in the sanctity of life and strives to protect it by extending health care services&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Family&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Education&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Honesty&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Faith/Religion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Registering new people and families&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conducting guided health assessments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Screening for and tracking specific conditions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Providing basic medicines and health supplies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reporting danger signs &amp;amp; referring to clinics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Following up about clinic visits and care&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accurate information about the health status of her patients&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close monitoring of the pregnant women to ensure that all deliveries take place at the health facilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All children to be immunized according to the expanded immunization program&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Childrens growth to be monitored&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fast transfer of community members who need emergency health care to the health facilities- ambulance transfer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Recognition from managers, colleagues and the broader community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Financial rewards such as monthly recharges for SMS, voice calls and data, rewards based on performance metrics, reimbursements or allowances for travel costs between communities being served and facilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Opportunities for continued education, training and skill improvement via refreshers, computer education etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Career development, especially in younger cohorts: added responsibilities for high-performing CHWs such as training new CHWs or mentoring low-performing CHWs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="a-day-in-the-life">A Day in the Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Janet is a CHW who has been working for BRAC for 2 years. She lives in Bembe Central, a periurban town. She visits 10 and 15 homes daily where many of the families live in brick/clay huts reinforced with straw with no electricity, running water or internet connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Janet visits homes based off a list after she finishes her day job. There is no particular order, although she follows the register. While she may get some specific calls, most days she just visits homes and records her visits in the book. Some visits can be as quick as 2 minutes. She walks along a dirt road with her BRAC outfit making her stand out. She often calls out to her neighbors as she walks alon the road. In the rainy season — when diarrhea is often worse — these roads flood. Janet does not visit homes on these days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During her visits Janet carries her register, an education booklet, drugs and other sales material in her bag which is very heavy. She readjusts the weight of her bag several times and sometimes drops her drugs. Bodas play an important role in the health system here. Janet has a trusted body driver, whom she asks to deliver drugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On days with her Supervisor, Janet might visit 20-25 homes. The Supervisor joins her at least once a month where they also conduct “health forums” together. Supervisors conduct technical procedures,such as taking BP, marking columns in the CHWs register and later copies this into their own during refresher trainings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A normal day lasts about 2 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design: Implementing Partners</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/partners/implementers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/partners/implementers/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="characteristics-and-strengths">Characteristics and Strengths&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>May have influence and reach with the government to adopt and scale-up the new model of care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have a good understanding of the health needs of communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have an appreciation for the role of digital technology in healthcare&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have deployed, or are planning to deploy, digital health tools in the community health space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support government’s CHW networks, and may have fielded their own cadre of CHWs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are leveraging data and data science to innovate on new approaches to achieving desired health outcomes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have access to health systems data from the deployment of a new model of care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May possess existing capacity, or are looking to build, the in-house capacity to deploy and implement digital health tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have already invested significantly in proprietary locked-in software&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keen to attract funding from large funders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have a presence in multiple countries&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Equitable access to quality health care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developing national and local capacities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cost-effectiveness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Government and donor relations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Harmonization and alignment to the national health strategies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integration with national digital health platforms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Government adoption and ownership of their model of care&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Government support and buy-in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Funder backing and resources to design and deploy digital health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>HCD and data science capabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May need further understanding and expertise in working with CHT and opensource tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Designing User Interviews</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/designing-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/designing-interviews/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Understanding the people you are designing for is a paramount step in the design process, and so one way to achieve that is through conducting user interviews. This tutorial will help design thinkers to understand users’ experiences from their own point of view in terms of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Why they use products in a certain way&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How they feel about something&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How they perform various actions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="background-current-situation-problem-andor-opportunity">Background (Current Situation, Problem, and/or Opportunity)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Interviews can be a great way to empathize with your users because interviews can give you an in-depth understanding of the users’ values, perceptions, and experiences. They allow you to ask specific questions, while remaining open to exploring your participants’ points of view. They are also often combined with other user research methods, such as usability tests or surveys, so as to gain deeper insights into objective results by asking a user about them and to elicit the user’s subjective opinion on products or interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="brief-overview-of-key-concepts">Brief Overview Of Key Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the word implies, semi-structured interviews are somewhat structured in that you prepare a set of topics you would like to cover during the interview, but still open enough that you can follow leads in the conversation and change the order of topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means you have an interview guide with the questions or themes that you want to talk to the user about, but you are free to change the order of questions or to explore different topics that may arise during the interview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>User interviews can be very informative and helpful, but only if they are used correctly and for the right things. It’s important to know what you can expect to get out of interviews and what you shouldn’t expect to get out of interviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>User interviews can be conducted for the following reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Exploration-before a clear concept has been defined or before a major redesign.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In combination with user tests and formal experiments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In combination with observations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="user-interview-requirements">User Interview Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A good interview requires preparation and careful consideration on the part of the interviewer.
It’s important to be aware of how to ask questions and how to listen in order to gain valid insights into your participant’s life and experiences&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-structure-user-interviews">How to Structure User Interviews&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you conduct a user interview, it is paramount to consider the best way of ordering questions. Below are some tips on what to ask in the beginning, in the middle, and at the end of a user interview.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="beginning">Beginning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the beginning of the interview, you should ask opening questions to set people at ease and build rapport. You should not ask about sensitive topics. Instead, focus on setting the stage and bringing your interviewees on board so they’re comfortable enough to be, and remain, open with you. Your questions at this stage can include the following:
Brief participants what topics will be covered
Brief participants how their data will be used
Asking “safe” questions such as what their role is in their organization
Asking concrete questions that are easy to answer&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="middle">Middle&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the middle of the interview, you’re hitting high gear. Having established a direct channel with your interviewees (the users), you move on and ask the bulk of your questions. The predetermined order of the questions may change based on the direction the conversation is taking. Some of the tips here include:
Keep the flow of the conversation as natural as possible, but cover the topics you want to cover.
Pick up on what participants have said earlier and get full replies to questions they have only partially answered.
Steer participants back on track if they go too far off topic.
Show that you have been listening.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="end">End&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the end of the interview, you wrap up in a way that makes participants feel as though they have said what they wanted to say and that their answers are valuable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things you should do include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Asking if there is anything participants would like to add.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Telling your participants what you are going to do with their data and what the value is for them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanking them for taking the time to help with your research.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: CHW Supervisor, Ann</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-supervisor-ann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/chw-supervisor-ann/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="supervisor.png" alt="CHW Supervisor">&lt;/p>
&lt;br>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“During refresher trainings, when I go there, it takes me 3 hours because I copy from one book to another.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="about">About&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Married with two school-aged children
Has one year of training in a health-related field
Not originally from the community, but communicates effectively with the CHWs
Salaried MOH employee
Has a personal mobile phone that ranges from a feature phone to a smart phone, used for communication
Has an email account primarily accessed via mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Overall responsible of the health of the community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Manages a group or groups of CHWs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communicates frequently with CHWs and other supervisors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Liaises with the facility-based health workers especially the nurses and clinical doctors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobilizes &amp;amp; leads CHWs to educate community on health promotion &amp;amp; disease prevention&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensures that the CHWs send in data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aggregates data from CHWs and sends to the data records person&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attends meetings with MOH officials at the district health center&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sits on the community development committee with chiefs and government officers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Training CHWs and reinforcing health knowledge and protocols&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Following up with CHWs on high-priority cases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Liaising with the facility-based staff on the needs at the community level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobilizing CHWs to educate community on health promotion campaigns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tracking progress towards key impact metrics and helping CHWs reach their targets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aggregating CHW data and reporting on activities to health system officials&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accurate data from the CHWs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to send reports to supervisors promptly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobilize and lead CHWs on community events for health promotion &amp;amp; disease prevention&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Closely monitor the progress of each individual CHWs and provide supportive supervision&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Motivate CHWs consistently so that they continue doing their volunteer community service&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Healthy community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increased utilization of available health services provided at the health center&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Recognition from supervisor for sending timely and accurate data&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="strengths-and-assets">Strengths and Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Literate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Background training in healthcare&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salaried (consistent source of income)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Familiar with socio-cultural norms of the community &amp;amp; committed to community’s health&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile phone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Earned community respect&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="a-day-in-the-life">A Day in the Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ann wakes up early in the morning to prepare her son for school and husband for work. She takes her son to school which is on her way to health center where she is based.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She needs to be at the health center by 9 am so she takes a bus for part of the journey and a motorbike for the rest of the journey. The health center is located about 10 km from her home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She attends to her public health officer’s duties based at the health center. She is primarily in charge of the community and market sanitation, so she facilitates the small scale traders who run business at the nearby market to get health check-ups that are mandatory before she issues them a certified health certificate that allows them to run food related businesses in the market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the course of her day, she collaborates with a wide range of stakeholders in order to perform her chores. She liaises with the clinicians and nurses to identify defaulters of care in order to organize for the follows up through the community health workers. The nurse would give her a list of children who have missed their vaccine appointments, the pregnant women who have missed their antenatal care clinics, the Tuberculosis and HIV/AIDs clinicians also have a list of defaulters of care that should be followed to ensure prompt care. She must liaises with the CHWs to be trace these patients and reintroduce them to care. This is one of her greatest challenge as it is hard to trace the children in the wide facility catchment area. You know it is her responsibility to ensure that the community health workers are creating demand for the health services at the community level and ensuring that the community members access the quality care at the health facilities. She assesses the performance of her CHWs by looking at how many community members they refer to the health facilities for care, and the adherence to care of the patients referred by each CHW. This is no mean easy task as CHWs are not paid and the villages they cover are wide and a very hilly terrain which becomes impossible during the rainy weather. Over half of the CHWs that she trained during the initiation of the CHW program in her area three years have dropped, and the new ones she has replaced need to be trained on the whole package of their role. She would gladly do this but “Oh, when will an non governmental organization come by to support us in this capacity building activity?” She exclaims. Meanwhile she must support the new CHWs by accompanying them at least once a month when they are doing their household visits in the villages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since there is an upcoming community based polio and tetanus campaign targeted for under-fives and women of reproductive health, she must select and contact several CHWs from each village that will help them administer these vaccines in their villages and therefore reach the most possible target population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She must also liaise with the area administrative chief who provide the go ahead of the community based activities to mobilize the community for health education and dialogue days and community health related activities. She and her CHWs lead the community to discuss on various disease preventive and health promotive activities that are tailored to meet health needs/gaps they have observed within the community. They use these regular forums to reinforce important health messages like the importance pregnant women going for ANC and children for immunization. She leads the community health workers and community members during community action days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She also works hand in hand with the schools heads for deworming and Vitamin A campaign targeted at children, a regular activity which she carries out with the CHWs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann’s 80% of her time is spent interacting with the community and the community health workers. This month’s monthly meeting with the CHWs is early next week. She must make some time to prepare some notes on how to make drinking water safe for use in the community, during a visit in the community, she observed that the community was using unsafe water for drinking and the CHW did not know what to advise her households to make the water safe. The CHEW continues to offer need based training to the CHWs depending on assessment of the knowledge deficits of the CHWs after the initial training. He guides the CHWs, on how to effectively communicate well with the community. She intents to guide the CHWs on the data items to collect as most of them have not been sending all the reports as required. If transport within the community was cheap or easier she would visit the CHWs who did not send reports and or those who send inaccurate data or incomplete reports and walk with them as they collect the data.. As a CHEW, she is charged by the MOH to aggregate data about the community’s state of health that is received from the CHWs on a monthly basis. The primary data items for her reflect the utilization of health services by the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann has a regular end of month meeting with her community health supervisor who is based in the Sub district hospital that is 150km away from her station early in the morning on Wednesday. She must prepare and present her monthly written reports and give a verbal report of the state of the community and performance of the CHWs under her supervision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann gets back to her home at 6 pm, she picks her son from school where he had been playing since 4pm when the other pupils leave school for home. She prepares supper for her family, and carries out the other family chores. She retires to bed at about 10pm tired but happy to have accomplished her day’s duties.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design: Local and Sub-National Governments</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/partners/local-governments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/partners/local-governments/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="characteristics-and-strengths">Characteristics and Strengths&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>They are often led by locally elected political leaders and are motivated to demonstrate health impacts for continued political support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tend to be more accountable to local communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have a thorough understanding of the local context and health needs of local communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They often have the legal and administrative mandate to set local health priorities, plan, allocate and mobilize resources, and deliver primary health care to their respective communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They are guided by national health strategy and community health strategy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They are responsible for managing CHWs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They are often motivated to adopt digital health technologies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have deployed, or are planning to deploy, digital health tools in the community health space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Comparatively, they have less cumbersome bureaucratic processes and red-tape in building partnerships&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Health and well-being of their citizens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Equitable access to quality health care services&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social health protection of their constituencies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local leadership and decentralization in health&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Innovation and digital technologies in community health space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>High impact door-step health care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community participation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partnerships with non-state actors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cost-effectiveness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sustainability&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Health systems strengthening support to keep up with growing population needs and tackle emerging public health challenges, e.g. NCDs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better institutional capacities to manage community health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regular guidance, coordination and support from the state/provincial and national governments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better data systems for evidence-based planning and monitoring&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technical partnership and support to manage digital health technologies&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Creating an Empathy Map</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/empathy-map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/empathy-map/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-tutorial">Purpose Of the Tutorial&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The tutorial will take you through the process of creating an empathy map as a way to synthesize the insights gathered during the discovery phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An empathy map is a visualization tool which helps you sum up what you learned from design research to help you better understand your users and articulate what you know to colleagues and stakeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map provides four major areas in which to focus our attention on, thus providing an overview of a person’s experience. Empathy maps are also great as a background for the construction of the personas that you would often want to create later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map consists of four quadrants. The four quadrants reflect four key traits, which the user demonstrated/possessed during the discovery stage. The four quadrants refer to what the user: Said, Did, Thought, and Felt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s fairly easy to determine what the user said and did. However, determining what they thought and felt should be based on careful observations and analysis as to how they behaved and responded to certain activities, suggestions, conversations, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="brief-overview-of-key-concepts">Brief Overview Of Key Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Insight refers to a remarkable realization that can help you to solve the current design challenge you are facing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-fill-out-the-empathy-map">1. Fill Out the Empathy Map&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="empathy-map.png">
&lt;img src="empathy-map.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Lay the four quadrants out on a table, draw them on paper or on a whiteboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Review your notes, pictures, audio, and video from your research/fieldwork and fill out each of the four quadrants while defining and synthesising:&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What did the user SAY? Write down significant quotes and keywords that the user said.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What did the user DO? Describe which actions and behaviours you noticed or insert pictures or drawing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What did the user THINK? Dig deeper. What do you think that your user might be thinking? What are their motivations, their goals, their needs, their desires? What does this tell you about his or her beliefs?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How did the user FEEL? What emotions might your user be feeling? Take subtle cues like body language and their choice of words and tone of voice into account.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="2-synthesise-needs">2. Synthesise Needs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You should look for the following within your data to identify your users’ needs:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Verbs—i.e., activities and desires. Mark and analyze any pieces of data that start with a verb as these are likely to contain or point towards a user need.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The user traits you noted. Again, mark specific user traits as these will lead towards the true needs of your users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contradictions and inconsistencies. Once you’ve picked out the users’ traits, you should look for contradictions and inconsistencies between them. For example, there may be a disconnection between what a user says and does, or they might show a positive action but portray a negative emotion through a quote.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Write down user’s needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="3-synthesise-insights">3. Synthesise Insights&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Look to synthesise major insights, especially from contradictions between two user attributes. It can be found within one quadrant or in two different quadrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also synthesise insights by asking yourself: “Why?” when you notice strange, tense, or surprising behaviour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Write down your insights.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design: Ministry of Health and National Governments</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/partners/national-governments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/partners/national-governments/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="characteristics-and-strengths">Characteristics and Strengths&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set national health priorities and design large-scale national public health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lead health sector reform agenda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guide the production, recruitment, and deployment of human resource for health, including community health workforce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regulate both public and private health service providers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set development cooperation policies and priorities in the health sector&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide financial resources to sub-national governments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Work closely with other ministries and sub-national governments to execute national health policies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compete with other ministries and government line agencies for resources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have access to large-scale funding from multilateral and bilateral international agencies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have an appreciation for the role of digital technology in healthcare&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have developed and rolled-out national digital health strategy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Responsible for setting digital technology and data standards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Often have an institutional home to anchor national digital health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have some in-house capacity to deploy and implement digital health tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are often looking to establish partnerships for leveraging digital health technologies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are leveraging data and data science to innovate on new approaches to achieving desired health outcomes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have access to health systems data from the deployment of a new model of care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>May have already invested significantly in proprietary locked-in software&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Safeguarding the health rights of the citizens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>International commitments in health, e.g. UHC, SDG, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>National ownership of public health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>National capacities to govern and manage community health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cost-effectiveness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Government adoption and sustainability&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Health systems strengthening support to keep up with growing population needs and tackle emerging public health challenges, e.g. NCDs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regular political commitments for increased spending in public health&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integration and interoperability of digital health technologies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better data systems for evidence-based planning and monitoring&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacity and resources to govern and manage digital health programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>HCD and data science capabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Regional Manager, Christina</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/regional-manager-christina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/regional-manager-christina/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="regional-manager.png" alt="Regional Manager">&lt;/p>
&lt;br>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I heard that some branches have already had challenges with mobile phones.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="about">About&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Christina been working at BRAC for six years. She manages four branches and works closely with the CHW Managers there. She makes sure CHW Managers are monitoring CHWs. She occasionally does random checks, driving out to villages and observing Managers with CHWs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Visionary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Good communication&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Respect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Responsibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wisdom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Empathy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Overall responsibility of the Region’s activities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oversees implementation of organisational goals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communicates organisational goals and strategies to CHW managers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Liaise and ensure compliance with Ministries, NGO boards and regulatory bodies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Promote advocacy efforts of the program&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supervises and supports staff to attain their career goals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approval of quarterly logistic plans for CHW managers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reviews and approves CHW’s continuous education programs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evaluates programs impact and advises on key priority areas of focus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Realignment of programs to changing ecosystem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Budgetary planning for region’s activities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tracking branches’ and CHW manager’s performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Monthly indicators tracking to ensure realization of organisational goals&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Real time access of data on supervision activities ongoing in their region&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Access to summary statistics on project indicators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Timely submission of monthly reports on retention and turnover rates for CHWs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Escalation of CHW retraining needs, challenges and proposed solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Opportunities to conduct random checks to assess the CHWs perceptions of their managers support&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Desire to improve lives of communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Desire to practice community health strategies learnt at school&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organisational goals align well with personal goals&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="strengths-and-assets">Strengths and Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Provided with a company car and computer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Has a welcoming heart and accessible to employees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team player&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Nurse, Mary</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/nurse-mary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/nurse-mary/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="nurse.png" alt="Nurse">&lt;/p>
&lt;br>
&lt;h2 id="about">About&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mary has formal clinical training but a limited ability to conduct complex surgical procedures. She sees +/- 50 patients a day, sometimes in their homes. She is literate in English and understands local dialects. She is sometimes stationed far from her rural town/family in spurts and makes regular trips to districts to hand-deliver reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary lives on $5/day and depends mostly on solar power at the clinic as she may not have electricity at home. She is enthusiastic about technology but has had little exposure. She has an email address that she does not check regularly and has a basic understanding of Windows OS. She uses Facebook and M-PESA on a low-end phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Good health. Anyone is only able to work and therefore take care of ones and other people’s needs if and when in really good health&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Family is the essence of one’s existence and that each child is entitled to love that can be best provided and experienced in the family setting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Education is the ticket for better, healthier and happier life for everyone&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Assessing patients and providing primary care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reporting service delivery statistics to health system officials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coordinating care for high-priority patients through CHWs and supervisors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initiating events to promote healthy practices in the community&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nurse Mary wants nil (zero) maternal and child mortalities in the community served by the health facility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nurse Mary needs all the community to be aware of the health care services that they can access at the health facility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nurse Mary needs everyone in the community to have access and adhere to continuous quality care provided at the health facility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nurse Mary needs all defaulters to health care available at the health facility that are in the community to be traced and re-introduced to care&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nurse Mary needs to keep and get accurate data of the target population that she provides health care for&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nurse Mary needs to keep abreast with new editions of nursing procedures through regular trainings/seminars&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Community enjoying services of skilled health professionals for deliveries which translates to no or very few maternal and child mortalities. More money for her to run the facility as finances for performance is a policy that is in use now in Kenya.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Healthier children, with fewer neonatal, infant or child mortalities, and 100% full immunization of all under-fives.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Progress within the nursing profession with continues and recognized certifications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Model health facility where other health facilities are encouraged to emulate and adopt those standards.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prompt report submissions to supervisors and the recognition by the supervisors for that.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="strengths-and-assets">Strengths and Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Literate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strong clinical knowledge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organizational skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Constant source of income-employment by the government&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile phones: smart phones, facebook, Whatsapp and access to email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Computer literacy: access email, basic understanding of the windows OS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Access to either solar or electricity power at the health center&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="a-day-in-the-life">A Day in the Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Her day at work starts early as she must be on duty at 7 am, to relieve the nurse who has been on cover of the health facility at night if she is in a health facility that as at least 2 of them. In the health facility, where she is the only nurse she comes to pick up from where she left last evening, if she was “lucky” not to be woken up to attend to a patient at night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She gets a report from the “night nurse” of all the in-patients-mainly women in labor, newborns born at night, children less than 5 years brought in at night for care and injuries resulting from accidents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>8am going to 9am, the outpatient is swollen with patients: mothers with under five children bringing them to the child welfare clinic, pregnant women some with under five children coming also for antenatal care, and elderly women and men, all weak, sick looking and would pass for nutritional support-if only there were supplements for the elderly. The ones in store are for the under 5 malnourished and pregnant women.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, she notes the need to do a health education session on how to eat a well-nourished meal using the locally available food stuffs, but now, she must do one on how to prevent contracting cholera as cholera as for the last 2 months being reported in many parts of the country. It is a regular practice to carry out health education sessions to the out patients. She will also talk to the CHEW today for a health education session with the CHWs during their monthly meeting on cholera prevention that the CHWs must disseminate to the community. She and the field CHEW must liaise consistently as they work together with the CHWs to promote the health of the community. Her role is to oversee the field CHEW and to help her meet the knowledge gap of the CHWs by consistently teaching CHWs on common local diseases and how to prevent them, identifying them, giving first aid and referring patients for specialized health care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CHWs are critical to her as they are the link between the community and the health facility that is very important. The CHWs help her trace the children under five lost to follow up, malnourished children in the community who need follow up, chronically ill patients in the community that need home based care and refer and support orphans and vulnerable children in the community. The field CHEW co-ordinates this activity, after giving her the list of the patients to be followed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her next in line activity is to see the ANC mothers, she co-ordinates their care, sends them for laboratory work, prescribe treatments and supplements based to the general health assessments of the woman and the lab results. She records care given in the maternal child booklet, and advises her on when to come for her next follow up. She briefly counsels on how to take care of herself during pregnancy, feed well and the exercises to take, maintain good hygiene and to plan to deliver her baby in the health facility: the individual birth plan, must be reinforced by the CHWs who can afford some more time for a one to one talk with the woman. She keeps a record of all the pregnant women she sees, both the new and those that come for subsequent visit. She will write a report based on this at the end of the month showing the new pregnancies, those that have it 4+ANC visits, new PMTC cases among other details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She will also attend to the under-fives, both those that have come for the routine immunization and growth monitoring and the sick ones who were brought for treatment. She will record all the care given in the mother child booklet and give brief advice on nutrition of the child while charting the weight on the growth monitoring chart. She will attend to the other sickly patients as well, give family planning counseling and services, and monitor the mothers in labor in the ward. Among other duties that she must attend to are emergency cases referred from the community, accompanying complicated cases to the higher level hospital for more specialized care, and assisting the doctors and clinicians in handling special cases when in facility like a hospital where these services are offered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The day has not started or ended if she has not read the temperature of the thermometers of the vaccine boxes to ensure that it is in the required temperature ranges and therefore the boxes are in good order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her monthly reports range from daily vaccine monitoring chart, to the ANC, immunization related records to the vaccine usage rates for the month. She places monthly based order for vaccine supplies based on the month’s usage, and must collect the vaccines from the sub-county headquarters before the end of the first week of the month. She attends a monthly visit organized by her supervisors at the sub-county district, at least monthly and frequently meets her colleagues during the irregular continuous education seminars organized by their supervisors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nurse Mary faces a lot of challenges, but the most pressing is the workload coupled with the intensity of the nature of the work that she faces day in, day out. She is entitled to work a maximum of 45 hours a week, but is that really what happens?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design: Creating an Actionable Problem Statement</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/problem-statement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/problem-statement/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The guide will take you through creation of an actionable problem statement in order to generate a greater quantity and higher quality solutions when you start generating ideas during ideation sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Defining your design challenge is probably one of the most important steps in the design thinking process, as it sets the tone and guides all of the activities that follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the define stage, you should end up creating an actionable problem statement which is commonly known as the point of view (POV) in design thinking. You should always base your point Of view on a deeper understanding of your specific users, their needs and your most essential insights about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your POV should never contain any specific solution, nor should it contain any indication as to how to fulfill your users’ needs in the service, experience, or product you’re designing. Instead, your POV should provide a wide enough scope for you and your team to start thinking about solutions which go beyond status quo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, you’ll also learn to frame and open up your Point Of View, which is the axis that Design Thinking revolves around – a challenge well-framed is half solved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-define-the-type-of-person-you-are-designing-for--your-user">1. Define the Type Of Person You Are Designing For – Your User&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Select the most essential needs, which are the most important to fulfill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work to express the insights developed through the synthesis of your gathered information.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="2-write-your-definitions-into-a-point-of-view-template">2. Write Your Definitions Into a Point of View Template&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="pov-statement.png">
&lt;img src="pov-statement.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Example&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>User&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Needs&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Insights&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>An adult person who lives in a city&lt;/td>
&lt;td>To use a car for 10-60 minutes 1-4 trips per week&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The user would not want to own his own car as it would be too expensive compared to his needs. He would like to share a car with others who have similar needs, however, there are no easy and affordable solutions for him. It is important for the user to think and live green and to not own more than he truly needs.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="3-create-a-point-of-view-mad-lib">3. Create a Point Of View Mad Lib&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can articulate a POV by combining these three elements – user, need, and insight – as an actionable problem statement that will drive the rest of your design work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s surprisingly easy when you insert your findings in the POV Madlib below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can articulate your POV by inserting your information about your user, the needs and your insights in the following sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[User . . . (descriptive)] needs [Need . . . (verb)] because [Insight . . . (compelling)]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example: An adult person who lives in the city… needs access to a shared car 1-4 times for 10-60 minutes per week … because he would rather share a car with more people as this is cheaper, more environmentally friendly, however it should still be easy for more people to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="4-make-sure-that-your-point-of-view-meets-the-requirements">4. Make Sure That Your Point of View Meets the Requirements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Provides a narrow focus.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Frames the problem as a problem statement.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspires your team.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guides your innovation efforts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Informs criteria for evaluating competing ideas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Captures people’s attention.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Is valid, insightful, actionable, unique, narrow, meaningful, and exciting.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Data Manager, Paul</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/data-manager-paul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/data-manager-paul/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="hrio.png" alt="HRIO">&lt;/p>
&lt;br>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It’s all about training them. The Community Health Workers are just villagers and farmers, so it’s training and more training.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="about">About&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Paul has worked at BRAC for two years. He’s very focused on his career and has lots of IT projects running. He is responsible for training the branches on how to use the mobile phones. Right now Paul is looking for the right quality of phones. He also wants to understand how the database will ensure reliable syncing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Critical thinker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strong communication skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Creativity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accuracy and attention to detail&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Problem solving skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team player&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Collating health system data from the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verifying data for accuracy and completeness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aggregating data and providing reports to nurses, supervisors, and health system officials with raw numbers and trends on key metrics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designing and maintaining data systems and databases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using statistical tools to interpret data sets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preparing reports that effectively communicate trends, patterns and interesting observations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accurate data reported by CHWs and verified by CHW Supervisors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Systems that check the completeness of data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Access to statistical tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Robust systems that can handle large data sets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Helping the organisation to make data driven decisions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Employing new skills learnt from colleagues&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="strengths-and-assets">Strengths and Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Statistical expertise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Presentation skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data visualization techniques&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Methodological&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Mapping User on the CHT Hierarchy</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/mapping-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/mapping-hierarchy/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The tutorial will take you through mapping of users on CHT hierarchy, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Defining the hierarchy (reporting structure)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Defining user roles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mapping user personas to the CHT hierarchy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="brief-overview-of-key-concepts">Brief Overview of Key Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/">user persona&lt;/a>&lt;/em> is a generalized character that embodies a particular type of user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>User roles are the activities that the user personas are expected to carry out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A hierarchy represents the reporting structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisitesrequired-resources">Prerequisites/Required Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/">Personas.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this section, you will define a hierarchy, define user persona roles and map user personas to the hierarchy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-define-the-hierarchy">1. Define the Hierarchy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Identify reporting structure of the user personas in order to have a flawless flow of data from one level to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="app-hierarchy.jpg">
&lt;img src="app-hierarchy.jpg"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For instance, a family member is part of a household. A household and CHWs are part of a CHW area. A CHW area and nurses are part of a health facility. Additional levels may be added as needed. The admin level operates outside of the hierarchy and gives access to all levels and people.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="user-hierarchy.png">
&lt;img src="user-hierarchy.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The app hierarchy is often modeled after the health system, health program or community structure. All people who are registered in the app must be associated with a place. These places are located in a hierarchy to other places.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="2-define-the-user-roles">2. Define the User Roles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Determine all the actors within the system in terms of who will be doing what.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="user-roles.png">
&lt;img src="user-roles.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="3-map-user-personas-to-the-hierarchy">3. Map User Personas to the Hierarchy&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="mapped-personas.png">
&lt;img src="mapped-personas.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Design: App Builders</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/app-builder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/app-builder/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="about">About&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>App builders and technical organizations have in-house or contracted software developers. They deploy health technology solutions for implementing partners such an iNGOs, Governments, UN agencies etc in the community health space. They have limited familiarity with end-users such as CHWs and HCD.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="values">Values&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Aligned with CHT principles and willing to contribute back to the CHT in the future&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Believe in building open-source technologies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Likeable personality&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open-mindedness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strong work ethic&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Build and deliver user experiences centered on the CHT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Steward the CHT app developer’s experience&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CHT Capacity Builders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technical support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak the language of the business&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="needs">Needs&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Capacity and expertise with the CHT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flexible technology (and tooling) to help build holistic digital health interventions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Build awesome and bug-free user experiences using the CHT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adoption of the CHT as the technology of choice for building community health apps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delivering effective interventions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Novel projects or interventions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developing skills&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="strengths-and-assets">Strengths and Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Diversity in skills sets: HCD, software development, database management, dashboard development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resourcefulness: bend the CHT&amp;rsquo;s capabilities to meet a given need&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Passion for problem solving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An inquisitive mind&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>