<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Onboarding on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/</link><description>Recent content in Onboarding on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Product Team</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/product-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/product-team/</guid><description>The goal of this page is to convey a general “lay of the land” so someone starting can see a lot of what’s out there related to Product Team without having to be surprised each day as new things pop up.
About Product TeamThe Product Team manages the entire software development life-cycle to understand problems, capture requirements, design and build modular software systems, and document everything along the way. We achieve this by working with CHT partners and health workers to design, build, and maintain the Community Health Toolkit and its open source tools.</description></item><item><title>All The Things</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/all-the-things/</guid><description>This page is meant to serve as a point of conversation, with a wide range of topics to be discussed when joining Medic or starting as a contributor. Many things are not in any particular order. The goal is to convey a general “lay of the land” so someone starting can see a lot of what’s out there without having to be surprised each day as new things pop up.</description></item><item><title>Technical Resources</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/technical-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/technical-resources/</guid><description>Note This page also contains Medic internal documentation links that are only accessible to Medic team members. This page contains materials that will help a CHT Contributor to master all the technical details they need to be successful when building tools related to the CHT. For Medic team members, this content is complimentary on a technical level to the Onboarding documents shared by the Internal Operations team. Keep in mind that this is a living document, and every contributor is encouraged to add to it when identifying learning opportunities that can set them up for success with the CHT.</description></item><item><title>Team Meetings</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/team-meetings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/team-meetings/</guid><description>Product Team Monthly CallWhyGetting to see each other all in one place at the same time, even if only online, lets people get to be around each other, learn from each other, and hear other perspectives. We&amp;rsquo;re real people! &amp;hellip;terrific people too. This is a small space to spend some time around each other as a group. We&amp;rsquo;re mostly trying to learn more about each other, celebrate recent successes, and cover the occasional big news or team-wide changes.</description></item><item><title>Daily Updates</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/daily-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/onboarding/daily-updates/</guid><description>WhatIn our fully remote environment, staying connected and informed is crucial. One of the ways we can ensure transparency, and collaboration, and keep everyone in the loop is by utilizing the #product-dailies channel in Slack for sharing daily updates.
WhoAll the Product Team members are expected to share daily updates in Slack (#product-dailies channel). Due to the nature of their work, Leadership Product colleagues might share less regular, but more consolidated updates.</description></item></channel></rss>