<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3.x on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/</link><description>Recent content in 3.x on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS Hosting in CHT 3.x</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/ec2-setup-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/ec2-setup-guide/</guid><description>Most production CHT instances are deployed on AWS EC2. Leveraging Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) and Elastic Block Store (EBS), CHT instances can easily be scaled up with larger EC2 instances and have easy increased disk space, backup and restores with EBS.
This guide will walk you through the process of creating an EC2 instance, mounting an EBS volume and provisioning Docker containers.
Create and Configure EC2 Instance Create EC2 (use security best practices)</description></item><item><title>Self Hosting in CHT 3.x</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/self-hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/self-hosting/</guid><description>Whether run on bare-metal or in a cloud provider, the Community Health Toolkit (CHT) core framework has been packaged into a docker container to make it portable and easy to install. It is available from dockerhub. To learn more how to work with docker you could follow the tutorial here and the cheat sheet here.
Note Before continuing, ensure all requirements are met. Installing with a compose file The CHT containers are installed using docker compose so that you can run multiple containers as a single service.</description></item><item><title>App Developer Hosting in CHT 3.x</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/app-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/app-developer/</guid><description>This guide assumes you are a CHT app developer wanting to either run concurrent instances of the CHT, or easily be able to switch between different instances without loosing any data while doing so. To do development on the CHT core itself, see the development guide.
To deploy the CHT in production, see either AWS hosting or Self hosting
Getting started Be sure to meet the CHT hosting requirements first.</description></item><item><title>SSL Cert Install in CHT 3.x</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/ssl-cert-install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/ssl-cert-install/</guid><description>Requirements Installed CHT-Core 3.x via either Self Hosted, EC2 or Local Setup, but must use docker-compose. Your own SSL certifications like Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. Copy certs into medic-os container On your server copy the .crt and .key files to the medic-os container. The existing self signed .crt and .key files will be overwritten:
sudo docker cp /path/to/ssl.crt medic-os:/srv/settings/medic-core/nginx/private/default.crt sudo docker cp /path/to/ssl.key medic-os:/srv/settings/medic-core/nginx/private/default.key Restart services Now that the .crt and .key files are in place, restart nginx in the medic-os container with:</description></item><item><title>Offline Hosting of CHT 3.x Server</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/offline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/hosting/3.x/offline/</guid><description>This guide is not meant for a production CHT instance. Support may be added in the future an offline CHT server in a production environment. Please see the &amp;ldquo;Considerations&amp;rdquo; section below.
Proceed only if you have staff familiar with DNS, TLS Certs, DHCP, LAN topology and Linux in general. This is a complex deployment where mistakes are easy to make unless proper training is in place.
Note This guide only applies to CHT 3.</description></item></channel></rss>