<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Experience Research on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/</link><description>Recent content in User Experience Research on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>User Interviews</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/user-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/user-interviews/</guid><description>User interviews serve the purpose of uncovering opportunities for innovation and for illuminating solutions to problems.
Generative interviews are used in the discovery phase of the development process when you’re looking for opportunities to solve for. Scoped interviews are used when a topic of interest has been identified and you’d like to gain a deeper understanding.
Planning Identify your research objectives Develop your interview questions Establish timelines and resources required: Recording equipment Personnel Location, or connectivity if remote Here is a generative interview template.</description></item><item><title>Focus Group Discussions</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/focus-group-discussions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/focus-group-discussions/</guid><description>Focus group discussions are a quick and convenient way to collect data from several users simultaneously. Use focus group discussions to gain insight into what users think about a topic or shared experience in a group setting and to learn about opinions, attitudes and preferences.
Planning Identify your research objectives Develop your focus group discussion guide Establish timelines and resources required: Recording equipment Stationary Personnel (facilitator, moderator) Location Mobile devices Here is a focused group discussion template.</description></item><item><title>Usability Testing</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/usability-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/usability-testing/</guid><description>Usability testing is the practice of testing how easy or difficult a design solution is to use by observing how users interact with it. These are one on one sessions that can be done in person where the facilitator observes the user directly, or remotely where the facilitator shares their screen and asks the user what they would do next and acts as their proxy.
Planning Prepare your design prototypes to test Identify your test goals and objectives Develop your test script, tasks and scoring criteria Establish timelines and resources required: Recording equipment (record the user and their interactions with the prototype when possible) Personnel Location or connectivity if remote Testing devices or device with screen sharing capabilities if remote Here is a sample usability test.</description></item><item><title>CES Surveys</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/ces-surveys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/ces-surveys/</guid><description>Customer Effort Score surveys are used to quantitatively assess the ease of use of your CHT app.
Planning Identify the key CHT workflows or tasks that are of interest to your program Create your survey to assess the difficulty of each of the above Establish the cadence in which to send the survey to users Tips: Use simple language in your survey questions Aim to keep the survey quick to complete, asking between 8-15 questions Use the 5-point likert scale Here is a sample CES survey.</description></item><item><title>Technical Working Sessions</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/technical-working-sessions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/user-experience-research/technical-working-sessions/</guid><description>A Technical Working Session is a collaborative meeting where backend users of the CHT (such as app developers and data scientists) and CHT Community product managers, software engineers, and UX researchers come together to dive deeper into technical issues and develop potential solutions in real time. These sessions provide valuable insights into the experiences of users developing and configuring the CHT.
Planning and Recruiting Technical working sessions can be set up in two ways: Partners reach out to the CHT Community for support with specific issues A CHT Community member identifies a relevant project to ongoing work and invites them to a technical working session: Ensure objectives for the session are clear and communicated in advance Identify a time that works best for both teams and the logistics of the call (platform, being on video, screen sharing, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>