<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Step-by-Step Tutorials on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Step-by-Step Tutorials on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building SMS Forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/sms-forms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/sms-forms/</guid><description>SMS forms allow users to submit reports from any device including feature phones without internet access. SMS forms are ideal in scenarios where targeted users have no way of accessing internet or where they are restricted to using feature phones.
This tutorial will take you through how to build SMS forms for CHT applications, including:
Defining SMS forms Setting validation rules for SMS forms Setting automatic responses to SMS reports You will be building a pregnancy registration workflow that allows Community Health Workers to register households, register household members, and register new pregnancies for the household members.</description></item><item><title>CHT Application Settings</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/application-settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/application-settings/</guid><description>This tutorial will take you through how to manage the CHT application settings, including;
Setting user roles and permissions Enabling and disabling transitions Configuring contact hierarchy and configuring replication. App settings allow you to both persist information that is critical to the application outside the code, and to create profiles that store the preferences for project deployments.
Brief Overview of Key ConceptsThe settings which control CHT apps are defined in the app_settings.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Multi-facility users</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/multi-facility-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/multi-facility-users/</guid><description>This tutorial will take you through how to create and assign users to multiple places in the CHT UI. Assigning users to multiple places is only available from CHT 4.9.0.
This tutorial covers;
Creating contacts and their associated users Creating places and assign contacts to those places Assigning users to multiple places The CHT application settings allows you to both persist information that is critical to the application outside the code, and to create profiles that store the preferences for project deployments.</description></item><item><title>Building SMS Schedules</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/sms-schedules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/sms-schedules/</guid><description>SMS schedules allow you to send reminder messages at predetermined times. These reminders serve as useful prompts for end-users to take specific actions.
This tutorial takes you through how to set up SMS schedules for CHT applications. It uses a pregnancy registration workflow and follow-up reminders for a Community Health Worker as an example. The same methodology can be applied to other workflows and reminders as needed.
Brief Overview of Key ConceptsSMS schedules are a series of SMS messages that are to be sent to specific contacts at future dates and times.</description></item><item><title>Building App Forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/app-forms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/app-forms/</guid><description>App forms allow users to submit reports from Android devices
This tutorial will take you through how to build App forms for CHT applications, including:
Authoring forms in Excel, Google sheets or other spreadsheet applications. Converting XLSForms to XForms Uploading XForms to CHT You will be building assessment workflow that allows Community Health Workers to conduct a health assessment for children under the age of 5.
Brief Overview of Key ConceptsApp forms serve as actions within the app.</description></item><item><title>Application Tests</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/application-tests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/application-tests/</guid><description>This tutorial takes you through testing the various configurable components of CHT applications using cht-conf-test-harness.
PrerequisitesComplete the following tutorials:
Building App Forms Building A Simple Task Building Target Widgets Building Contact Summary Importance of testing your application Testing your CHT application is important as it ensures you are consistently maintaining your application and defining implementation requirements. Testing also helps the user make better architectural decisions, optimizes the forms, tasks and other components of the application.</description></item><item><title>Local Couch2pg Setup</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/couch2pg-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/couch2pg-setup/</guid><description>Couch2pg is deprecated. For data synchronization, refer to CHT Sync.
This tutorial will take you through setting up a Couch2pg service.
By the end of the tutorial you should be able to:
Set up a Couch2pg service Run the Couch2pg service CHT Couch2pg is a background process that moves data from Couchdb to Postgres through one way replication. It therefore, needs to have full read and write access to both the Postgres Database and Couchdb upstream.</description></item><item><title>Local Docker Setup</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/_partial_docker_setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/tutorials/_partial_docker_setup/</guid><description>Linux (Ubuntu) macOS Windows (WSL2) Download and install Docker Desktop.
Alternatively, on Linux you can use the following commands to install Docker Engine. (This will reduce the layers of technical abstraction for running containers, but will not include a GUI application for managing your Docker resources.)
curl -fsSL get.docker.com -o get-docker.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sh get-docker.sh # OPTIONAL: Allow user to run Docker without sudo dockerd-rootless-setuptool.sh install echo &amp;#34;export PATH=/usr/bin:$PATH&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.</description></item></channel></rss>