<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Messaging and SMS on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/</link><description>Recent content in Messaging and SMS on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SMS message states</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/sms-states/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/sms-states/</guid><description>Interaction with SMS providersCHT Applications can use CHT Gateway and third party aggregators to send and receive SMS messages.
When an SMS report comes in from a user, medic-sentinel adds the appropriate list of scheduled messages (to be sent at a future date) to the report doc.
Periodically, sentinel checks for messages that need to be sent, and sets their state to pending if their scheduled sending time has been reached or passed.</description></item><item><title>Short Contact Identifiers</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/shortcodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/shortcodes/</guid><description>Short unique identifiers for contacts are often used to identify contacts in messaging workflows. Unique short codes are generated on doc.patient_id against any document of a person type, and on every doc.place_id against any document of a place type. By default, these IDs start at 5 numeric digits long, and will increase in length as deemed necessary by the generation algorithm.
If the length is increased, this increase is stored in a CouchDB documented called shortcode-id-length:</description></item><item><title>Message Loops</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/message-loops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/guides/messaging/message-loops/</guid><description>Endless messaging loops can between the webapp and a mobile number via the gateway due to autoreplies from the webapp.
See the Github Issue.
Solution: Add the offending number(e.g 800 or SAFARICOM) to the Outgoing Deny List in the webapp&amp;rsquo;s app_settings configuration file.
&amp;#34;multipart_sms_limit&amp;#34;: 10, &amp;#34;outgoing_deny_list&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;800, SAFARICOM&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;contact_summary&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;</description></item></channel></rss>