<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UX Research Repository on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/</link><description>Recent content in UX Research Repository on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Key Concepts</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/key-concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/key-concepts/</guid><description>There are a number of Baserow key concepts to understand before diving in. These are specific to how we’ve chosen to implement the repository.
Interview Subject This is the person that was interviewed or otherwise provided information/feedback.
Example: Julius Nyerere
Organization The company that the “Interview Subject” belongs to or associates with.
Example: MoH Furahi
Samples These are links to, and metadata about, the “Evidence”. These are typically audio or video recordings stored on google drive, but can also be links to PDFs, forum posts, etc.</description></item><item><title>About Interviews</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/about-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/about-interviews/</guid><description> Be sure to record the interview (audio and/or video) Name the file like “2022-06-05 Interview with Julius Nyerere from MoH Furahi” Upload the file to Google Drive here (private link).</description></item><item><title>Adding Nuggets</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/adding-nuggets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/adding-nuggets/</guid><description>The majority of research observations will come from interviews with CHT users. Here’s how you will enter these observations, called “Nuggets”, into the UX Research Repo.
After conducting your interview, copy the video recording to Google Drive (more info here). You’ll need to reference this later.
High Level Steps Add the Organization (of the person you interviewed) if it doesn’t already exist Create the Interview Subject if this is the first time we’ve interviewed or entered observations from this person.</description></item><item><title>Synthesizing Nuggets</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/synthesizing-nuggets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/synthesizing-nuggets/</guid><description> Product owners review new Nuggets weekly Deal with duplicates Product trio and stakeholders review Nuggets quarterly Facilitator creates a new &amp;ldquo;Grid&amp;rdquo; on the Nuggets table with the date of the workshop Facilitator applies filters to identify Nuggets to be reviewed Date (last synthesis workshop to current date) Focused group (Care or Allies) Not already associated to an insight Export filtered Nuggets to CSV Make copy of latest Miro board and import CSV as stickies Product trio and stakeholders discuss and sort stickies into existing or new themes Define problem statements per theme as insights Return to Baserow and add insights to corresponding nuggets</description></item><item><title>Publishing Insights</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/publishing-insights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/ux-research-repo/publishing-insights/</guid><description>Product owners and UXR review insights dashboard for each Focused Working Group in Klipfolio on a quarterly basis to share: Number of interviews conducted Common themes Infographics of interviews to date Table of insights and number of stories associated with each Emerging themes Share on platforms Internal All hands Slack External CHT Round Up Call Forum Here’s an example forum post.</description></item></channel></rss>