<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in Privacy on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding Privacy Policies to Apps</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/privacy/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/privacy/privacy-policy/</guid><description>As of 3.10.0, privacy policies can be customized for every language, by adding desired content into HTML files.
Privacy policies are now publicly accessible rather than only being available after logging in. This means it can be shared with third parties, for example, app store compliance. If your instance URL is https://my-health-facility.org, then the privacy policy is available at https://my-health-facility.org/medic/privacy-policy. Added in 3.17.0.
Add these HTML files to the privacy-policies folder in your configuration.</description></item><item><title>Privacy &amp; Data Protection Policy</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/privacy/policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/privacy/policy/</guid><description>Note This policy is reviewed and updated periodically by our Responsible Data Working Group and is intended as a resource for the CHT community. If you have any questions, please reach out to our Data Protection Officer at support@medic.org.
Table of Contents Table of Contents Our responsible data promise Compliance with applicable data regulations and policies Data and protected health information Use of software to collect and process data Protected health information policy Security practices Technology security overview Security training for our Partners Inquiries with Medic’s Data Protection Officer Our responsible data promise As a non-profit organization, Medic Mobile (“Medic”)’s mission is to advance good health and human flourishing by building open source technology with and for hard-to-reach communities.</description></item></channel></rss>