<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>At Medic on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/</link><description>Recent content in At Medic on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migration from CHT 3.x to CHT 4.x in EKS - Kubernetes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/data-migration-3x-eks-to-4x-eks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/data-migration-3x-eks-to-4x-eks/</guid><description>Like the Deploy to EKS guide, this guide is meant for Medic Teammates migrating Medic hosted CHT Core deployments. However, given there may be other users who will benefit from understanding the process, this document is published for all to read.
CHT Core hosting architecture differs entirely between 3.x and 4.x. When both versions are running in Kubernetes, migrating data requires specific steps using the couchdb-migration tool. This tool interfaces with CouchDB to update shard maps and database metadata.</description></item><item><title>Deploy CHT Core on Medic hosted EKS</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/deploy-on-eks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/deploy-on-eks/</guid><description>While not directly available to the public who might be doing CHT Core development, having Medic&amp;rsquo;s process for using our Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (AWS EKS) publicly documented will help Medic employees new to EKS. As well, hopefully external developers looking to re-use Medic tools and process to use EKS will find it helpful.
While these instructions assume you work at Medic and have access to private GitHub repositories, many of the tools are fully open source.</description></item></channel></rss>