<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – At Medic</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/</link><description>Recent content in At Medic on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contribute: Product Development Process</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Medic Product Team operates in a way that is most commonly referred to as &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/continuous-discovery-overview/">Continuous Discovery&lt;/a>. That process helps us to focus on the impact of our work and keep teammates well-aligned with the people who use the CHT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To allow teammates to truly learn from and empathize with those using the CHT, the Medic Product team has cross-functional subteams, called &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/focused-groups/">Focused Working Groups&lt;/a>, each aligned with different user types. Each group is focused on a specific set of users of the CHT and has an aligned roadmap. Roadmaps are made up of defined initiatives, which map to goals and strategies. There is a big emphasis on working towards outcomes (not only &lt;em>outputs&lt;/em>). Product teammates work together, across disciplines, to understand opportunities for improvement, find solutions that will have an impact, and then build, deploy, and measure them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of responsible maintainers of a software system, software engineers also dedicate time to performing &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/code-health/">Code Health&lt;/a> tasks. That ensures updates, upgrades, code enhancements, and small bugs are still handled while the team works on highly focused user-facing objectives.
Each Focused Working Group has defined Objectives and Key Results (OKRs), which set their focus for a given quarter. These, in turn, are derived from the Product Team&amp;rsquo;s yearly Objective Goals Strategies Measurements (OGSMs). The &lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/schedule-of-events/">Schedule of Activities&lt;/a> has more on the timing of all this through out any given year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contribute: Product Team Core Competencies</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-core-competencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-core-competencies/</guid><description>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Core Competency&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Reliable&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sets and communicates clear expectations about when something needs to/will be done and does it without prompting.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Team Player&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Acts in the best interest of the team and actively looks for ways to help the team. Makes time to support teammates to be successful.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Growth Mindset&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Always seeking to improve. Open minded, teachable, and coachable.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Proactive&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sees things that need doing and takes action to keep things moving and make the team successful.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Effective Communicator&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Communicates regularly, openly, and effectively using the appropriate channels.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>