<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Health Toolkit – Step-by-Step Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Step-by-Step Tutorials on Community Health Toolkit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: CHT Local Environment Setup</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/local-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/local-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose-of-the-tutorial&#34;&gt;Purpose of the tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will take you through setting up a local environment to build and test CHT applications. This includes setting up the necessary tools to download and run the CHT public docker image as well as a command line interface tool to manage and build CHT apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the tutorial you should be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View the login page to CHT webapp on localhost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload default settings to localhost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brief-overview-of-key-concepts&#34;&gt;Brief overview of key concepts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHT Core Framework&lt;/strong&gt; The Core Framework makes it faster to build full-featured, scalable digital health apps by providing a foundation developers can build on. These apps can support most languages, are offline-first, and work on basic phones (via SMS), smartphones, tablets, and computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medic Project Configurer&lt;/strong&gt; a.k.a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;medic-conf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is command-line interface tool to manage and configure CHT apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker&lt;/strong&gt; is a tool designed to make it easier to create, deploy, and run applications by using containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Containers&lt;/strong&gt; allow a developer to package up an application with all of the parts it needs, such as libraries and other dependencies, and deploy it as one package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;required-resources&#34;&gt;Required resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you begin, you need to have some useful software and tools that are required for things to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, install &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;nodejs&lt;/a&gt; 8 or later and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/get-npm&#34;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also require Docker for your operating system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/&#34;&gt;Docker for Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/editions/community/docker-ce-desktop-mac&#34;&gt;Docker for MacOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/editions/community/docker-ce-desktop-windows&#34;&gt;Docker for Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation-steps&#34;&gt;Implementation steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have the dependent tools and software install, you are ready to begin setting up your CHT local environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-install-medic-conf&#34;&gt;1. Install medic-conf&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using npm on your terminal or command line, install medic-conf globally using the following command;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;npm install -g medic-conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can confirm that the installation was successful by typing &lt;code&gt;medic-conf&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal or command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;confirm-medic-conf.png&#34; alt=&#34;confirm medic-conf&#34; title=&#34;Confirm medic-conf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-install-the-core-framework&#34;&gt;2. Install the Core Framework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/medic/cht-core/blob/master/docker-compose.yml&#34;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/a&gt; file to a folder of your choice. Be sure to place it in a folder that&amp;rsquo;s easy to find on terminal or command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your terminal or command line and navigate to the folder where you have your &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/medic/cht-core/blob/master/docker-compose.yml&#34;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/a&gt; file and run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;docker-compose up
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the command is done running, navigate to &lt;code&gt;https://localhost&lt;/code&gt; on a Google Chrome browser and login with the default username &lt;code&gt;medic&lt;/code&gt; and default password &lt;code&gt;password&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;medic-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;medic login&#34; title=&#34;Medic login&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-create-and-upload-a-blank-project&#34;&gt;3. Create and upload a blank project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;medic-conf&lt;/code&gt; you can create a blank project. This provides you a template from which you can begin working on CHT. Just run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;mkdir cht-app-tutorials
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; cht-app-tutorials
medic-conf initialise-project-layout
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;init-project-layout.png&#34; alt=&#34;initialise project layout&#34; title=&#34;Initialise project layout&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then deploy the blank project onto your local test environment with the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;medic-conf --url&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ce5c00;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;https://medic:password@localhost --accept-self-signed-certs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;accept-self-signed-certs&lt;/code&gt; tells medic-conf that it’s OK that the server’s certificate isn’t signed properly, which will be the case when using docker locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have run the above command it should complete with the message: &lt;code&gt;INFO All actions completed.&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;all-actions-completed.png&#34; alt=&#34;all actions completed&#34; title=&#34;All actions completed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequently-asked-questions&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/cant-upgrade-to-3-8-version/608&#34;&gt;How do I upgrade to a higher version of the webapp?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/unable-to-install-core-framework-in-cloud-instance/533&#34;&gt;How do I access the instance remotely?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Contact and User Management - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/contact-and-users-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/contact-and-users-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose-of-the-tutorial&#34;&gt;Purpose of the tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial you will learn how to create and edit contacts and their associated users in the CHT application using the default contact creation forms. This will help you get familiar with the UI of the webapp as well as some features and functionality. If you are already comfortable with this, you can skip to &lt;a href=&#34;creating-and-managing-users-and-contacts-with-medic-conf.md&#34;&gt;manipulating contacts and their associated documents using medic conf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brief-overview-of-key-concepts&#34;&gt;Brief overview of key concepts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contacts&lt;/strong&gt; are people or places that are created in the CHT application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt; are both patients in the system and users of the system, such as CHWs or Nurses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Places&lt;/strong&gt; represent either an actual physical location such as a health facility, clinic, or a grouping such as a household or CHW area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact forms&lt;/strong&gt; are forms in the CHT app that are used to create people or places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHT app hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt; is often modeled after the health system, health program or community structure.  All people who are registered in the app must be associated with a place. These places are located in a hierarchy with other places. For instance, a Family Member is part of a Household. A Household and CHWs are part of a CHW Area. A CHW Area and nurses are part of a Health Facility. Additional levels may be added as needed. The Admin level operates outside of the hierarchy and gives access to all levels and people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;app-hierarchy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;app hierarchy&#34; title=&#34;Default app hierarchy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt; represent credentials and roles / permissions for accessing the application. This can either be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who can log into the application, such as CHWs or Nurses or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials granting external software restricted permissions to perform certain tasks, such as allowing an external service permission to write reports via the api.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;required-resources&#34;&gt;Required resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have a functioning CHT instance with contact forms configured. Read &lt;a href=&#34;setting_up_local_configuration_environment.md&#34;&gt;How to set up a CHT local configuration environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation-steps&#34;&gt;Implementation steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you will work with the default contact forms and the default hierachy. The default hierarchy is illustrated above as part of the overview of key concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While logged in as an admin user, you will first create the Health Facility, CHW Supervisor, CHW Area, and CHW. You will then create the users for the CHW so that they can log in and create households and household members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-create-the-health-facility-chw-supervisor-chw-area-and-chw&#34;&gt;1. Create the Health Facility, CHW Supervisor, CHW Area, and CHW&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-new-health-facility&#34;&gt;Create new Health facility&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While logged into the CHT application, go to the people tab and select &lt;code&gt;New health facility&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-facility/select-new-facility.png&#34; alt=&#34;new health facility&#34; title=&#34;New health facility&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 options for assigning a primary contact for the new facility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a new contact as you are creating the new facility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selecting a primary contact from already created contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now we will skip creating or assigning a primary contact so that we can focus on creating the new facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-facility/skip-primary-contact.png&#34; alt=&#34;skip primary contact&#34; title=&#34;Skip primary contact&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the details of the facility and submit the form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-facility/enter-facility-name.png&#34; alt=&#34;enter facility details&#34; title=&#34;Enter facility details&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see the newly created facility appear on the left hand side and when you select it, you will see details of the facility appear on the right hand side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-facility/created-facility.png&#34; alt=&#34;created facility&#34; title=&#34;Created facility&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-chw-area-and-chw&#34;&gt;Create CHW Area and CHW&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now create a place and the primary contact for the place within one form. We want to create a CHW area within the facility that we previously created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the Health facility on the left hand side. You will then select &lt;code&gt;New area&lt;/code&gt; on the right hand side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-area/new-chw-area.png&#34; alt=&#34;new chw area&#34; title=&#34;New CHW area&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the option that lets you create a new person within the form. This person will automatically become the primary contact for the created place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-area/create-new-person.png&#34; alt=&#34;create new person&#34; title=&#34;Create a new person&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the required fields and go to the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-area/fill-required-fields.png&#34; alt=&#34;fill fields&#34; title=&#34;Fill required fields&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will get an option to name the place after the created contact person or name it yourself. If you select &lt;code&gt;Yes&lt;/code&gt;, the new place will be named &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;contact-name&amp;gt;&#39;s Area&lt;/code&gt;. For example &lt;code&gt;Jane Doe&#39;s Area&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-area/name-after-primary-contact.png&#34; alt=&#34;name after contact&#34; title=&#34;Name after contact&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you submit, a new CHW area will be created. You should see on the right hand, the CHW Area name, the primary contact of the CHW Area, and the facility that the CHW area belongs to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-area/created-chw-area.png&#34; alt=&#34;created area&#34; title=&#34;Created CHW Area&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-chw-supervisor&#34;&gt;Create CHW Supervisor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a primary contact for an existing place (in this case, for the facility that we created without a primary contact); select the place and the select the &lt;code&gt;New person&lt;/code&gt; action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-supervisor/new-person.png&#34; alt=&#34;new person&#34; title=&#34;New person&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new person form will appear with an option to change the place the new person will belong to. Once you submit this form, a new contact will be created in the Facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-supervisor/belongs-to.png&#34; alt=&#34;belongs to&#34; title=&#34;Belongs to&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will set the newly created person as a primary contact for the Facility they belong to. To do this, select the facility and then select the &lt;code&gt;Edit&lt;/code&gt; action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-supervisor/edit-facility.png&#34; alt=&#34;edit facility&#34; title=&#34;Edit facility&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see an edit form from which you can set the primary contact of the facility and submit to apply the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-supervisor/set-primary-contact.png&#34; alt=&#34;set primary contact&#34; title=&#34;Set primary contact&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-create-the-chw-user&#34;&gt;2. Create the CHW user&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the CHW and CHW Supervisor contacts created, you may want to log in as a CHW and perform some actions. To do this, let&amp;rsquo;s create a CHW user that&amp;rsquo;s linked to the CHW contact we created earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the hamburger menu and select &lt;code&gt;App Settings&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-user/app-settings.png&#34; alt=&#34;app settings&#34; title=&#34;App settings&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are on the &lt;code&gt;App Settings&lt;/code&gt; page, select &lt;code&gt;Users&lt;/code&gt; on the right hand side and then select &lt;code&gt;Add user&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-user/add-user.png&#34; alt=&#34;add user&#34; title=&#34;Add user&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an &lt;code&gt;Add user&lt;/code&gt; form. Fill in the user name, the select the role as &lt;code&gt;CHW&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Regional admin&lt;/code&gt;. In the &lt;code&gt;Place&lt;/code&gt; field, select the name of the CHW area whose CHW you want to create a user for (you can search by typing the first few letters of the CHW area name). Once that is done, under the &lt;code&gt;Associate contact&lt;/code&gt; field select the name of the CHW whose user you are creating. Finally, input a password and hit submit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-chw-user/fill-user-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;user details&#34; title=&#34;Fill user details&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this is done, you can logout and log into the app using the username and password that you just created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequently-asked-questions&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/is-there-any-downside-of-creating-too-many-users/531&#34;&gt;Is there any downside of creating too many users?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/for-offline-users-how-often-does-the-app-try-to-refresh-if-there-is-an-available-internet-connection/503&#34;&gt;For offline users, how often does the app try to refresh if there is an available internet connection?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/can-one-person-belong-to-multiple-places-in-the-same-hierarchy/101&#34;&gt;Can one person belong to multiple places in the same hierarchy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps: Contact and User Management - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/contact-and-users-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/beta/apps/tutorials/contact-and-users-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose-of-the-tutorial&#34;&gt;Purpose of the tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial you will learn how to create and edit contacts and their associated users in the CHT application using medic-conf. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;creating-and-managing-users-and-contacts.md&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this tutorial for a useful overview of key concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brief-overview-of-key-concepts&#34;&gt;Brief overview of key concepts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/medic/medic-conf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;medic-conf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a command-line interface tool to manage and configure your apps built using the Core Framework of the Community Health Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more &lt;a href=&#34;creating-and-managing-users-and-contacts.md#brief-overview-of-key-concepts&#34;&gt;key concepts&lt;/a&gt; in part 1 of this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;required-resources&#34;&gt;Required resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have a functioning CHT instance and have medic-conf installed locally. Read &lt;a href=&#34;setting_up_local_configuration_environment.md&#34;&gt;How to set up a CHT local configuration environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation-steps&#34;&gt;Implementation steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these steps you are going to create a Health Facility, CHW areas, primary contacts for the CHW areas, and their associated users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-create-health-facilities-using-medic-confs-csv-to-docs-and-upload-docs-features&#34;&gt;1. Create Health Facilities (using medic-conf&amp;rsquo;s csv-to-docs and upload-docs features)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create contacts and their associated users with medic-conf, you will need to create a CSV file with the information of the contacts and the users that you would like to create. The name of the file determines the type of doc created for rows contained in the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, file named &lt;code&gt;place.district_hospital.csv&lt;/code&gt; adds the property &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;district_hospital&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; and a file named &lt;code&gt;person.clinic.csv&lt;/code&gt; add the property &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;person&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a CSV file named &lt;code&gt;place.district_hospital.csv&lt;/code&gt; and add the details of the health facilities you would like to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nairobi South Facility&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nairobi West Facility&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nairobi East Facility&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file to a folder name &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; in your project&amp;rsquo;s base directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open terminal or command line. &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; to your project&amp;rsquo;s base directory and then run the command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;medic-conf csv-to-docs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will convert rows of the CSV files from the &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; folder to JSON docs that are stored in a &lt;code&gt;json-docs&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upload the JSON docs to your local test instance, run the command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;medic-conf --url&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ce5c00;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;https://&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;@localhost --accept-self-signed-certs upload-docs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to replace the values &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with the actual username and password of your test instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-create-chw-areas-chw-contacts-and-users-using-medic-confs-create-users-feature&#34;&gt;2. Create CHW Areas, CHW Contacts and Users (using medic-conf&amp;rsquo;s create-users feature)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next you are going to create CHW areas for the health facilities you created in the step above along with the CHW contacts and users for these CHW areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a CSV file named &lt;code&gt;users.csv&lt;/code&gt; and add the details of the Users, CHW contacts, and CHW Areas you would like to create. Save this file in the base project directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;username&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;password&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;roles&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;phone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;contact.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;contact.phone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;contact.sex&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;contact.age&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;place.type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;place.name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;place.parent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;mmutiso&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;q3Z5-vH5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;district_admin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mary Mutiso&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0712345678&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mary Mutiso&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0712345678&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Female&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;health_center&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mary Mutiso&amp;rsquo;s Area&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;facility uuid&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value &lt;code&gt;place.parent&lt;/code&gt; is the uuid of the Facility to which the CHW Area belongs to. You can get this value by selecting the Facility in the webapp and copying the last portion of the url.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;facility-uuid.png&#34; alt=&#34;facility uuid&#34; title=&#34;Facility uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zsh&#34; data-lang=&#34;zsh&#34;&gt;medic-conf --url&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ce5c00;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;https://&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;@localhost --accept-self-signed-certs create-users
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will create the CHW area, the CHW contact, and the user that the CHW will use to log into the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequently-asked-questions&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.communityhealthtoolkit.org/t/can-one-person-belong-to-multiple-places-in-the-same-hierarchy/101&#34;&gt;Can one person belong to multiple places in the same hierarchy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
