<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributing code and documentation on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/</link><description>Recent content in Contributing code and documentation on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First time Contributors Guide</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/first-time-contributors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/first-time-contributors/</guid><description>Who this is forDocumentation exists for everything from how to compile the CHT from source to how to build the docs site locally. However, where do you start? What if you&amp;rsquo;ve never contributed to an open source project before? This guide helps the newcomer make their first contribution.
If this isn&amp;rsquo;t you, head over to our Community section where list out other actions for new community members who are not developers.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>All maintainers and contributors in this community are required to act according to the following Code of Conduct. These guidelines help steer our interactions and help us provide and ensure a safe environment for everyone.
Our StandardsExamples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment include:
Using welcoming and inclusive language Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences Gracefully accepting constructive criticism Focusing on what is best for the community Showing empathy towards other community members Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include:</description></item><item><title>Technical Resources</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/technical-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/technical-resources/</guid><description>This page contains materials that will help a CHT Contributor to learn the technical details they need to be successful when building tools related to the CHT.
Keep in mind that this is a living document, and every contributor is encouraged to add to it when identifying learning opportunities that can set them up for success with the CHT. The main goal here is to provide the technical people who are new to the CHT with a list of resources that could be beneficial for them in both the short and long term.</description></item><item><title>Disclosing vulnerabilities</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/disclosing-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/disclosing-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>In the CHT Community, we take the security of our systems seriously and value the security community. Disclosure of security vulnerabilities helps us ensure the security and privacy of the CHT users.
GuidelinesWe require that all researchers:
Make every effort to avoid privacy violations, degradation of user experience, disruption to production systems, and destruction of data during security testing; Refrain from using any in-scope compromise as a platform to probe or conduct additional research, on any other system, regardless of scope; Perform research only within the scope set out below; Use the identified communication channels to report vulnerability information to us; and Keep information about any vulnerabilities you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered confidential between yourself and Medic until all production systems have been patched.</description></item><item><title>MIT License</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/mit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/community/contributing/mit/</guid><description>This license is required to be included with the first-contributions content the CHT docs uses in the first time contributors guide:
MIT License Copyright (c) 2016 - present Roshan Jossey Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;#34;Software&amp;#34;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions: The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.</description></item></channel></rss>