<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Integrations on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/</link><description>Recent content in Integrations on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/android/</guid><description>The CHT Android application can be launched by clicking on a link or invoking an intent in another Android app. This is useful for enabling login by SMS, directing a user to a specific page, and integrating between Android applications.
Sending a URL When the user clicks on a link to a CHT instance from an SMS, email, WhatsApp, or any other app, Android will prompt the user to choose whether to open the URL in the Android app or the browser.</description></item><item><title>Custom</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/custom/</guid><description>The CHT Core Framework includes functionality that allows sharing data with any API-based system. Developers have configured CHT integrations with OpenMRS, KenyaEMR, Bahmni, DHIS2, RapidPro, Apache NiFi, OpenHIM, custom electronic medical records (EMR), and several other systems.
OverviewIntegrating a CHT App into your digital health ecosystem starts with identifying an integration use case. It&amp;rsquo;s important to first understand all the components present in the ecosystem (EMR, laboratory system, community health information system, etc) and then plan out what the workflow will look like operationally.</description></item><item><title>DHIS2</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/dhis2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/dhis2/</guid><description>Most health systems have regular reporting requirements for community-level activities. Health workers often carry around heavy logbooks to manually record all relevant activities. When it is time to submit their data, community health workers (CHWs) summarize what was recorded in their logbooks and share this information with their supervisors, who in turn create paper records of these totals across entire community units or health facilities. This paper record is often passed to yet another individual whose responsibility is to manually key in the data into a health information management system, such as DHIS2.</description></item><item><title>OpenMRS</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/openmrs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/openmrs/</guid><description>OpenMRS is an open source electronic medical record system used in dozens of countries. Integrating CHT apps with OpenMRS can open up opportunities to improve health outcomes for patients by promoting better coordination of care. For example, referrals by CHWs in the community can be sent electronically to health facilities using OpenMRS so that nurses and clinicians can prepare for their visit and have full access to the assessment done by a CHW.</description></item><item><title>OppiaMobile</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/oppia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/oppia/</guid><description>OppiaMobile is an open source mobile learning platform built by Digital Campus specially designed for delivering learning content, multimedia, and quizzes in low connectivity settings. All the content and activities can be accessed and used when no internet connection is available, and users can earn points and badges for completing activities and watching videos. To learn more about the platform, check out the overview, OppiaMobile on Github, and their documentation site.</description></item><item><title>RapidPro</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/rapidpro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/features/integrations/rapidpro/</guid><description>RapidPro is a software product that allows you to visually build logic to support interactive messaging flows. The flows support a variety of technologies such as: SMS, USSD, IVR, Telegram, Facebook Messenger, and WhatsApp. RapidPro is open source and provides an API to integrate with other applications. To learn more about the platform, check out RapidPro on GitHub or join their Google Group.
OverviewCHT-based SMS workflows can be configured to support registering of new patients or pregnancies, recording outcomes of visits, confirmation via auto-responses, and scheduling reminders.</description></item></channel></rss>