<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building and Maintaining Forms on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/</link><description>Recent content in Building and Maintaining Forms on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuring UHC Mode</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/uhc-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/uhc-mode/</guid><description>Introduced in v2.18.0
The CHT&amp;rsquo;s UHC Mode empowers CHWs to provide equitable and timely care to families in their catchment area. The Community Health Toolkit supports this use-case by displaying the number of visits made to a household and highlighting households which haven&amp;rsquo;t met their visit goal in red at the top of the contact list.
The date last visited is colored red whenever the date is 30 days or more in the past.</description></item><item><title>Creating Additional Docs from App Forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/additional-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/additional-docs/</guid><description>In version 2.13.0 and higher, you can configure app forms to generate additional docs upon submission. You can create one or more docs using variations on the configuration described below. One case where this can be used is to register a newborn from a delivery report, as shown below. First, here is an overview of what you can do and how the configuration should look in XML:
Extra Docs Extra docs can be added by defining structures in the model with the attribute</description></item><item><title>Making Calls and Sending SMS from App Forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/app-form-sms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/app-form-sms/</guid><description>Triggering Calls and SMS When an XForm is loaded on a phone you can start a phone call or trigger the sending of an SMS within the form itself. This can be useful if within a task or assessment, you want to tell the user to contact a patient, or perhaps a health worker at a facility.
To set up the call or SMS you&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a link with tel: or sms: within a note field.</description></item><item><title>Fetching forms from Google Drive</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/google-drive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/google-drive/</guid><description>To work collaboratively on form design it can be helpful to keep XLSForms in Google Drive. The fetch-forms-from-google-drive action downloads these XLSForms so that they can be converted to XForms and uploaded to your CHT app.
This action requires the following files in the top-level folder of your CHT app config: forms-on-google-drive.json and .gdrive.secrets.json.
forms-on-google-drive.json This JSON file contains key value pairs, where the key is the relative path and name for the downloaded file, and the value is the file&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive File ID.</description></item><item><title>Input data available in forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/form-inputs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/form-inputs/</guid><description>CHT forms have access to varying amounts of input data depending on the type of form and its source.
contact forms Available data:
initial contact data inputs data for user Contact data via contact selector Initial contact data in contact forms Create forms Forms for adding contacts have access to a small group of fields contained in a top-level group that is named for the contact_type id of the contact being added (so person, clinic, etc).</description></item><item><title>Including Multimedia in Forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/multimedia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/multimedia/</guid><description>Multimedia Formats There are many supported formats for video, audio, and images. We recommend using h.264(mpeg) for video, jpeg for images, and mp3 for audio. When creating videos or images keep in mind the dimensions and storage capabilities on phones that may be used. Lower end phones have smaller storage and screen sizes. When rendering images, video, and audio the CHT uses the browser&amp;rsquo;s built in rendering tools. This means you can render any media format that is supported by the minimum version of Chrome.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Wealth Quintiles</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/wealth-quintiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/wealth-quintiles/</guid><description>Introduced in v2.16.0
Household surveys with questions about the home, possessions, and access to safe drinking water have been used to create equity score and improve the targeting of health services. This guide will cover how quintile information from a household survey can be used in customizing care for individual household members. For example, the equity quintile can be used to increase the number of pregnancy follow-ups for women in specific households, or to display specific notes or questions within patient forms.</description></item><item><title>Customizing Titles in the Reports List</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/report-titles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/report-titles/</guid><description>Added in 3.9.0
By default the CHT shows the name of the subject of the report in the reports list. This can be overridden by configuring the subject_key property with a translation key in the form document.
The translation uses a summary of the report as the evaluation context so you can include report fields in your value, for example: Case registration {{case_id}}. Useful properties available in the summary include: from (the phone number of the sender), phone (the phone number of the report contact), form (the form code), subject.</description></item><item><title>Versioning forms</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/versioning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/apps/guides/forms/versioning/</guid><description>Added in cht-core 3.15.0 and cht-conf 3.10.0
When uploading app or contact xforms, cht-conf 3.10.0+ will automatically generate a version and include it in the form doc&amp;rsquo;s xmlVersion property. The version has two properties.
Property Description time The time that the form was uploaded to the server in millis since the epoch. sha256 A hash of the xform content. For example:
&amp;#34;xmlVersion&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;time&amp;#34;: 1658717177750, &amp;#34;sha256&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;6f0bbfe5a9a9ebeb25784165879afec5e311b197cbd76ade5698c83c22dd9a8f&amp;#34; } When a user fills in a form with an xmlVersion property, the version is copied in to the report doc as the form_version property.</description></item></channel></rss>