<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Health Toolkit – Quick Guides for Designers</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Guides for Designers on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design: Designing User Interviews</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/designing-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/designing-interviews/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Understanding the people you are designing for is a paramount step in the design process, and so one way to achieve that is through conducting user interviews. This tutorial will help design thinkers to understand users’ experiences from their own point of view in terms of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Why they use products in a certain way&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How they feel about something&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How they perform various actions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="background-current-situation-problem-andor-opportunity">Background (Current Situation, Problem, and/or Opportunity)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Interviews can be a great way to empathize with your users because interviews can give you an in-depth understanding of the users’ values, perceptions, and experiences. They allow you to ask specific questions, while remaining open to exploring your participants’ points of view. They are also often combined with other user research methods, such as usability tests or surveys, so as to gain deeper insights into objective results by asking a user about them and to elicit the user’s subjective opinion on products or interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="brief-overview-of-key-concepts">Brief Overview Of Key Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the word implies, semi-structured interviews are somewhat structured in that you prepare a set of topics you would like to cover during the interview, but still open enough that you can follow leads in the conversation and change the order of topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means you have an interview guide with the questions or themes that you want to talk to the user about, but you are free to change the order of questions or to explore different topics that may arise during the interview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>User interviews can be very informative and helpful, but only if they are used correctly and for the right things. It’s important to know what you can expect to get out of interviews and what you shouldn’t expect to get out of interviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>User interviews can be conducted for the following reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Exploration-before a clear concept has been defined or before a major redesign.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In combination with user tests and formal experiments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In combination with observations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="user-interview-requirements">User Interview Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A good interview requires preparation and careful consideration on the part of the interviewer.
It’s important to be aware of how to ask questions and how to listen in order to gain valid insights into your participant’s life and experiences&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-structure-user-interviews">How to Structure User Interviews&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you conduct a user interview, it is paramount to consider the best way of ordering questions. Below are some tips on what to ask in the beginning, in the middle, and at the end of a user interview.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="beginning">Beginning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the beginning of the interview, you should ask opening questions to set people at ease and build rapport. You should not ask about sensitive topics. Instead, focus on setting the stage and bringing your interviewees on board so they’re comfortable enough to be, and remain, open with you. Your questions at this stage can include the following:
Brief participants what topics will be covered
Brief participants how their data will be used
Asking “safe” questions such as what their role is in their organization
Asking concrete questions that are easy to answer&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="middle">Middle&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the middle of the interview, you’re hitting high gear. Having established a direct channel with your interviewees (the users), you move on and ask the bulk of your questions. The predetermined order of the questions may change based on the direction the conversation is taking. Some of the tips here include:
Keep the flow of the conversation as natural as possible, but cover the topics you want to cover.
Pick up on what participants have said earlier and get full replies to questions they have only partially answered.
Steer participants back on track if they go too far off topic.
Show that you have been listening.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="end">End&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the end of the interview, you wrap up in a way that makes participants feel as though they have said what they wanted to say and that their answers are valuable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things you should do include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Asking if there is anything participants would like to add.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Telling your participants what you are going to do with their data and what the value is for them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanking them for taking the time to help with your research.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Creating an Empathy Map</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/empathy-map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/empathy-map/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This guide will take you through the process of creating an empathy map as a way to synthesize the insights gathered during the discovery phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An empathy map is a visualization tool which helps you sum up what you learned from design research to help you better understand your users and articulate what you know to colleagues and stakeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map provides four major areas in which to focus your attention on, thus providing an overview of a person’s experience. Empathy maps are also great as a background for the construction of the personas that you would often want to create later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map consists of four quadrants. The four quadrants reflect four key traits which the user demonstrated/possessed during the discovery stage. The four quadrants refer to what the user: said, did, thought, and felt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is fairly easy to determine what the user said and did. However, determining what they thought and felt should be based on careful observation and analysis of how they behaved and responded to certain activities, suggestions, conversations, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="brief-overview-of-key-concepts">Brief Overview Of Key Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Insight&lt;/em> refers to a remarkable realization that can help you to solve the current design challenge you are facing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-fill-out-the-empathy-map">1. Fill Out the Empathy Map&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="empathy-map.png">
&lt;img src="empathy-map.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Lay the four quadrants out on a table, draw them on paper or on a whiteboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Review your notes, pictures, audio, and video from your research/fieldwork and fill out each of the four quadrants while defining and synthesising:&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What did the user SAY? Write down significant quotes and keywords that the user said.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What did the user DO? Describe which actions and behaviours you noticed or insert pictures or drawing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What did the user THINK? Dig deeper. What do you think that your user might be thinking? What are their motivations, their goals, their needs, their desires? What does this tell you about her beliefs?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How did the user FEEL? What emotions might your user be feeling? Take subtle cues like body language and their choice of words and tone of voice into account.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="2-synthesize-needs">2. Synthesize Needs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Look for the following within your data to identify your users’ needs:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Verbs, that is, activities and desires. Mark and analyze any pieces of data that start with a verb as these are likely to contain or point towards a user need.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The user traits you noted. Mark specific user traits as these will lead towards the true needs of your users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contradictions and inconsistencies. Once you have picked out the users’ traits, you should look for contradictions and inconsistencies between them. For example, there may be a disconnect between what a user says and does, or they might show a positive action but portray a negative emotion through a quote.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Write down user’s needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="3-synthesize-insights">3. Synthesize Insights&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Look to synthesize major insights, especially from contradictions between two user attributes. It can be found within one quadrant or in two different quadrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also synthesize insights by asking yourself &amp;lsquo;why?&amp;rsquo; when you notice strange, tense, or surprising behaviour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Write down your insights.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design: Creating an Actionable Problem Statement</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/problem-statement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/problem-statement/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This guide will take you through how to create an actionable problem statement in order to generate a greater quantity and higher quality solutions when you start generating ideas during ideation sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Defining your design challenge is probably one of the most important steps in the design thinking process as it sets the tone and guides all of the activities that follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the define stage, you should end up creating an actionable problem statement which is commonly known as the point of view (POV) in design thinking. Base your point Of view on a deeper understanding of your specific users, their needs, and your most essential insights about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your POV should never contain any specific solution, nor should it contain any indication as to how to fulfill your users’ needs in the service, experience, or product you are designing. Instead, your POV should provide a wide enough scope for you and your team to start thinking about solutions which go beyond status quo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, you will also learn to frame and open up your point of view, which is the axis that design thinking revolves around – a challenge well-framed is half solved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-define-the-type-of-person-you-are-designing-for--your-user">1. Define the Type of Person You Are Designing For – Your User&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Select the most essential needs which are the most important to fulfill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work to express the insights developed through the synthesis of your gathered information.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="2-write-your-definitions-into-a-point-of-view-template">2. Write Your Definitions Into a Point of View Template&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="pov-statement.png">
&lt;img src="pov-statement.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Example&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>User&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Needs&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Insights&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>An adult person who lives in a city&lt;/td>
&lt;td>To use a car for 10-60 minutes 1-4 trips per week&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The user would not want to own a car as it would be too expensive compared to his needs. He would like to share a car with others who have similar needs. However, there are no easy and affordable solutions for him. It is important for the user to think and live green and to not own more than he truly needs.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="3-create-a-point-of-view-mad-lib">3. Create a Point of View Mad Lib&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can articulate a POV by combining these three elements – user, need, and insight – as an actionable problem statement that will drive the rest of your design work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is surprisingly easy when you insert your findings in the POV Madlib below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can articulate your POV by inserting information about your user, the needs, and your insights in the following sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[User . . . (descriptive)] needs [Need . . . (verb)] because [Insight . . . (compelling)]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An adult person who lives in the city… needs access to a shared car 1-4 times for 10-60 minutes per week … because he would rather share a car with more people as this is cheaper, more environmentally friendly, however it should still be easy for more people to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="4-make-sure-that-your-point-of-view-meets-the-requirements">4. Make Sure That Your Point of View Meets the Requirements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your POV should:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>provide a narrow focus,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>frame the problem as a problem statement,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>inspire your team,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>guide your innovation efforts,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>inform criteria for evaluating competing ideas,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>capture people’s attention, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>be valid, insightful, actionable, unique, narrow, meaningful, and exciting&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Design: Mapping User on the CHT Hierarchy</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/mapping-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/mapping-hierarchy/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="purpose-of-the-guide">Purpose Of the Guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This guide will take you through mapping of users on CHT hierarchy, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>defining the hierarchy (reporting structure)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>defining user roles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mapping user personas to the CHT hierarchy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="brief-overview-of-key-concepts">Brief Overview of Key Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/">user persona&lt;/a>&lt;/em> is a generalized character that embodies a particular type of user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>User roles&lt;/em> are the activities that the user personas are expected to carry out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>hierarchy&lt;/em> represents the reporting structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisitesrequired-resources">Prerequisites/Required Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/personas/">Personas.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-define-the-hierarchy">1. Define the Hierarchy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Identify the reporting structure of the user personas in order to have a flawless flow of data from one level to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="app-hierarchy.jpg">
&lt;img src="app-hierarchy.jpg"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For instance, family members belong to a household. Households and CHWs belong to a CHW area. CHW areas and nurses belong a health facility. Additional levels may be added as needed. The administrator level operates outside of the hierarchy and gives access to all levels and people.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;figure class="right col-6 col-lg-8">&lt;a href="user-hierarchy.png">
&lt;img src="user-hierarchy.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The app hierarchy is often modeled after the health system, health program or community structure. All people who are registered in the app must be associated with a place. These places are located in a hierarchy to other places.&lt;/p>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="2-define-the-user-roles">2. Define the User Roles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Determine all the actors within the system in terms of who will be doing what.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="user-roles.png">
&lt;img src="user-roles.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;br clear="all">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="3-map-user-personas-to-the-hierarchy">3. Map User Personas to the Hierarchy&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="mapped-personas.png">
&lt;img src="mapped-personas.png"/> &lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>