<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick Guides for Designers on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Guides for Designers on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Designing User Interviews</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/designing-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/designing-interviews/</guid><description>Purpose Of the Guide Understanding the people you are designing for is a paramount step in the design process, and so one way to achieve that is through conducting user interviews. This guide will help design thinkers to understand users’ experiences from their own point of view in terms of:
Why they use products in a certain way How they feel about something How they perform various actions Background (Current Situation, Problem, and/or Opportunity) Interviews can be a great way to empathize with your users because interviews can give you an in-depth understanding of the users’ values, perceptions, and experiences.</description></item><item><title>Creating an Empathy Map</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/empathy-map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/empathy-map/</guid><description>Purpose Of the Guide This guide will take you through the process of creating an empathy map as a way to synthesize the insights gathered during the discovery phase.
Background An empathy map is a visualization tool which helps you sum up what you learned from design research to help you better understand your users and articulate what you know to colleagues and stakeholders.
The map provides four major areas in which to focus your attention on, thus providing an overview of a person’s experience.</description></item><item><title>Creating an Actionable Problem Statement</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/problem-statement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/problem-statement/</guid><description>Purpose Of the Guide This guide will take you through how to create an actionable problem statement in order to generate a greater quantity and higher quality solutions when you start generating ideas during ideation sessions.
Background Defining your design challenge is probably one of the most important steps in the design thinking process as it sets the tone and guides all of the activities that follow.
In the define stage, you should end up creating an actionable problem statement which is commonly known as the point of view (POV) in design thinking.</description></item><item><title>Mapping User on the CHT Hierarchy</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/mapping-hierarchy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/design/guides/mapping-hierarchy/</guid><description>Purpose Of the Guide This guide will take you through mapping of users on CHT hierarchy, including:
defining the hierarchy (reporting structure) defining user roles mapping user personas to the CHT hierarchy Brief Overview of Key Concepts A user persona is a generalized character that embodies a particular type of user.
User roles are the activities that the user personas are expected to carry out.
A hierarchy represents the reporting structure.</description></item></channel></rss>