<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Product Development Process on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/</link><description>Recent content in Product Development Process on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Continuous Discovery Overview</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/continuous-discovery-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/continuous-discovery-overview/</guid><description>The continuous discovery mindset is one that acknowledges that digital products are never &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; and can always be made better. The &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; aspect is that those working on the product should empathize with those who use it and operate with those people in mind, both for finding the most impactful areas of work and in how to measure impact.
Teammates choose work with impact in mind and develop solutions with an expectation that people will use what is built and we can measure a positive change.</description></item><item><title>Focused Working Groups</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/focused-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/focused-groups/</guid><description>The Product team as a whole is focused on digital health tools helping to achieve Universal Health Coverage, and care reaching everyone when and where they need it. The team is made up of 4 different groups, with each group focusing on outcomes to serve different people.
See the overall Product Team Roadmap.
Care TeamsFocused on building effective tools to provide care in the hardest-to-reach communities.
Key users: Patients, Families, Caregivers, Community Health Workers, Supervisors.</description></item><item><title>Migration from CHT 3.x to CHT 4.x in Kubernetes</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/data-migration-k8s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/data-migration-k8s/</guid><description>Like the Deploy to EKS guide, this guide is meant for Medic Teammates migrating Medic hosted CHT Core deployments. However, given there may be other users who will benefit from understanding the process, this document is published for all to read.
CHT Core hosting architecture differs entirely between 3.x and 4.x. When both versions are running in Kubernetes, migrating data requires specific steps using the couchdb-migration tool. This tool interfaces with CouchDB to update shard maps and database metadata.</description></item><item><title>Deploy CHT Core on Medic hosted EKS</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/deploy-on-eks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/deploy-on-eks/</guid><description>While not directly available to the public who might be doing CHT Core development, having Medic&amp;rsquo;s process for using our Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (AWS EKS) publicly documented will help Medic employees new to EKS. As well, hopefully external developers looking to re-use Medic tools and process to use EKS will find it helpful.
While these instructions assume you work at Medic and have access to private GitHub repositories, many of the tools are fully open source.</description></item><item><title>Schedule of Activities</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/schedule-of-events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/schedule-of-events/</guid><description>Annually Set goals (strategies and measures) Identify desired outcomes the team will work towards Quarterly Choose outcome(s) for Focused Working Groups to work towards Outcome kickoff Monthly Communicate status and progress of work towards current outcome(s) Recognize and establish certainty around time sensitive, project-initiated tasks Weekly Conduct interviews Continued iterative work on identifying opportunities, weighing possible solutions, building, and measuring Triage potential side-loaded opportunities</description></item><item><title>Quality Assistance</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/quality-assistance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/quality-assistance/</guid><description>Goals Software developers should have full ownership of what they are building, including quality. The team still benefits from having the QA engineering mindset of QA engineers. QA engineers automate more tests and processes. In ShortA software developer writes code and performs testing on that code where a QA engineer assists by recommending tests to perform and adding additional end-to-end tests.
In DetailA developer should be able to write code and release it when done.</description></item><item><title>Code Health</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/code-health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/code-health/</guid><description>Healthy code is code that is easy to understand and update. Over time all code becomes less healthy as dependencies become out of date, new language features or code style rules are introduced, and changes are made that add complexity. This is sometimes referred to as technical debt as it makes it progressively harder to make new code changes. No project is ever completely healthy, so we need an ongoing process to improve the least healthy parts of the code so the CHT can be sustainable long term.</description></item><item><title>Transparency &amp; Accountability</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/transparency-accountability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/contribute/medic/product-development-process/transparency-accountability/</guid><description>It is important that people around Medic, our partners, and community can always see what is being worked on and that commitments are made and kept. There are a few key ways teammates are expected to operate to enable such transparency and accountability.
GitHub project boardsEach FWG has a board where tickets are displayed and actively kept up-to-date. These boards are publicly readable and anyone should be able to see the items on the board, what state they are in, and have an expectation of when they will be done.</description></item></channel></rss>