<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHT Gateway on Community Health Toolkit</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/</link><description>Recent content in CHT Gateway on Community Health Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/configuration/</guid><description>CHT gateway supports Android 4.1 and above. To have it up and fully working, follow the 3 steps below.
Install the latest APK from the releases page in the cht-gateway repo. This APK is not in the Play Store, you will need to side-load it as is done with CHT Android.
Open the app. if you are installing the app for the first time or afresh, you will get a Warning:medic-gateway is not set as the default messaging app on this device .</description></item><item><title>Phones</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/phones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/phones/</guid><description>In order to use SMS workflows with the CHT you will need an SMS gateway. For reliability an SMS Aggregator, such as Africa&amp;rsquo;s Talking or RapidPro, is recommended. When an SMS Aggregator is not available, an Android device running CHT Gateway can be used to send and receive SMS in your CHT application. You may use an existing Android device and are not required to purchase a new one. However, for more reliable sending and receiving of SMS, the Android device should be in your organization’s office or facility with a consistent internet connection.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting</title><link>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.communityhealthtoolkit.org/building/messaging/gateways/gateway/troubleshooting/</guid><description>In a techlead heaven, we would have immediate physical access to gateway phones, but alas, most of the time we have to hand them over to the partner. Fortunately, comes this guide on debugging gateway problems.
Follow the steps as below (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have physical access to the phone, start with step 2 i.e debug from the server side first)
Make sure that the device:
Is connected to the internet.</description></item></channel></rss>